<string key="Lore_Chapter_GettingStarted">Getting Started</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_GettingStarted_StartingLocation">Starting Locations</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_GettingStarted_StartingLocation">Safe Spawn Beaches</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_GettingStarted_StartingLocation">When you first enter Aeternum, you'll appear on one of a few beaches. These areas act as a &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="GettingStarted_Sanctuaries"&gt;Sanctuary&lt;/a&gt;, where other players cannot attack you as long as you are not a &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Crime"&gt;Criminal&lt;/a&gt;.\n\nThese areas have a limited variety of resources to get you started, but won't get you very far without heading inland. Drowned Sailors raised by the Corruption of Aeternum roam these beaches, so it's best to move on quickly.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_GettingStarted_Outposts">Outposts</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_GettingStarted_Outposts">Neutral Hubs throughout Aeternum</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_GettingStarted_Outposts">Outpost are un-claimable neutral settlements that can be used by any player. They are spread throughout Aeternum with one or two in each major region.\n\nOutposts house a number of important benefits and stations, including:\n  • Outposts are the only place to access &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_Overview"&gt;Trading Posts&lt;/a&gt;\n  • Most outposts offer Sanctuary, where non-criminals cannot be attacked\n  • Every Outpost has an Inn, which can be activated as respawn location\n  • Outposts offer free storage for items personal to each character. Each outpost's storage is unique, meaning items stored at one outpost cannot be retrieved at a different outpost.\n  • Outposts offer a number of crafting stations for public use. Each contains a different selection of stations.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_GettingStarted_Coin">Earning Coin</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_GettingStarted_Coin">Economy and Trading Posts</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_GettingStarted_Coin">Coin is earned by killing enemies or by selling items at &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_Overview"&gt;Trading Posts&lt;/a&gt; located within each &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="GettingStarted_Outposts"&gt;Outpost&lt;/a&gt;. Once earned, your Coin is safe. You do not drop it when defeated in combat.\n\nThe simplest option to earn Coin is by defeating Corrupted or Angry Earth enemies. In addition to Coin, they also may drop Talismans and Animorum, which are dropped by various enemies throughout Aeternum. These items have no other use, but they can be dropped if you die. This makes it a good idea to sell them quickly. Talismans and Animorum are unique in that they can be sold directly to the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_Overview"&gt;Trading Post&lt;/a&gt;.\n\nOther items can be posted for sale, but another player must buy them for you to earn any Coin. Players can &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_SellTab"&gt;post an item for sale&lt;/a&gt;, which leaves the item available for others to purchase at a price set by the seller. Additionally, players can &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_BuyTab"&gt;order an item&lt;/a&gt;, which offers to purchase a specific item for a price set by the buyer. You can sell instantly to these buy orders, or post an offer for your item in hopes that it will be purchased later.\n\nFor more info, the Systems Guide has a full chapter dedicated to the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_Overview"&gt;Trading Post&lt;/a&gt;.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_GettingStarted_LevelingUp">Leveling Up</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_GettingStarted_LevelingUp">Character Progression in New World</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_GettingStarted_LevelingUp">When you level up, you'll be rewarded points you can spend on Attributes and Trade Skills. You can spend these points however you see fit. There are no classes in New World.\n\nYou can open the Progression screen at any time (default: [K]). There you can spend any points you've accrued to enhance your capabilities. Points are either Attribute points or Trade Skill points. They are not shared.\n\nAttributes are an expression of your character's overall capabilities as a person. They determine things like your total HP and Stamina, your defense against various types of damage, and whether or not you can wield certain weapons. You can hover your mouse over each attribute to learn about its affects, and you can experiment with your points to see their effects before committing to them.\n\nTrade Skills represent your ability to perform different actions. This includes harvesting, refining, and crafting items. You can see the specific effects of each level of a trade skill by mousing over the number for any given level.\n\nYou won't be able to unlock every point in every skill. You'll need to work with other players or use the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_Overview"&gt;Trading Post&lt;/a&gt; to obtain high tier equipment.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_GettingStarted_Social">Friends and Company</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_GettingStarted_Social">Working with Other Players</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_GettingStarted_Social">There is strength in numbers, and cooperation is key to overcoming the greatest challenges Aeternum presents. There are a few key ways to work with others.\n\nFirst, you can create a Group with other players. You can use the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_SocialMenu"&gt;Social Menu&lt;/a&gt; or Local Players list to invite other players to a Group. Doing this will help you to keep track of their location, health, and map marker. Groups are short term and can be left at any time. Up to 5 players can be in one. They're the best way to work with others when adventuring or heading into a battle.\n\nFor longer term cooperation, players can join each other's Company. You can use the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_SocialMenu"&gt;Social Menu&lt;/a&gt; to invite others to your Company, which you created along with your character. Companies can have major impacts on Aeternum, including claiming Territories and declaring &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="GettingStarted_War"&gt;War&lt;/a&gt;. Members of Companies each have a rank, granting them various permissions like the ability to invite others, place structure blueprints, and withdraw items from the Company's storage. You can find information and controls for your Company in the Company screen (defaut: [G]).\n\nYou can also add players as a Friend so that you can see when they're online and make grouping with them easier in the future. By clicking their Player Portrait, you can click the Add Friend button to send a Friend Request. If they accept, they'll be listed in the Social Menu so you can see their status and do things like invite them to a Group or send them a Whisper without needing to search for them.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_GettingStarted_War">War</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_GettingStarted_War">Conquer and Defend Territories</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_GettingStarted_War">Companies throughout Aeternum can declare War on each other. During a War, the Companies involved can attack each other without the usual Criminal penalties. Wars take place over a set amount of time, and have a Pre-War phase to allow defenders to prepare.\n\nEach Company has the ability to set a Siege Window from the Company screen (default: [G]). While defending, the defending Company's Territory Protection can be ignored by attackers during this window. This means that their claim can be taken during this time, even if they've paid for protection. Companies should make sure that their Siege Window is set to a time that is easy for their members to participate, maximizing their chances of repelling attacks during this time of vulnerability.\n\nFor more detailed information about &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="War_Overview"&gt;Territories and War&lt;/a&gt;, there is a chapter of the Systems Guide dedicated to it.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_GettingStarted_Sanctuaries">Sanctuaries and Lawless Areas</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_GettingStarted_Sanctuaries">Places Where Crime Works Differently</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_GettingStarted_Sanctuaries">Some areas of Aeternum act as either a Sanctuary or a Lawless Area. These have largely opposite effects.\n\nIn a Sanctuary, non-criminals cannot be harmed by other players. &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Crime"&gt;Criminal Intent&lt;/a&gt; cannot be enabled in these areas. If you have time on your Criminal Timer, however, other players may still hurt you since Criminal Intent is not required to do so. This makes Sanctuaries a haven for players who have not committed any recent crimes, but incredibly dangerous for those who have. Most &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="GettingStarted_Outposts"&gt;Outposts&lt;/a&gt; are Sanctuaries, with a few exceptions.\n\nIn a Lawless Area, committing crimes does not increase your Criminal Timer. You still have to enable your &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Crime"&gt;Criminal Intent&lt;/a&gt; (default: [U]), but your Criminal Timer will not be increased regardless of what actions you take. These are areas where player vs. player combat is common, and anyone can turn on you in an instant without suffering the usual penalties. Lawless Areas are dangerous, but often offer some of the highest Tier resources. Some &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="GettingStarted_Outposts"&gt;Outposts&lt;/a&gt; are Lawless Areas. You can tell if an Outpost is Lawless from its icon on the Map.</string>