<string key="Topic_08_EbonscaleReach">Tales of Ebonscale Reach</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_08_EbonscaleReach">Named for the black fungus that grows within, the ruins of Chinese settlers lay amidst lush wetlands, majestic waterfalls, and towering cliffs</string>

<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Chapter_01">The Empress' Journey</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_01_01">Act I Scene II</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_01_01">Beginnings of Rebellion</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_01_01">ACT I SCENE II - THE EMPRESS' JOURNEY\n\n(The darkened stage is set with a lone throne and the Empress sitting upon it.)\n\nThe Taiying Empress: Half-brother of mine! What brings you to the throne room at such an hour?\n\nShang Wu: I should be asking the same of you, sweet sister. Your coronation is set for tomorrow and yet you've already taken your perch.\n\nThe Taiying Empress: Tomorrow, it will not matter. Tomorrow, I shall be Empress.\n\nShang Wu: We shall see about that...\n\n(The stage lights up fully to reveal Shang Wu's forces in hiding ready to strike.)\n\nShang Wu (to the audience): My long-despised enemy shall be forced to flee, and I shall be the Emperor of China!\n\n(Lights out.)</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_01_02">Act II Scene III</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_01_02">Beginnings of Revenge</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_01_02">ACT II SCENE III - THE EMPRESS' JOURNEY\n\n(Half of the stage is covered in sand to represent the beach the Empress and her forces washed up upon.)\n\nRetainer 1: Your Highness, this island was not on any of our maps, and as for that red, collapsed mountain in the distance...\n\nThe Taiying Empress: We will make camp here. There is a power in this place, an old power... It may be the key to returning home and retaking my throne.\n\nRetainer 2: I do not trust it, your Grace.\n\nThe Taiying Empress: Do you not trust me, your paragon, who led you from persecution from the forces of Shang Wu?\n\nRetainer 2: I apologize tenfold, your Grace. We of course trust our beloved leader.\n\nThe Taiying Empress: Then all is not lost. We will investigate this shattered mountain, and we will harness the energies it holds. So, I might sail home one day to take back what is rightfully mine.\n\n(Lights out.)</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_01_03">Act III Scene I</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_01_03">Conversion of the Guard</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_01_03">ACT III SCENE I - THE EMPRESS' JOURNEY\n\n(The stage is lit in red tones.)\n\nThe Taiying Empress: And with this Dragon's Pearl I shall convert our band of refugees into my mighty empire!\n\nGuard 1: Yes, your highness. I would follow you anywhere.\n\n(The Empress presses the Dragon Pearl to Guard 1's forehead and he begins to scream.)\n\nGuard 1: I can feel it, the Corruption tearing apart my mortal soul, twisting it! Oh, the agony!\n\n(A mask with rubies where the eyes are is placed upon Guard 1's head from the prop trapdoor.)\n\nGuard 2: I cannot fall to the same fate, I must flee!\n\nThe Taiying Empress: As my loyal subject you will submit to the Corruption. It will make you strong where you are now weak, and afraid.\n\n(Guards 3 and 4 hold down Guard 2 so the Empress can press the Dragon Pearl to Guard 2's forehead as he begins to scream.)\n\nThe Taiying Empress: Rise, rise my champions! You will all have the gift of Corruption soon enough!\n\n(Lights out.)</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_01_04">Act IV Scene V</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_01_04">Finale</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_01_04">ACT IV SCENE V - THE EMPRESS' JOURNEY\n\n(The Empress is surrounded by the full cast in the ruby-eyed masks.)\n\nThe Taiying Empress: Where is Zeng Lingyun? Has my most loyal handmaiden truly abandoned her post when she is most needed? No matter. I shall continue on without her, with my new army. First Aeternum, and then the world shall be mine!\n\nFull Corrupted Cast: All hail The Empress, Dragon of Aeternum, destined ruler of the worlds old and new!\n\nThe Taiying Empress: Enough sentimentality. Begin construction on my fleet of ships. The ranks of my legion swell like a mighty red wave preparing to crash onto distant, familiar shores and wash away the pathetic weakness of the old ways. To arms!\n\nFull Corrupted Cast: To arms!\n\n(The Empress smiles and takes her seat on her Corrupted throne.)\n\n(Lights out.)</string>

<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Chapter_02">Dragon Fascination</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_02_01">Dragons at Her Command</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_02_01">Ebonscale's Dollies</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_02_01">I have served the Empress since she was a girl hiding behind her mother's skirts, playing with her dragon dolls.\n\nI cannot serve the Empress through this. If Taiying ever leaves Aeternum, if Corruption ever gets off of this island, the whole world will be forfeit, not just Shang Wu's forces.\n\nShe wields supernatural power over the minds and bodies of her followers as if they were her childhood dolls. I shudder to think how she views her own people, as mere fodder for her smoldering revenge.\n\nNow that we are on Aeternum, I see there is no going back home. Now, I must help cage the dragon that has been born here.\n\n-ZL\n\n</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_02_02">Dragons of All Elements</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_02_02">Ebonscale's Shrines</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_02_02">The shrines that the Empress ordered to be built around Ebonscale Reach each correspond to a different element important in dragon lore.\n\nIt is said by our people that the Old World was shaped by dragons. Long serpents lay down to form the rivers, while mountains were made by great leviathans hunkering down to rest. Even the air we breathe in was first breathed out by the dragons. Their gift of fire is the most obvious elemental connection of all. Dragons are all around us; one only has to know where to look.\n\nIt seems the great Taiying Empress' desire to see dragons allows her to conjure them with this strange new power she has acquired. Does she shape the power or does the power shape her?\n\n-ZL</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_02_03">The Ordering of the Earth</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_02_03">Aeternum Disrupts</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_02_03">Order ruled the Old World, but this New World is chaos. The five elements (wood, metal, fire, water, and earth) infuse Aeternum, but they exist out of balance. Spirit and air forge nature around us, as does life and death itself. Air replaces the principles of metal and wood in our four shrines. How can this be? \n\nI know the heavenly force that ordained my once-beloved Taiying Empress, but there are strange forces at play here. I lose sight of the truth I once knew. My memory becomes mist. The crimson of Corruption terrifies me. In my chambers, I hear my Empress weeping, lamenting her tie to this unnatural power.\n\nI know doubts plague her mind. She regrets the hellish bargain she made. I pray there is a way to save her without destroying her.\n\nZL</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_02_04">The Ordering of the Heavens and Hells</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_02_04">Aeternum Disrupts</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_02_04">Heaven and Hell were natural consequences of life on earth before Aeternum. Heaven is the divine ruler of the skies who gifts their eminence to the royal bloodline. Hell, in its ten courts, is the darkness pervading the earthly prison it traps human souls in.\n\nBut there are no courts or judges here, only untamed and uncaring wilderness. This cannot be Hell, it is far too disorganized in its tortures. Seeing Taiying take on the mantle of Corruption is far worse than any Hell of iron beds or oil cauldrons.  \n\nI heard her weeping again, for herself or for her people I could not say.\n\nZL</string>

<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Chapter_03">Empress' Descent</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_03_01">Cursing at the Sky</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_03_01">A People Betrayed</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_03_01">A thousand curses upon the head of Shang Wu, usurper of our Empress' throne!\n\nA thousand curses upon all the men who backed this betrayer, driving our true ruler from the throne room and into hiding!\n\nA thousand curses upon this island, where our ships crashed in our flight from our homeland!\n\nCurse its 'mysteries' and 'secrets' and all this bloody irritating sand. Nothing good will come of staying here long. I can feel a stale evil in the air around this place, and at night it is almost as if I can feel that broken mountain in the distance turn its red gaze upon me. Tomorrow I am summoned to the Empress' chambers, and I will explain my concerns to her then.\n\n-Zhi</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_03_02">Flash of Anger</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_03_02">A Petitioner Caged</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_03_02">Today, I witnessed something disturbing.\n\nA petitioner came to the Empress, in her makeshift palanquin on the beach, and decried this land of Aeternum. He claimed it would only lead to our doom. I found myself nodding in agreement; I, too, hate this place.\n\nBut in a flash of anger quite unlike her, the Empress set her royal guard upon him. They beat him bloody and dragged him to the crude cells we had only just erected yesterday. He is to be held there without food or water for as long as she deems necessary.\n\nI'm very lucky that the Empress didn't see me nodding, or I fear I'd be dying of thirst in a cell, too.\n\nI would expect this behavior of the treacherous Shang Wu, but now even our beloved Empress has become hard and warlike. Her brown eyes have turned redder and redder. What has become of the upstanding woman we followed out of our homeland?\n\n-Jing</string>

<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Chapter_04">The Departed</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_04_01">Rising Waters</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_04_01">Before the Flood</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_04_01">The water levels around the house have been slowly but steadily rising. I see the dark, pregnant clouds in the distance, ready to release their rain on us again. I fear the house will not survive it. We've taken everything off of the floor and stacked the furniture, but now the water completely encircles our little hovel. Is this our punishment for following the Empress? We stand together and pray the stagnant water stops rising, for it is all we can do.\n\n-Yang</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_04_02">Ebbing Waves</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_04_02">After the Flood</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_04_02">Waves crash where my house used to be. I never considered it a home, not after having to flee our true homes in the Old World, but it was a place to hang my hat and rest my feet. I will miss it sorely.\n\nBut our misfortune is nothing compared to that of our neighbors, the Chens. The flash floods came so quickly I saw the father of the family swept away in a rush of water. The body hasn't yet been found.\n\nThe Empress promises we will recover, that she has a plan to restore us to an even greater glory than we had in the Old World. Standing at the edge of the dirty, treacherous water, I cannot see how that is possible.\n\n-Yang</string>

<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Chapter_05">Hopkins' Joke Book</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_05_01">Gator Puns</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_05_01">Gator Hater</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_05_01">What do you call an Alligator Detective?\n\nAn Investi-gator!\n\n\n\nWhat did one Alligator say to the other who was in the way?\n\nPlease move, I need to get Bayou!\n\n\n\nWhat do you call a scaled creature who's excellent with directions?\n\nA Navi-gator!\n\n\n\nWhat do Alligators call artistic Turkeys?\n\nPoultry in motion.</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_05_02">Two Alligators Walk Into A Bar...</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_05_02">Gator Hater</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_05_02">Two Alligators walk into a settlement bar. One orders and says, "I would like a water... but it CANNOT have ice in it."\n\nThe barkeep asks, "Why the big clause?"\n\nThe Alligator replies, "I don't know, I've had them my whole life!"</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_05_03">Tiger Puns</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_05_03">Tiger Fighter</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_05_03">What's the difference between a hiding leopard and a hiding tiger?\n\nA tiger can't be spotted.\n\n\n\nWhat did the tiger tell her kids before dinner?\n\nLet us prey.\n\n\n\nWhy was the tiger angry after the race?\n\nBecause the winner was a cheetah.\n\n\n\nWhy can you trust what a tiger says?\n\nThey ain't lion!</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_05_04">What Do You Get...</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_05_04">Tiger Fighter</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_05_04">What do you get with the eyes of a tiger, the paws of a monkey, the tail of an alligator, and the heart of a turkey?\n\nA lifetime ban from the Aeternum Zoo.\n\n\n\n\n\nNote: Workshop on this one with Redridge, it'd be more effective if there actually was an Aeternum Zoo.</string>

<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Chapter_06">Dragon Shrines</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_06_01">How to Maintain</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_06_01">Shrine Excellence</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_06_01">Note from Long:\n\nThe Dragon Shrines are now completed. Please refer to this note on their maintenance.\n\nNightly: Clean ash from incense offerings, respectfully distribute food and herbal offerings.\n\nWeekly: A complete cleansing of the Shrine by dancing with incense. More notes to come on cleansing.</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_06_02">How to Cleanse</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_06_02">Shrine Purity</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_06_02">Listen, Zhang. No one said your dancing had to be any good. You just need to dance with the incense to properly cleanse impurities from the Shrine. I don't care how stupid you think you look.\n\nI can tell if you do it without dancing, we all can! Suck it up and start moving those hips, this is for the safety and piety of our Empress!\n\n-Long</string>

<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Chapter_07">Bao's Curiosity</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_07_01">On Corruption</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_07_01">Questions Unanswered</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_07_01">Corruption is a source of despicable evil, but how much do we really know about it? I know a Dynasty Corrupted Heavy could bring me down in one swing, but why are they so powerful? Does the Corruption affect muscle growth, or how hot the blood runs in combat?\n\nAlso, what on earth is with that brimstone Corrupted smell? Can they smell each other? I can't imagine it's pleasant.\n\n-Bao</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_07_02">On Dryads</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_07_02">Arboreal Mysteries</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_07_02">Trees come to life on two legs, or so Artificer Long tells me. She calls them Dryads. I can't imagine she's right, though. With the rate trees are cut down and regrown on Aeternum, you'd think they'd all turn into screaming monsters seeking revenge on the lumberjacks of the land. So if they're not trees, and they're not people, what are they?\n\n-Bao</string>

<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Chapter_08">Long's Journal</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_08_01">The Invitation</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_08_01">Entry One</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_08_01">The elemental dragon shrines are my finest work yet! The Empress was most impressed, and offered me a place of honor to dine at her side tonight. That's a rare gift for a common-born woman like me. I will have to brush up on my table manners. As the final descendent of the Long family, I'd hate to embarrass my ancestors by using the wrong spoon.\n\nI wish Lian was here, she was always the graceful sister. Her death at sea was a huge loss for all of us.\n\n-Long</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_08_02">The Rejection</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_08_02">Entry Two</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_08_02">I can barely believe what I just saw. My hands shake as I write this.\n\nOur beloved Taiying Empress, the great dragon of our time, has become a monstrosity.\n\nGone is her legendary beauty, her face cracked with veins of red that oozed down her neck and arms. She held out a red orb that appeared to be some kind of pearl, and tried to do something terrible to me with it. I ran past the guards, out of her fortress, and I did not stop running until I reached the Skysong Lagoon. Whatever our Empress has dabbled in here, whatever terrible power now animates her, will destroy us all.\n\n-Long</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Chapter_10">Danya's Logs</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_08_03">Life Away from the Empress</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_08_03">Entry Three</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_08_03">I found a small gathering of settlers in Moss Mire, the leaders among them named Redridge and Danya. Redridge seems kind enough, but I highly doubt I can trust Danya to stick his neck out for anyone besides himself. I wonder what his true motive is in founding this small smattering of buildings we are calling a settlement.\n\nAt least we are far enough from the Empress's forces that they won't come raiding us any time soon. We are in talks to construct a fort to the north for that very purpose, to fight off invaders. Until then, I will tell  Redridge everything I know about our new common enemy. This knowledge is the only reason I don't regret serving under her for so long.\n\n-Long</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_08_04">The Fort Rises</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_08_04">Entry Four</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_08_04">The fort is finally complete. With the steady stream of castaways, we might even be able to put up a fight against Corruption invasions. \n\nUnfortunately, its completion also means those three factions will begin warring for control of the territory. I am not looking forward to that carnage. We should all be uniting against the Corruption, not fighting each other over petty land squabbles.\n\n-Long</string>



<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_10_01">A Ledger of Favors</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_10_01">Settlement Library Relations</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_10_01">Magistrate Redridge - No outstanding balances.\n\nSurvivalist Hopkins - Copy of The Epic of Gilgamesh lent.\n\nArtificer Long - Three units of classics owed, when will she get back to me?\n\nTrader Xian - Still obsessed with Commentaries of Zuo, I almost can't bring myself to take it away.\n\nCommander Hartford - Still refuses to speak to me after the Bear Incident.\n\nAlchemist Lane - All favors paid off, steady requests for poetry about fishing.\n\nAdjudicator Wen - No outstanding balances.\n\nBarkeep Bao - The rotten git won't return Tristan and Iseult. Deny all his building requests.</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_10_02">Book Request</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_10_02">Letter to Bao</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_10_02">Bao,\n\nIt is in your best interest to return my copy of Tristan and Iseult.\n\nIt would sure be a shame if your request for a new expansion to the bar got denied. Or if it burned down.\n\nAll the best,\n\nElder Danya</string>

<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Chapter_11">Chang's Scrolls</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_11_01">Aquanaja</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_11_01">Slinking On By</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_11_01">From the library of Chang's fishing scrolls:\n\nShould you ever see a spout of water emerge from the sea of Ebonscale Reach, know you have seen the Aquanaja. This rotund, flesh-like serpent dwarfs all other serpents, for it is at least the length of a galleon. It shoots spouts of water out into the air for reasons unknown. Perhaps it is playing, toying with onlookers? Either way I dream of capturing it one day, and feeding the settlement with its bounty.</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_11_02">Fishing With a Cause</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_11_02">Tournament For the People</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_11_02">From the library of Chang's fishing scrolls:\n\nThe people of Ebonscale Reach have been through so much. Flooding, starvation, a mad Empress breathing down the backs of their necks...\n\nI just want to make things easier for them. I once had a dream, a dream that there could be a grand competition between fisher folk whose results would determine prizes. The fish collected during this tournament would go towards feeding the settlement in the end, and it would be a great chance to get the fishers of Aeternum together.\n\nThe last time I tried establishing one, though, the Empress sent her guards down upon me and I was killed most brutally. One day, one day...</string>

<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Chapter_12">Empress and Isabella</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_12_01">The Empress' Bargain</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_12_01">The Deal</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_12_01">The Empress met with a strange man today, one hooded and reeking of death. The floods have taken a great deal from us all, most notably in the Empress’ spirits, but I warned her right away this man was not to be trusted.\n\nStill they had a meeting in her palace, my treasured ruler ignoring my counsel. \n\nWhen the two emerged from their meeting the stink of death was on my Empress too, and no matter how many times I bathed her it would not come off.\n\nI asked her what the man offered, to which she replied: “Everything we lost.”\n\nI asked her what she was to give in return and she paused before whispering: “Everything we are to gain.”\n\nZL\n</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Title_12_02">The Tempest and The Empress</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Subtitle_12_02">A Fated Meeting</string>
<string key="08_EbonscaleReach_Body_12_02">We are to receive a special guest today. It is unlike my auspicious Empress to be so full of nerves. Her usual grace holds us all together as a court as we are reminded by our shining example of how we are to conduct ourselves. \n\nThis guest is referred to in whispers as The Tempest, and the other servants say she leaves scarlet death in her path. If the Taiying Empress is to make a deal with her, I fear she will lose herself even more than she already has in her flight to Aeternum and all the troubles that came with it. \n\nBut I cannot say this. She has becoming increasingly unreachable, pulling away from even myself as The Tempest draws nearer. Each day brings new violence in her heart, and all I can do is pray this Tempest does not besmirch my lady’s mind further. \n\nZL</string>