<string key="Topic_14_Edengrove">Tales of Edengrove</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_14_Edengrove">An Ancient crater with lush forests and ruins that hide Aeternum's legendary Spriggans</string>

<string key="Topic_TwinFalls">Wincroft's Journal</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_TwinFalls">Journal of Ealderman Wincroft</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Chapter_02">Wyrdwood</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Title_02_01">An Unexpected Find</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Subtitle_02_01">01 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Body_02_01">We were making our way east from the Cleave. We might not have noticed the unusual trees had one of the wagons not gotten caught in the mud. While the industrious among us fought to get it to solid footing, we made an unusual discovery – or should I say, the most idle among us made the discovery: the Adler Boys, who have yet to carry their weight beyond gossip and shirking their chores. In this instance, their idleness proved a boon.\n\nThe boys had slipped into the woods and had come upon a strange copse of trees – trees that seemed limmed with a strange blue light, suffusing the wood. We might not have known, had they not returned with branches from the same trees – branches they were using as makeshift swords, not knowing the value of what they held. The boys dubbed it “Wyrdwood” and insisted on keeping their new “swords.”\n\nWe quickly noticed the wood was remarkably lightweight and sturdy, so we set aside the labor with the wagon a moment to search the area. This wood may be worth harvesting – for if we fashioned homes or walls from the wood, such structures might prove remarkably sturdy. Perhaps the wagon being caught in the mud was not a setback after all, but a blessing!\n\n-Ealderman Wincroft</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Title_02_02">Harvesting</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Subtitle_02_02">02 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Body_02_02">The Adler Boys led our band to the copse of the blue-limmed trees, the “Wyrdwood,” and the trees looked dense enough to harvest – it was unusually strong for its weight (though it took us fashioning some stronger hatchets to bring the trees down).\n\nThe discovery was a boost to morale – the discovery of the Wyrdwood even made me hesitant to berate the Adlers for straying from the wagons, though they had been warned countless times.\n\nWe set about harvesting what we could, while others got the wagons to dry ground – it seemed fortune favored us, and fortune could be made should we collect enough!\n\n-Ealderman Wincroft</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Title_02_03">Be Warned</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Subtitle_02_03">03 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Body_02_03">Our fortune with the Wyrdwood soon turned sour. As we sought more of the trees, it did not take us long to see that the trees neighbored one of the great stone ruins: the same ancient ruins with the preserved corpses, standing at attention, the ones that were said to walk with blue fire in their chests. Fortunately, we spotted the ruins at a safe distance, so we quickly and quietly returned to camp – the lumber had already been loaded, so we were soon on our way.\n\nI consulted my maps of the region, and if there were a tie between the wood and the ruins, it was likely other sources of the Wyrdwood could be found near other ancient sites. I did not wish to test our luck by seeking them out - but perhaps the knowledge could be of use to a merchant.\n\nFor now, we continue our search for a settlement to make our own – our wagons continued along the roads, making their way east: We'll travel to the other edge of the Cleave if need be, but I'll not settle for nesting near ruins or outposts, that much I swear.\n\n-Ealderman Wincroft</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Chapter_01">Wincroft's Journal</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Title_01_01">Unload the Wagons</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Subtitle_01_01">01 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Body_01_01">Finally, our travels across the Cleave has yielded fruit! We have come upon a stretch of land, fertile and rich, secluded enough that one may hear their own thoughts from the yammering and chopping of wood and clanging of hammer to metal in the settlements to the south. And the waterfalls nearby, such a sight to behold!\n\nThe traders of the outposts warned us of the dangers of the Cleave, but I see now they sought to keep us from the unblemished land – here is where we will make our mark, found a claim, and build our homes. We have seen little else but bear tracks in the area, and while numerous, we have not seen their owners since our arrival.\n\nI must ask: Why has such a stretch lain untouched for so long?\n\nWhy, it must have been awaiting us - and we are thankful for nature's gift. We shall unload the wagons and put the timber within to good use!\n\n-Ealderman Wincroft</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Title_01_02">A Paradise Found</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Subtitle_01_02">02 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Body_01_02">The beauty of the area is astounding. Everything grows so quickly in the earth, and so much so that the gardens are to bursting – azoth blesses this place, the vegetation especially.\n\nIt grows so thickly, in fact, the men have taken to shifts to trimming away the excess vegetation on the houses and fences, yet it seems to grow back with every dawn, thicker than before. While the Adler Boys frequently complain of the chore, they did make mention of something I had not noticed before – they said the greenery seemed to grow thickest from the homes fashioned with the Wyrdwood timber we had carried with us from the West. Does one encourage the other?\n\n-Ealderman Wincroft</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Title_01_03">Layabouts</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Subtitle_01_03">03 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Body_01_03">The Adler Boys, gossipers and layabouts, have been causing trouble, even though I've tried to put their idle hands to use trimming the vegetation back. The two made light that we need not need to fear the bears in the woods – we have no need to bolt our doors at night, for the grass and vine that beset our homes would do it for us.\n\nMay the bears take them both if they don't mind their tongues.\n\n-Ealderman Wincroft</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Title_01_04">Damnable Bears</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Subtitle_01_04">04 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Body_01_04">Troubles plague us! Not from the land, nor the construction, but the animals, who have grown overbold at our intrusion. While we saw signs of bears and wolves in our journey here, we encountered nothing – yet now that we are making a home in this place, bears have been sighted in increasing numbers at the edge of our settlement.\n\nWe keep the doors secured, food out of reach, yet their numbers seem to grow with each passing day. I have sent the Adler Boys (they are the swiftest of us, since we lost the horses) to run for the local outpost for more powder and perhaps to hire some hunters – we shall make short work of these beasts. This is our home, not theirs, and if they persist, they shall see we have claws as well.\n\n-Ealderman Wincroft</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Title_01_05">Trapped</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Subtitle_01_05">05 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Body_01_05">Without the help of the Adler boys - even with their complaining and slowness at the task - the vegetation is proving more than a match for us – the vines are growing thick, more than we can hack away with every morning – and by afternoon, it tangles around our homes again. It is as if nature itself is seeking to drive us away.\n\nShould things in the village become too much, I may seek shelter in the shack up the river, though I would not want to be trapped there should the bears roam that far, there is little place left to flee.\n\n-Ealderman Wincroft</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Title_01_06">Not a Paradise</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Subtitle_01_06">06 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TwinFalls_Body_01_06">The horror I beheld when I awoke this morning – our homes, swallowed in vines, and the roars of the bears through the village – I knew the wilderness acted with intent and did not welcome our intrusion. I confess my cowardice – I ran , ran here, but even the falls could not drown out the cries of the other villagers as the beasts fell upon them.\n\nI fear no help will come. I no longer hold out hope for the Adler Boys' return: I pray they kept running, and they lead no one else to this False Paradise. A green death that surrounds us, and if we do not keep our wits about us, it shall harvest us, not the other way around.\n\nLight fades, and I see great shapes circling the flimsy walls of this shack. I shall keep quiet and hope nothing comes - but I know this hope to be a lie.\n\n-Ealderman Wincroft</string>

<string key="Topic_FiveFarms">Letters From Five Farms</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_FiveFarms">Scattered storys penned by the inhabitants of the Five Farms</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Chapter_01">The Ever Night Letters</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_01">His Return</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_01">01 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_01">We burned Adriaen today, his flesh given over first to the strange wasting disease on the isle, then second to the flames of the pyre. I could not hold my composure and wept, yet others among us remained silent.\n\nHe had already been feared lost almost a season ago – some claimed they thought they had seen him amongst evil-looking soldiers, but they could not be sure, and feared to approach too closely lest they be captured as well.\n\nStill, to see him return, so sickly and feral like a hound, lashing out at all he could find, it took three men of the town to bring him down with clubs until he collapsed, still clinging to life. We gathered around, horrified, none of us knowing what to make of it, until Marten ordered we burn him, lest the infection spread.\n\nKathrijn</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_02">A Parting Gift</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_02">02 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_02">I examined Adriaen's ashes on the morrow – I could not say whether the flames had consumed him or whether he had simply vanished, for no bones or trace of him remained - only a strange shaping of wood, dyed red, that seemed untouched by the fire. A parting gift, I thought, something that sustained him and not even the fire could burn away.\n\nI did not speak of what I had found, merely buried the keepsake in the fields where Adriaen had labored for the harvest, and then I scattered Adriaen's ashes from the pyre atop it. Wherever Adriaen is now, I hope he is at peace.\n\nKathrijn</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_03">The Flower</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_03">03 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_03">I found some small comfort today. Where I had buried the Adriaen's red keepsake – the oddly shaped sculpture of wood - a violet flower had sprouted. I sought to pluck it for the mantle, but it resisted my efforts, so I brought a knife and clipped it sharply where it clung to the soil.\n\nIn the morning, however, the flower had died, the petals black, though I had made sure it had enough soil and water – and the smell from it was quite peculiar, almost like rot. I cast the remains away, then returned to where I had taken the flower the day before. To my surprise, new flowers had blossomed where I had buried the keepsake, almost a dozen sprouting forth where none had been the day before.\n\nI am afraid to speak of the matter to Marten. I thought to tell my Mother what I had seen, but then put it out of my mind – she did not want to speak of Adriaen - as if by saying his name we would bring the disease upon us.\n\nKathrijn</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_04">Lost Among Flowers</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_04">04 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_04">Marten has not returned. We went out in search of him, but it seemed he had wandered off. There were no signs of a struggle, nor bandits from the road, but they gathered us together and ordered us to bolt the doors. It has been days now, and the villagers have taken to whispering amongst themselves.\n\nI did not speak of the flowers I saw where Marten had vanished, and how their color looked red in the dusk, as if drinking in the day's last rays. The flowers grow thickly there as they did at Adriaen's grave – and I have seen them elsewhere in the village as well. The men and women complain about them, how they choke the crops and seem to resist spade and shovel.\n\nThey call them not flowers, but weeds – to me, they still have a beauty about them, and I am glad there is some trace of it on this isle, for there is little joy to be had.\n\nKathrijn</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_05">I am Certain of It</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_05">05 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_05">I saw Adriaen last night. It was no trick of the eye - he was at the place where I had scattered his ashes. It was barely a moment, then he was gone from sight. Though I know it would have made mother and father upset, I took a torch and went to see for myself – yet there was nothing, only a thick carpet of flowers, even thicker than before, so thick it was impossible to see if any tracks lay in the dirt.\n\nI remained there for longer than I realized, for when I came to my senses, dawn was rising, and there I was in my nightclothes. Adriaen, I will watch for you, and next time, I shall be swifter – if you are to be found, it is I who will catch you if you wander outside the village.\n\nI took a flower and placed it in the sill, a reminder to you that I still think of you. Unlike the first flower, this flower was pulled easily from the soil at my touch, as if recognizing me.\n\nKathrijn</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_06">Empty Bed</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_06">06 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_06">My daughter, my precious daughter Kathrijn is gone. Her bed was not slept in, and on the sill, one of those horrid-smelling flowers, wilted and dead. They seem to infest the fields now like a blight, a vile weed that jests at our labors.\n\nThe men gathered together in search of her, and rode out in the early morning. It was nearly night before they returned, and they were half their number, their faces white. They would not answer our questions until they were inside, the door and shudders bolted. When I pressed for details, had they found her, they said nothing except that I must put her out of my mind.\n\nThe other men said nothing, merely clutched their weapons to them.\n\nMarisse</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_07">In the Flower Fields</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_07">07 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_07">Marten's daughter, Anika, claims to see have seen Kathrijn. She said she saw her with Adriaen, and two other men of the village who had gone missing. I told her where, and she said, “in the flower fields.” I told her to stop telling stories, and she went quiet at my tone. She asked quietly if she could sleep in my room, and I sent her to bed rather sternly. \n\nThe child has taken to sleeping beneath my bed when scared. If it gives her comfort, so be it. The poor child has nowhere else to sleep, and her presence makes Kathrijn's absence… it makes it less, for a time.\n\nMarisse</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_08">They Are Not Lost</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_08">08 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_08">I shared Anika's imagined tale of seeing Kathrijn and Adriaen with the millwright Elias, while we were drawing from the well. I cloaked Anika's tale with scorn, expecting him to shake his head sadly and offer sympathy.\n\nInstead, Elias went quiet, not with disbelief, but in that hesitation I know comes from fear of speaking the truth. I pressed him on it – even threatened to strike him, until at last he cried out that he had seen them, too.\n\n“They're not lost,” he said. “They've been coming back. Each of them… sometimes to the fields. We see them walking among the flower beds, but gone at our approach – we work in pairs now, for fear of being led off into whatever hell claimed them.”\n\nI told him that if we were lost out there, we would want to be found. He shook his head. “It is bad enough they have come back to us, we should not go looking for them. They aren't our people, our family anymore - they belong to the island.”\n\nMarisse</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_09">The Violet Sea</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_09">09 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_09">Elias has taken to checking on me. I do not leave the bed, I feel not myself. Elias volunteered to take Anika for a time, though the child still wishes to sleep here, beneath the bed, seemingly content to be close to me.\n\nI awake some nights, not certain of where I am – there is simply the smell of the flowers, all around us. It is a sea, calm, not like the storm-thrashed waves that surround the isle.\n\nMarisse</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_10">A Gift on the Sill</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_10">10 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_10">I awoke to a flower on the sill. Its petals were black, its stem resting in a dirty cup as if dug out of a river. The flower smelled of rot, yet I could not throw it out.\n\nI do not know how I knew, but I knew Kathrijn had left for it for me. My daughter had told me she was alive. That I should seek her out amongst the flowers.\n\nMarisse</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_11">Vanished</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_11">11 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_11">Marisse is gone. We went in search of her, even braved the darkness, but to no avail. We searched for two days and two nights. But her going missing - that is not the worst of it. Not at all. It was what I found on my return.\n\nWhen I returned, I immediately went to Marisse's bedroom to see if she had returned - and found flowers scattered about the bed, the same grave flowers that have swallowed our village.\n\nThe flowers… they are so bright when they lie in the earth, violet by day, yet blood red at dusk – and they die so quickly when cut from earth's embrace. We have seen the life this isle brings… we have not seen the death it brings, in all its shapes and kinds.\n\nI fear to say it, but this village is no longer ours. It belongs to all those who have gone missing. And soon we will lie like the petals about the bed in this village, each home now their home.\n\nElias</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_12">Black Petals</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_12">12 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_12">I was hiding beneath Marisse's bed when Elias returned. When he stood in the doorway, I didn't move. I hadn't moved since the night before - when Marisse had come home. And spread the flowers.\n\nWhen Elias found me, he asked about the flowers Marisse had scattered around the bed. I didn't tell him I had heard her return. I didn't tell him I had seen the flowers fall. I didn't tell him I was there.\n\nI didn't tell him because he is more scared than me, and adults are not supposed to be scared.\n\nI didn't tell him when she had come home, the floorboards did not make a sound. I didn't tell  him how afraid I was to breathe. How I saw Marisse's feet, dirty, torn, covered in scabs, as she walked slowly around the bed, a black petal falling with each step. I only closed my eyes and prayed until she was gone.\n\nBut she's not gone. None of them are. I need to find a new hiding place where no one knows.\n\nAnika</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_13">Hiding</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_13">13 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_13">I am still hiding. It has been three days - I have no more food, I am so hungry, but I am afraid to sneak out, to get more.\n\nAll the people of the village who had left came back. They smelled like the flowers in the fields when they are dug up. They don't speak, they simply walk, even do the same things they used to do but they don't do it properly – they do it like they barely remember how.\n\nI don't know how long I can stay here, but they are not leaving. I can hear them moving through the houses even now, their feet scraping on the floorboards, hear their breath. Sometimes… sometimes I think I hear Marisse, whispering my name. She wouldn't hurt me. She would never hurt me.\n\nAnika</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Title_01_14">Sound at the Door</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Subtitle_01_14">14 Subtitle</string>
<string key="FiveFarms_Body_01_14">I do not know how long I can stay here. I hear Marisse's voice more and more, in the distance, but I do not know if it is real. I am able to see the whole of the village from my hiding place now, so I do quick looks when I think it is safe.\n\nThis last time, I thought I saw Marisse in the field, walking toward me through the flowers – smiling, happy. If it is her, then I will run to her, and ask her to take me away from this horrid place.\n\nThere is a sound at the door – someone is here. Marisse?\n\nI can smell flowers, freshly cut. She has come for me, to lay the petals around me so I might sleep.\n\nAnika</string>

<string key="14_Edengrove_Chapter_03">Davies' Field Notes</string>
<string key="14_Edengrove_Title_03_01">Horned-Tooth Mandje</string>
<string key="14_Edengrove_Subtitle_03_01">The Mythical Eel</string>
<string key="14_Edengrove_Body_03_01">A scrap of notes from Master Fisher Davies' Journal:\n\nIn the fresh waters of Edengrove lurks a sea monster rarely sighted near the surface.\n\nHorned-Tooth Mandje, the mythical eel of legend, swims through fresh water undulating its long, slimy body through the waters.\n\nIts legend states that those who would harm the Horned-Tooth Mandje's waters would face her wrath, a massive tide coming to wash away the perpetrator. This is how Edengrove stays so clean, or at least one would imagine.</string>
<string key="14_Edengrove_Title_03_02">Azoth Waters</string>
<string key="14_Edengrove_Subtitle_03_02">Sparkling Blue</string>
<string key="14_Edengrove_Body_03_02">A scrap of notes from Master Fisher Davies' Journal:\n\nThe crystal blue water of Edengrove is inhabited by any number of fish who've mutated thanks to azoth's transformative powers. Fish with two heads, two hearts, and four fins aren't uncommon here, and fish in these waters often share traits. Just the other day I caught an Azoth-Tinged Fish whose dorsal fin was that of a swordfish and the pelvic fins were that of a bass.</string>