<string key="Topic_03_GreatCleave">Tales of Great Cleave</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_03_GreatCleave">The wintry advance towards the Shattered Mountain filled with Corrupted forces</string>

<string key="Topic_GreatBridge">Prieto's Log Book</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_GreatBridge">Musings of D. Prieto</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Chapter_01">Prieto's Notebook</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Title_01_01">The High Span</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Subtitle_01_01">01 Subtitle</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Body_01_01">Even though we have suffered much, and the Bridge has been taken from us, I still carry hope that one day we will be able to drive the Corrupted from its ramparts.\n\nI still recall the wonder when I first set eyes upon the bridge that crossed the Great Cleave. If there was every proof of the architectural skill of those who came before – the bridge quelled all doubts. It is a feat of engineering, something that could be said to rival the wonders of Europe and the East - if only others could see it.\n\nI've surveyed the bridge, both when I arrived, and from a distance later on – it is with great sadness we had to say farewell, to retreat, but I and the other settlers… it was too dangerous to remain within its shadow.\n\n-D. Prieto, Queensport Engineer</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Title_01_02">The Survey</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Subtitle_01_02">02 Subtitle</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Body_01_02">The Bridge seems a continuation of the Ancient roads that cut the isle. The massive pillars that support it suggest it was built to carry heavy cargo, most likely the great stone blocks that compose the Ancient ruins – for we discovered a temple on the Eastern side, complete with the great statues seen elsewhere on the isle. \n\nThe temple is not safe to explore, however: Wolves, seemingly of frost (!), stalk amongst the standing skeletons of the temple – yet I do not know which is worse, the wolves or the skeletons: the skeletons seem to watch us silently, their bone and armor perfectly preserved, spears in their hands of bone. Perhaps they once Bridge guards in times past. Now? They guard it in death.\n\nAs with the other Ancient structures I've surveyed, the Bridge seems a cross of mortared stones and pillars of rock that seemed to be shaped seamlessly from a single, great block of stone. How the Ancients constructed such marvels is a mystery – either they had armies of laborers, or, especially in the case of the uncut stone, perhaps a means of shaping the mountains and the canyons to their will, perhaps using the power of the Isle itself? \n\nWe may never know their mysteries, and with the Corrupted and the other creatures now atop the Bridge, we may never be able to uncover its secrets – if we survive at all.\n\n-D. Prieto, Engineer</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Title_01_03">Cold Fruits of Winter</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Subtitle_01_03">03 Subtitle</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Body_01_03">We underestimated them – we assumed the Corrupted cunning, yes, but in the back of our minds, we considered them our lessers, barely capable of speech, and still clinging to the garments of settlers of old. We saw them as nothing more than the same shells we had seen to the South – the Withered we eagerly cut down as we harvested what we could from the isle.\n\nThis arrogance has cost us the Cleave. \n\nThe Corrupted used the winter against us – as they always have, I now see. They don't feel the cold stabbing at them, it does not slow their march. And worse, the day they fell upon the Great Bridge, they proved capable of not just cunning, but tactics: they used a winter flurry to mask their approach on both roads leading to the Bridge, and even if the watch had time to call out, their voices were lost in the storm. The Corrupted then set upon the remaining soldiers – but none of them did they cut down. Instead they pinned them, shackled them, and carried them away – where? To the North, perhaps. If so, they did not remain there long – within a season, they had returned, the sight of which nearly broke us as we caught sight of our lost men and women upon the Bridge, side by side with the Corrupted.\n\n-D. Prieto, Engineer</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Title_01_04">Grey Sister</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Subtitle_01_04">04 Subtitle</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Body_01_04">The sight of them is like a knife to the heart. Losing the Bridge was a blow to our morale, but what occurred not soon after nearly pushed us to retreat from the Cleave entirely.\n\nThe entire season, the Corrupted still commanded the Bridge, but as the season ended, they were joined by others – and among their number, we saw our own brothers and sisters. They were standing guard as they had before, but this time, they stood not against the Corrupted – but with them. \n\nI still watch from afar, a single spyglass to pierce the storm. And when I raise the spyglass to see what lies there upon the Bridge, I see their commander, staring back at me, her eyes like two burning coals in the hollow of her face.\n\n-D. Prieto, Engineer</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Title_01_05">Counterattack</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Subtitle_01_05">05 Subtitle</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Body_01_05">I know not what to make of recent events – there are rumors of strange occurrences to the South, blue lights along the lanterns of the roads, and even the dead walking, azoth burning in their chests. I would have passed this off to rumors and wild tales…\n\n…had not the Bridge been touched by the same madness.\n\nI was watching through the spyglass when I saw the first of the Corrupted struck down, its head split from its shoulders – at first, I thought it was only by imagining, perhaps spurred by hope – but no, there was fighting upon the Bridge, another group perhaps, but it was certain – they were attacking the Corrupted!\n\nI sought another vantage point, but the sight gave me hope – I moved swiftly so I could see the battle play out, but this may be the turning point in our efforts!\n\n-D. Prieto, Engineer</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Title_01_06">The Ancients Awaken</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Subtitle_01_06">06 Subtitle</string>
<string key="GreatBridge_Body_01_06">At first I thought the fighting on the Bridge was perhaps a counterattack by another company, or a drunken dare by Merchand and his thugs (who have long boasted they could take the Bridge in their undergarments) – it was neither.\n\nMy heart froze colder than the surrounding frost as I saw skeletons, spheres of blue light burning in their chest, slowly marching the span of the Bridge – and when the Corrupted launched themselves at the attackers, the Ancient Keepers did not fall back but met them head-on: the Corrupted were ruthlessly cut down, their remains cast from the Bridge as they dissolved into ash, leaving only their weapons to fall to the stones below – in moments, the Ancient Keepers had taken half the Bridge, seemingly uncaring of the numbers of the Corrupted.\n\nI see now it was fortunate we had not staged the same assault, for the Corrupted had been prepared – for us, perhaps, but not this. In response to this unexpected attack, reinforcements swarmed the Bridge like ants, Corrupted erupting from hidden places in the surrounding rocks to drive back the Guardians – but to no avail.\n\nWhen the sun fell, the Bridge had once again changed hands – and the Corrupted were no longer its master. The blue fire in the chests of the Guardians lit the top of the Bridge now, marking it as their own.\n\n-D. Prieto, Engineer</string>

<string key="Topic_TideBattle">Queensport Battle Log</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_TideBattle">Battle Log of the Great Cleave</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Chapter_01">Tides of Battle</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Title_01_01">Long in the Tooth</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Subtitle_01_01">01 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Body_01_01">Even the snows fight us. It slows our march, and sinks its fangs into us, as if hungry to drain our warmth. It is a friend and ally to the Corrupted - the Corrupted use it as cover, hide in it, and strike without warning – we are only flesh, and while the isle may grant many of us a rebirth (or curse us), it does nothing to drive the cold from us. \n\nFrostbite has claimed many of us, and some of us have not the fingers to hold weapons, nor the strength to walk where the cold has eaten at their feet and toes. Several of us do not believe the Cleave is worth holding at this price, and many more believe that we have already lost to the Corrupted and the elements.\n\nStill, we march. Still, we fight. I fear if we do not hold the Cleave, and we withdraw to warmer climes, we will be surrendering the heart of the isle to the Corrupted.\n\nYet we continue to fight, one and all.</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Title_01_02">Changing of the Watch</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Subtitle_01_02">02 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Body_01_02">The Bridge exposes us to the harshest wind, and many of us seek shelter behind the stone blocks. The watchmen at the bridge's end are not so fortunate – they must stare into the whipping wind and keep their eyes open to the threat of an attack – whether the frost wolves to the east, who are growing in number, or the incursions of Corrupted to the North. They must keep their eyes open, even when their lids are in danger of freezing solid.\n\nThe two Wathers draw straws to see who mans the East edge of the Bridge. For as terrible as an attack by the Corrupted might be, the shadow of the ancient temple there and the way the wolves seem drawn to it is unsettling, and adds further burden to a Watcher's heart.</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Title_01_03">Movement in the Snow</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Subtitle_01_03">03 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Body_01_03">The Watchers on the western edge of the Bridge has reported of a new development – he claims to see silhouettes moving in the snows, out of gunshot and arrow range, moving in such small numbers as to be a waste of a target to our siege engines. Yet, he sees a few of these shapes a day – and there is no hint of their destination.\n\n“I fear they are hiding in plain sight, digging beneath the snow,” one Watcher muttered by the fire. “If they were there, we wouldn't know it until their blades were at our throat.”\n\nThe other Watcher laughed, but without humor. “That would be a mercy, to be free from this hell.”\n\nThere are other hells, I thought. Earlier in the season, I had seen what had happened to one of our band of scouts, walking with the Corrupted, marching in pace with them – not as slaves, but as the Corrupted themselves. There are other hells - the cold is but one of them, and far from the worst.</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Title_01_04">Watch's End</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Subtitle_01_04">04 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Body_01_04">Soldiers are deserting. The gloom that consumed Wickbury was a blow to everyone, as was the sightings of what seemed to be priests leading the Corrupted. We were not fighting an army – we were fighting a crusade from the North. The loss of the Bridge only added to our woes, and many saw little to hold onto. “We cannot stop a tide that has already filled our flanks and now rises before us upon the Bridge. The battle will not be won here, we must retreat to Brightwood.”\n\nThe talk grows in the camps. In the times when we were united in purpose, any such talk would earn lashes – cruel, but perhaps necessary. But then again, that may be why the alliance fell. Hearts may harden across many deaths, until you feel little at all. After that, there lies little difference between the Corrupted and the soldiers.\n\nIf we do not fight the Corrupted, they will consume us. If we fight the Corrupted, they will consume us. Either way, the spirit is tested, and it can only be tested so far before it breaks.\n\n\n-L.G., Acting Captain</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Title_01_05">Beyond the Cleave</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Subtitle_01_05">05 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Body_01_05">One of Rutherford's scouts returned – he was one of the ones who had drunk the Brightlake concoction, the one that gave strength to the spirit, and lessened the poison of the lands north of the Cleave. He had suffered, true, but he came to us in right mind, and – to our amazement – smiling.\n\n“They're not just what we once were,” he said. “They're still like us. I've seen beyond the fortifications – they have farms. Towns. Even what might be a church, at the summit of the mountain!”\n\nThe men mumbled their surprise, but I was the first to speak in anger – I held my tongue, to give the man some moments of peace to enjoy his return, but his words angered me beyond all reason. I shall walk, collect my thoughts – this fool of a scout, he does not know the truth in what he saw.\n\nIf we have not yet lost this war, the sighting of the church has done so, whether the soldiers realize it or not.\n\n-L.G., Acting Captain</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Title_01_06">The Red Church</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Subtitle_01_06">06 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Body_01_06">Rutherford's scout continued to speak as the night wore on, as if his words were intended to give hope – he prattled on, continuing on about the farms, the structures near the Shattered Mountain – the ‘civilization' in the North. When he spoke again of the church that he had seen, I could take no more.\n\n“You saw a church,” I heard myself say. “Yet the Corrupted have no religion like any we know. You think this means they are to be reasoned with? That peace will be easier? A church only means we have a canyon wider than the Great Cleave between us – not physically, but in spirit. We know they do not seek to kill us. Do you welcome conversion to… to that?!”\n\nI pointed at the crown of the Shattered Mountain, the isle torn from its foundation. “You think you bring words of hope, that we might make peace, but I tell you – in a single structure, you have given us proof that there will be no peace until we are all as they are, and all worship as they do.”\n\nWe are no match for the Corrupted if a twisted religion drives them. I had no patience to speak to the man further – I shall do question him again when I have calmed myself.\n\n-L.G., Acting Captain</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Title_01_07">Further Word</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Subtitle_01_07">07 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Body_01_07">The Rutherford scout, ashamed at my harsh words, did not boast further of his discoveries to the north, and the hope left his features. I felt no remorse in his newfound silence, for best he lose hope now and let truth guide his actions.\n\nI interrogated him most thoroughly. He said that yes, he had seen remnants soldiers we had lost in the camps to the North. He had seen many things… not simply the foul church he had seen, brimming with red light, but the labor of the Corrupted, and worse… leaders. The Priests we had seen upon the Bridge were not unique – there were many, all serving whatever twisted religion led them.\n\nWe had already seen what they could do at the Bridge… at the Wickbury. And would likely do so again – to think they numbered more than the three we had seen – it is a dark thought.\n\n-L.G., Acting Captain</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Title_01_08">The Obelisks</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Subtitle_01_08">08 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Body_01_08">What almost broke me was when the returning scout spoke of the obelisks. Not the ones we'd seen to the South, not the ones common elsewhere in the isle. He saw others, larger ones, being excavated by the Corrupted. Worse, there were other obelisks already unearthed… but these obelisks, freed from the earth – and the scout paused at this, for I feel the import of his words was at last becoming clear to him – he said these obelisks seemed… alive, floating above cyst-like wells in the landscape – floating stones, like the one atop the mountain, harnessed by the Corrupted and their priests.\n\n“Like they are making a claim,” I prompted. His eyes widened at that, and before he could express his confusion, I cut him off. “Not like ours. Never like ours. A claim that is their own, one that will consume this isle. And in coming here, by adding to their ranks – why we've shown them the way to destroy us.”\n\nWe must fallback to the Brightwood. Others must know of what we've found.\n\n-L.G., Acting Captain</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Title_01_09">Field of Madness</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Subtitle_01_09">09 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Body_01_09">We retreated into the forests, conserving our powder. We fell back on familiar trails, careful to strike at the Corrupted and then retreat before more came to its aid. When one of us fell, a soldier would stab a blade through the victim so that they might re-awaken faster and rejoin us at the front. The grudges among the soldiers grow, but in others, it becomes a curious competition, to stave off the most deaths – and for others, to quickly spill the blood of the fallen so they feel as little pain as possible and awaken, still ready to fight.\n\nIt is a field of madness. We fight the Corrupted who have our corrupted brothers and sisters among their number, who, too, seem reborn to fight – we slaughter them as we slaughter our own, all for gaining a few feet of ground, to briefly hold a slice of the Ancients road – to anoint this land and claim its azoth with our blood.\n\nWhen I stare at the Corrupted – the ones who bear tattered shreds of an age of a hundred years ago, or wear a rusted mask of a Conquisitador, I wonder if settlers ages past went through this cycle as well – and the only victory was in the corruption that spreads like the blood upon the snows.</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Title_01_10">Blind South</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Subtitle_01_10">10 Subtitle</string>
<string key="TideBattle_Body_01_10">I ran into people from the South, where they still fight over wood and flint and timber – great matters to them, but their words, their actions almost sparked me to anger.\n\nDid they not see who we fought? Did they not see the Withered and the Wraiths and the Corrupted as but the first symptoms of something far more terrible? \n\nTheir eyes are filled with azoth – and in a terrible moment, it reminded me of the fire in the eyes of the Corrupted, the twisted red light that seemed to drive them to violence, that seemed to consume them.\n\nAnd I wondered if perhaps the Corruption and the azoth were both of the same well from which we drew.</string>

<string key="Topic_Excavation">Lipscomb Letters</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_Excavation">Personal Messages of J. Lipscomb</string>
<string key="Excavation_Chapter_01">The Excavation</string>
<string key="Excavation_Title_01_01">Buried Constellations</string>
<string key="Excavation_Subtitle_01_01">01 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Excavation_Body_01_01">I almost wish the sparkling rock had not caught our eye, but so it did. Now here we are, and beasts the like of which have never been seen remind me we are strangers to this isle – and the farther north we go, both man and beast alike, become more feral and unapproachable.\n\nThe danger started simply enough – while scouring the track, Dunne caught traces of that glittering rock, the one that glitters like stars lie within. Seeing pieces of the ore lying quite thickly about, we spent days looking for a vein of the stuff and sought to mine it. To be sure, we feared the sound of our pickaxes would wake the Corrupted from the Cleave - but that was not to be our misfortune.\n\nAs we unearthed the “Star Rock” day upon day and piled it upon the wagons for the outpost, we could not help but notice the days grew colder and colder, more sharply each night. We had learned not to stray too far east and south on account of the great bears, but the sudden onset of winter was something we had not expected. Dunne had caught sight of wolves, he claimed, but he said they did not howl, nor move as he had ever seen a wolf move – he said that they looked as if they were rimed with ice, wreathed around like a coat of winter.\n\n-J. Lipscomb</string>
<string key="Excavation_Title_01_02">A Wolf Wreathed in Ice</string>
<string key="Excavation_Subtitle_01_02">02 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Excavation_Body_01_02">I saw one of the strange wolves today. Dunne did as well, though he is not here to speak of it. It was mid-day, and I saw it all play out most clearly.\n\nWe had lifted some of the star ore to the carts, when suddenly, soundless, there was a wolf – a thing shaped as a wolf – at the opening of the mine. It was as if it had just broken free from a glacier, for spikes of ice covered its coat, as if the two were wedded.\n\nI bid my muscles to move, to run, to scream, yet I could do nothing. Dunne was not so fortunate – he issued a cry, as if to drive the thing off, and held a chunk of the starmetal over his head threateningly: as he did, the beast was suddenly upon him, its jaws at his throat. My eyes did not deceive me – I watched as frost blanketed Dunne's throat where the fangs sank into flesh and froze the blood as it jetted from his wound.\n\nI confess I did not stop to aid him – I fled into the mine, hiding there, praying warmth shall return to my bones. If I escape this place, I shall not return, for I am convinced those beasts did not arrive by chance – our working of the ore must have brought them, as if they sought to guard it against those who would take it.\n\nI hereby relinquish my claim to this mine – if others wish it, they must answer to the devils in the ice and make peace with them.\n\n-J. Lipscomb</string>

<string key="Topic_Eastburn">Eastburn Ledger</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_Eastburn">The records of William Eastburn, honorable thespian</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Chapter_01">The Theatre</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Title_01_01">The Storm</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Subtitle_01_01">01 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Body_01_01">After much turmoil, Elizabeth and I have made it through the storm. This foul tempest has claimed the rest of our troupe… Alcott, Bancroft and Blythe are no longer with us. But alas, the show must go on! Elizabeth and I must simply find a new crew. A new audience awaits us - And with the power of theatre, we shall enrich their hearts and minds!\n\n-William Eastburn</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Title_01_02">Hamlet</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Subtitle_01_02">02 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Body_01_02">Earlier today, a miracle occurred! Alcott, Bancroft and Blythe, battered and smashed against the rocks not one week ago, have returned to us perfectly well! I saw them run through on the spires with my own two eyes, but here they stand… risen from the grave to join us in our cause. They appear veritably shaken even now, but they are glad to be alive once again.\n\nOn this island, can we not perish? How brilliant, how mad! Imagine how this could be used to heighten the realism of our shows... To see Juliet run through with the knife, to see Hamlet cut down with the sword! I must tell the crew at once. I will become the greatest showman the world has ever seen!\n\n-William Eastburn</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Title_01_03">Rehearsals</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Subtitle_01_03">03 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Body_01_03">Rehearsals for our performance have begun, but it is clear that the crew is less committed than I am. They've run through these scenes a dozen times, but talks of “pain” have now dominated their conversations. Even Elizabeth, my dear sweet muse, is prompting me to omit the scene of Blythe's beheading- the CLIMAX, of all things! There is only so much complaining I can take!\n\nWe've taken refuge at the Inn in Cleave's Point. The place is full of scoundrels and thieves, but when they heard of our play they were brimming with excitement! If only Alcott and Bancroft understood my work like they do…\n\nThese blithering fools! Do they not respect me enough to give me their all? To be a true artist, one must be willing to suffer for their art! Heaven knows I have, with all their complaining. If god must strike me down, so be it. Rehearsals shall continue as planned.\n\n-William Eastburn</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Title_01_04">The Show Must Go On</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Subtitle_01_04">04 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Body_01_04">The final dress rehearsal has come and gone, and these petulant worms have hardly an ounce to give me! Alcott and Bancroft give their performances well, but I must chain them up in the night to keep them from deserting me. Even worse, Blythe's speech has started to slur- and last night she tried to cleave my head from off of my shoulders!\n\nI'm keeping Blythe under lock and key until further notice, as it is clear she is unable to perform. To prevent the spread of her feral nature, I've kept her locked away, far from the others. Elizabeth, to my dismay, was distraught when I informed her that she would play the role instead- but the show must go on! She has not died before thus far, and that will make the beheading even sweeter… Oh joy! What a show this will be! Cleave's Point will be in awe of my brilliance!\n\n-William Eastburn</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Title_01_05">Elizabeth</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Subtitle_01_05">05 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Eastburn_Body_01_05">I thought I understood the nature of this island. But like Icarus before me, I have flown too close to the sun.\n\nElizabeth played the part perfectly. Every line, brimming with emotion… but when the beheading came, she faltered. She cried out to me, pleaded, but in my brash foolishness I had Bancroft drop the axe. When she dissipated into dust, she did not return… Instead, she sparked with an energy I have never seen before. Her voice screamed out from the heavens what a terrible man I was, and that she would haunt me for eternity. Then, my beloved muse vanished.\n\nAlcott and Bancroft have left me, seizing the opportunity to take flight as I mourned upon the stage. Blythe has now begun to decay, and I fear she may break from her chains at any moment.\n\nEvery night I am tormented by visions of Elizabeth, hanging over my bed to punish me for my transgressions. As the sun sets, I can hear her voice wail from over the walls. Now I only wish for death, but it never comes. Every time I try, I can feel something foul welling up inside of me…\n\nOh, what a fool I was! What an insolent, vain, blithering, insufferable fool. I knew of their pain, and I cared not. What a curse this island is! Blast the fates that brought me here!\n\nIf only I had understood their suffering. If only I had cared.\n\n-William Eastburn</string>

<string key="03_GreatCleave_Chapter_05">Plans of the Corrupted</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_05_01">Mysterious Orders</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_05_01">Found in Sunderfort</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_05_01">**The page is covered in strange symbols and markings, looking like no language you have ever encountered, yet somehow the sounds come unbidden into your mind. You recognize the circle-and-split-fork design used as the banner by the Corrupted across Aeternum. Could this be their language?** \n\nUbemabayib mit'enggâf fip'anda ambi. Ngo atwak fi 'av mifiwo ñâb. Wu p'â kuñ mip'ânfâp ag, p'â edendakti pad Aeternum ven af.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_05_02">The Twisted Smelter</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_05_02">Found in Acedia Bastion</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_05_02">**This page is covered with the symbols and markings you've come to know as the Corrupted language. The foreign sounds fill your head as you read. This page has a crude drawing of a smelter, and some liquid being poured into crucibles.**\n\nMiven pad fangok fi Aeternum yi kot'une ñân p'â ve urompi xapwing ambi. Âbtahâr pad azoth deñâñogambi euwângubda rongembi. Ngo xagimbi he akimbi ika'atku miwod itkâ âbtawungu 'ufoxo axo.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_05_03">Bonemeal</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_05_03">Found in Breakaway Fort</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_05_03">**A page with the cramped symbols of the Corrupted language. Taking up much of the page is a sketch of skulls and bones being pounded to dust.** \n\nUbamabayib rugi impane 'adoh uwâkombe azoth kevambi yi detwek. Baguf xak'ov bab mi a p'ânvâboxo pab ambi. Xa xauwâñâb ñâna ko, ngo uwâkombe 'ami xaipix xa pab veh axo, he mip'âtweg ubaxahev xakong ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_05_04">Ritual Mine</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_05_04">Found in Hollowing Fort</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_05_04">**Another page with more of the Corrupted writing. This page has a drawing of miners digging ore from the depths, and what appears to be one of the Corrupted Cultists leading a ritual.** \n\nXafang bing Magmebeg umik'ig vetix at pa ngub a, fa nena pad miwonuykañ a atkifitorambi. Xayi miawi xa ñâtwap mi'anutu mip'u nguboxo.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_05_05">Clearcutting</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_05_05">Found in Nullcavity</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_05_05">**Yet another page written by the Corrupted. Along the side of the page are images of trees being cut and dragged away for some unknown purpose.** \n\nXayup pad tif tid gufoxo ubatif mimak'â'a fi pab nero yi p'â ag 'umbi mi a. Bar vetimbi, uatkiguf panumbi heñ ika'atku axo he ngo ubaguf miwod kengâmbi.</string>

<string key="03_GreatCleave_Chapter_06">James' Letters</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_06_01">Request for Reassignment</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_06_01">Found in Tempest Lane</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_06_01">To the attention of: General Alazar\nName: James Sexton, Soulwarden\nCurrent post: Eastburn Outpost, Great Cleave\nRequested post: Anywhere else\n\nAdd'l. Notes:\nI'll take whatever we've got. Send me to the front lines in Shattered Mountain, if that's what it takes. No battle can be more painful than the memories I have here, with her.\n-J.S.\n</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_06_02">One Last Love Letter</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_06_02">Written in a shaky hand</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_06_02">Patricia, my love,\n\nThe tincture isn't working. My leg is turning black, and the ice is creeping toward my heart. I was in such a hurry to leave this place, I got sloppy. I let the Corrupted overwhelm me. Now, it seems, I'll never leave.\n\nHow ridiculous, to lie in the snow and wait for the end, to scribble my last words in the dark! I wish you'd ran away with me, all those times I asked. If only I'd found the right words then. \nMaybe this is for the best. When they recover my Heartgem from my corpse, they'll lay it next to yours.\n\nI'll be with you soon.\n-James\n</string>

<string key="03_GreatCleave_Chapter_07">The Herald's Victory</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_07_01">Pictures On The Wall</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_07_01">Found in Eeriedune Graveyard</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_07_01">My followers have completed construction of the village, under my guidance. I have spent much of my time planning our future, and one thing concerns me: the Corruption to the north, past the Ancient gate. And while some called me a fool to do so, I set forth to see this evil for myself.\nI ventured north of the gate, able to avoid the attentions of the demons long enough to learn what I needed to. But, fate decided to set me on a new path. Climbing through the mountain passes, I slipped and found myself in a ruin of the Ancients. Inside, artifacts and riches filled the cave to the brim, but what drew me in were the murals on the wall. I did not recognize something specific in them at first, but having studied the spiritual paths of many, I should be able to recognize a ritual!\nFrom my loose understanding of the murals, I believe the Ancients had a way of sanctifying areas on the island, explaining why the settlements to the south are protected from attack. These murals showed me how to do the same! This may be the best way to protect my flock, to give them the peace that so many of them deserve.\nI claimed the artifacts in the cave, bringing back as many as I was able to carry, and have matched many to the murals. I must determine how this ritual was done so that I may perform it here for the village, and will not rest until I do!</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_07_02">Scorched Earth</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_07_02">Found in Misty Borough</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_07_02">&lt;i&gt;I have done it. I now understand how the Ancients performed their wonderful, terrible, ritual. I have already taken the first steps, distributing the tokens to each of the townsfolk.&lt;/i&gt;\n\nNo, I mustn't! It is wrong, it is foolish, it is evil! Their wills exterminated! I don't... I need, I must...\n\n&lt;i&gt;As the Herald of this flock, it falls to me to make the hard decisions for everyone. I held a meeting at the church and explained that the ritual would protect this hilltop... and all in attendance agreed that we must do whatever we can to protect ourselves...&lt;/i&gt;\n\nSomething in those ruins, unclear how... I am fighting for control, but I feel it winning. I have given my most trusted follower specific instructions on what to do. Being near the stone lends me strength, but I know it must be consumed in the ritual. This... will be the last time I have control, and I cannot stop the ritual. But... my flock, they will not be taken by Corruption. Their souls, their minds, will be freed. It is the only way.</string>

<string key="03_GreatCleave_Chapter_08">Klaus' Memories</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_08_01">Blue-Winged Serpe</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_08_01">Beast of the Water</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_08_01">There is a creature, a blue winged serpent that lurks in the Great Cleave's waters. Some don't believe it exists, but I've had it on my line more than once and that is one tricky beastie.\n\nI've heard it roaring in the night, breaching the water like a dolphin to let loose its terrible cry. One day it shall be mine, and then no one will doubt me.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_08_02">Soulwarden Supplies</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_08_02">Feeding the Troops</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_08_02">The Soulwardens, a noble order of Aeternum, are at times all that stand between the southern settlements and complete Corruption.\n\nThey operate in Corruption-heavy areas and dish out punishment towards those who would attack innocents and spread their Corrupted filth whether by offering power or force.\n\nThey may have just arrived but they're already doing some good for this island, so I've thrown my support behind them. Will you help me as well, Machera?</string>

<string key="03_GreatCleave_Chapter_09">Corpora Oseguera</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_09_01">Codex I</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_09_01">Paiveti p'ekome, mikuñ Efiki pad bih Eipa ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_09_01">Bi xak'ub pad xap'âni, kot'uneok t'etâknângik at ambi uyih pad. Mav kot'uneok tu añipambi 'ag K'ox Eipa, yi kot'uneok ñix ambi.\nMav kot'uneok tu 'ag Eâbtak'ongek manâx, t'ei kot'uneok tu ambi yâmbi.\nHe kot'uneok tu t'etâknângik 'adoh, yi kot'uneok ñix ambi. Ngo bih fa kot'uneok ven t'etâknângik at ambi.\nEpab eher pad bih Eipa ven ambi. He bih eipa i'âba Ketiro 'apâmbi ven ba rungegambi.\n\nPaikitkâ Ubakomeo Oseguera</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_09_02">Codex II</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_09_02">Paiveti p'ekome, Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook xa bih u'aping ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_09_02">He xa Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook bih Ubeipa uwâruknâr fipin ungok.\n\nNgo bih Eâbtabig Eâbtak'uko Uwâruna axo.\nBing Ingot fipin Uwâñi p'â yâk'up fa. Bing Uwâkombe fipin Âbta'atku p'â dek'ân fa.\nK'o ñâkaok pad k'oba he de, Uwângov p'â ngokoxo.\n\nPaikitkâ Ubakomeo Oseguera</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_09_03">Codex III</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_09_03">Paiveti p'ekome, Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook xa bih u'aping ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_09_03">He xa Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook bih Ubeipa uwâruknâr fipin ungok.\n\nNgo bih Eâbtabimbi Eâbtak'uko 'Atkâ axo.\nMab bih Uwâñi fipin p'â Ngo'ook p'â k'unoxo. Mab Ngo'ook fipin 'Agmox p'â rompuxo fa.\nXa kendu mirux urompu.\nXa Tik.\nXa Ngoñ.\nXa Gab.\n\nPaikitkâ Ubakomeo Oseguera</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_09_04">Codex IV</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_09_04">Paiveti p'ekome, Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook xa bih u'aping ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_09_04">He xa Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook bih Ubeipa uwâruknâr fipin ungok.\n\nNgo bih Eâbta'ag Eâbtak'uko Yiñâmbâ axo.\nYed 'Agmox fipin Magmebeg p'â kâknahoxo. Yed 'Agmox fipin p'â At'u vevu xamitâñ ganexo.\nXa Uwâgañ fipin miñâg p'â 'afahoxo.\n\nPaikitkâ Ubakomeo Oseguera</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_09_05">Codex V</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_09_05">Paiveti p'ekome, Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook xa bih u'aping ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_09_05">He xa Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook bih Ubeipa uwâruknâr fipin ungok.\n\nNgo bih Eâbtubafix Eâbtak'uko bih Eâbtabig, bih Eâbta'atki, he bih Eâbtakendu ambi.\nXa Eâbtakendu, Uwângov p'â ngokoxo.\nXa Eâbtakendu, Eâbtak'uko p'â ngokoxo.\nÂbtakenduok fa Eâbtativ eher pad bih Ewupwat ven ambi.\n\nPaikitkâ Ubakomeo Oseguera</string>