<string key="Topic_12_MonarchsBluffs">Tales of Monarch's Bluffs</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_12_MonarchsBluffs">Hilly bluffs with an island fortress that stands tall against the waves</string>
<string key="Topic_AnonymousManuscripts">Anonymous Manuscripts</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_AnonymousManuscripts">Various letters, diaries, and other writings of authors unknown</string>

<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Chapter_04">Squash Farmers</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_04_01">The River Provides</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_04_01">Found in Tres Campos</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_04_01">This 2nd year harvest proves our stubbornness was justified. Already more are clamoring to join our budding community. The soil is rich and the river provides.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_04_02">The Community Grows</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_04_02">Found in Tres Campos</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_04_02">It is wonderful to now have neighbors! Our shared toil has enriched the lives of us all. 4th year harvest is just around the bend and my heart soars.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_04_03">A Sudden Turn</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_04_03">Found in Tres Campos</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_04_03">Something peculiar has been discovered in the fields. We have lost a good portion of our harvest to a rot that appeared, quite literally, overnight. We have seen no worm or fly, yet the fruit is blackened and bruised. And the soil reeks of death.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_04_04">The Odd Tempest</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_04_04">Found in Tres Campos</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_04_04">There was quite the lightning storm last night. The river would glow with each strike and the mill cast long, spastic shadows across the fields. If I subscribed to the superstitions of my kin, I would call it an ill omen. But there is no denying the grand spectacle it was. The whole village sheltered together and gasped in time with each thunder clap.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_01_05">Undying Rot</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_01_05">Found in Tres Campos</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_01_05">Our crops continue to rot as villagers leave one by one. Those who were stubborn enough to stay are now too stubborn to leave. Those foolish enough to eat these crops turn gravely ill. All our harvests fail, what did we do to deserve this blight?</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_01_06">Running Away</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_01_06">Found in Tres Campos</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_01_06">I sense that the lightning storm was merely the beginning of the end for our lives here. We've had vicious attacks from these... monsters. Husks that seem human, but only ravage and destroy. The remaining families have lost members in the attacks, and we survivors are now forced to flee this area. We have no choice but to leave.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_01_07">Brief Respite</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_01_07">Found at Lakeside Farms</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_01_07">We've had some luck to move farther north. We've found fertile land and decided to rebuild. Nestled within the crags that surround it, we soon saw a small lake as a respite in our journey and replanted our crops. Scorching our tools, we found that fire cleansed them of the stench of the blight. We remain vigilant in how we use the soil. But, we are unsure if those freaks with the red eyes will find us here, too. Mayhap it is only a matter of time...\n\n-F. Sneed</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_01_08">In the Shade of Farside</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_01_08">Found in Farside Township</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_01_08">Some of us have settled in the west side of the valley, naming the farm "Lakeside." We settled opposite of them to the east, naming our township "Farside." The crags and trees shroud that soil in a year-round shade. Though this would be detrimental to some crops, we've found these conditions perfect to grow a healthy rhubarb crop on this island. The Lakeside families shared with the Farside families a technique to hold back the blight: cleansing the tools we use with fire. May it help us survive the horrors of this island.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_01_09">Last Judgement</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_01_09">Found in Farside Township</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_01_09">The attacks begin again, but none of us were under the naive impression that those fiends would leave us alone. Lakeside has already fallen, and the red-eyed monsters are swarming on Farside. Those of us that have survived these attacks have decided to make for the settlement to the north in Devil's Quarry. It is the last judgement for us, and the settlement may be our only salvation.</string>

<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Chapter_02">How Deep the Well?</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_02_01">Casting Stones</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_02_01">A loose page from an anonymous diary.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_02_01">I wish they would discipline that child. I have shooed him away from the well more times than I can count. Yet still today… there again. Casting stones.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_02_02">One Stone Too Many</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_02_02">A loose page from an anonymous diary.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_02_02">I woke to a faint scream and a splash. I found a pile of stones on the edge of the well. I called to no answer then sent the remaining stones to the depths.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_02_03">Still Missing</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_02_03">A torn and unsigned letter.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_02_03">Our child has still not been found. I never imagined a heart could ache so.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_02_04">Suspicions</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_02_04">A torn and unsigned letter.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_02_04">We now believe the old crone may know something about our child's disappearance. She would never cease complaining about the noise of innocent play and has offered little in the way of concern.</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_03">Notes from Traitor's Hold</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_03_01">Captain's Demands</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_03_01">Found in Traitor's Hold</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_03_01">I don't think I can take much more of this. I try my best to craft weapons for these insolent pirates, and all I am met with are more demands from this mad Captain! All he wants is more shine, more gilded handles... I am collecting my due fees, and quite a handsome pay at that, but I shall decidedly not put my mark on these weapons. In fact, I would be ashamed to admit these trinkets are my own work!\n\n-L. Harrison, Master Artificer</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_03_02">Pistoleer's Plight</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_03_02">Found in Traitor's Hold</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_03_02">The damn weapons won't even fire! What use are these damn things if they're nothing but pretty toys!</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_04">Missives from the Mines</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_04_01">The Plight of a Gambler</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_04_01">Found in Mines de Miclot</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_04_01">Just one more... These damned walking cadavers, their blank eyes glowing red. Mocking me. My wounds cloud my head, but just one more...</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_04_02">Belly Full of Riches</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_04_02">Found in Mines de Miclot</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_04_02">Quite curious is the case of the creatures in this mine! As some lucky adventurers have discovered, these fiends do in fact eat any gems they find. One could hypothesize that in life they worked these mines, once a rich source of precious stones on Aeternum. However, one must ask, why do they eat them? The idea I propose is based on their patterns of hoarding! They must have some semblance of the value of these stones and, in a lust to hoard wealth, they put such small stones into the safest place they can muster: their own bodies!\n\nFinding precious gems in the belly of these poor wretches is still rare. Some guess that only one in a group of ten Withered may have a gem in their belly. With that in mind, good luck! You may need it.\n\n-Dr. H. Garrison</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_05">Ranching by Riverside</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_05_01">Stenchfork</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_05_01">Found in Arruda Ranch</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_05_01">Some madman attacked me! He was crazed and wild, with red eyes that struck fear in my heart. I held him back with my pitchfork, and he ran away. The stink coming off of him is one I will not soon forget. Now, that stench won't come off my pitchfork no matter how many times I wash it.\n\n-Tomas</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_06">Lee's Reconnaissance</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_06_01">Now I See</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_06_01">Found in Archernar</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_06_01">Now I see what Thorton was talking about in her last letter. These Ancient Guardians are ferocious, suspended in undeath to guard the ruins of a society we may never understand. Well, out with the old and in with the new as I always say. I will try to cull as many Ancient Guardians as I can while out hunting so that Survivalist Thorton might have some relief from their blockades. If only I had someone to help with this...</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_06_02">Lee's Special Pants</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_06_02">Found in Archernar</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_06_02">Those bastards! Those dastardly, villainous fiends! The mace-wielding miscreants of Archernar killed me, and even worse, they damaged my pants! This is azoth-infused silk, and incredibly hard to come by. It isn't easy being the most fashion-forward Survivalist of all the settlements but it's a title with which I find immense pride. I will have my revenge for this affront to my aesthetics.</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_07">Deals with the Devil</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_07_01">Punishment</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_07_01">Found in Devil's Quarry</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_07_01">Coming to this island was a mistake. I came to this island seeking fortune and riches. But, I was mislead. This place is no heaven...\n\nAs I lie here, dying, I feel my soul leaving this husk. Ah, is this how it felt Faustus? To have body and soul ripped to pieces by the claws of fiends?\n\nMaybe, like Faustus, my fate was sealed when I signed to come to this place. Maybe coming to this island was both my sin and my punishment.\n\nOh, Margarete...</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_08">The Ballad of Madman Montore</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_08_01">The Last Words of a Doomed Sailor</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_08_01">Found in Deadman's Anchor</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_08_01">I hear his footsteps coming closer, his boots booming against the wooden planks beneath me... He'll make quick work of the flimsy door and barricade I've created. Montore has gone mad. He's slaughtered his own crew as we crashed on the island. But, more terrifying than that, the dead sailors around me seem to come back to life. Their eyes are empty, twisted by Montore's madness. I hide here, but I know that I too will meet the same fate. This entire expedition was doomed.</string>

<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Chapter_03">Unknown Explorer</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_03_01">The Noise</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_03_01">A loose journal page signed with an X.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_03_01">I saw the strange blue flashes light up the hillside again last night. And there was a noise… hard to describe… melodious, but also dreadful. Like something out of a dream. I have not had a decent night's sleep in weeks.\n\n- X</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_03_02">Care is Abandoned</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_03_02">A loose journal page signed with an X.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_03_02">I question the wisdom of this location for rest and storage. It is beset upon nightly by wolves. There must be a den nearby. It is strange how cavalier some have become in this place. As if death was all there is to fear, and now that it has forsaken us, all care is abandoned.\n\n- X</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_03_03">Who Walked First?</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_03_03">A loose journal page signed with an X.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_03_03">This archway appears to predate the temples and monoliths. I wonder who the first to walk this accursed land were and what befell them. These are the thoughts that haunt my eternal, sleepless, nights.\n\n- X</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_03_04">Tempting Fates</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_03_04">A loose journal page signed with an X.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_03_04">We have set camp near the burned hovel, despite my words of dissent. I'm not so quick to dismiss the past. Why tempt the fates? Are we doomed to repeat the same mistakes for all eternity?\n\n- X</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_03_05">Full Moon</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_03_05">A loose journal page signed with an X.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_03_05">On nights like this, when the full moon glistens through the tall trees and the very air itself seems to reverberate with warmth and power, it can be easy to forget the horror of our plight. The dire battle we wage to keep our very souls fades like a distant dream. Such is the insidious nature of this hell.\n\n- X</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_03_06">Sleep of the Dead</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_03_06">A loose journal page signed with an X.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_03_06">I sleep like the dead. The temperate air and soothing sounds of the waterfall put me in such a state… It is not unlike a drunken stupor. My senses feel dulled and my body detached. Why in this place of eternal life, do I feel less alive than ever?\n\n- X</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_03_07">Again the Noise</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_03_07">A loose journal page signed with an X.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_03_07">That awful noise filled the air. And fire. Blue fire.\n\n- X</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_03_08">Ancient Grove</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_03_08">A loose journal page signed with an X.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_03_08">This seems to mark an entrance to what is now a modest, if it can be called that, grove of Wyrdwood trees. These “Ancients” clearly valued this place. But for what? What secrets do these strange trees hold?\n\n- X</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_03_09">Quite the View</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_03_09">A loose journal page signed with an X.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_03_09">From this vantage, the largest of the spires cuts through the sky. It is clear that their locations held great meaning. But to what end?\n\n- X</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_03_10">Grand Stairs</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_03_10">A loose journal page signed with an X.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_03_10">Such a feat of engineering! And yet there seems to be no attempt to harness the power of the falls themselves. And what of these braziers? I see no evidence that they have ever been alight. Odd indeed.\n\n- X</string>

<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Chapter_05">The Fall</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_05_01">Up to No Good</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_05_01">A loose letter from an unknown author.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_05_01">Jonas was with those hooligans again. I saw them on the bridge and the following morning his face was a mess. I don't like how this place is changing him. He is not the boy I once knew.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_05_02">Violent Storm</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_05_02">A loose letter from an unknown author.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_05_02">There was a great commotion several nights ago. Several fevered shouts could be heard from the crest of the waterfall. The precise words were lost to the tumult of the falls themselves. But there were several figures silhouetted against the storm tossed sky in what appeared to be a violent struggle. A thunderbolt forced me to avert my gaze for but an instant and they were gone. I've heard nothing since.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_05_03">On the Banks of the River</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_05_03">A loose letter from an unknown author.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_05_03">More flotsam has washed upon the riverbank this morning and amongst it was a great clump of human hair, matted and bloodied. I fear it belongs to Jonas.</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_11">Douglas' Watch</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_11_01">Change of Tune</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_11_01">Found in Monarch's Bluffs Watchtower</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_11_01">As I rest here, watching the waves crash upon the beach, I reminisce about my old life. I was a budding antiquarian: the stories of the past, and the people that made those stories so real to me, drove me to this Island. Though at first the hardships of this island made my outlook on surviving here bleak, my tune has changed.\n \nTo be honest, when Bixford recommended to me to be a Watcher, I didn't understand why anyone would do this job. But, over time, investigating the ships, talking to new folks, and aiding them after crashing onto the island... Hearing their stories, piecing together their past, and helping them figure out their future on the island. It scratches an itch! I'll thank Bixford next time I'm in the settlement...\n \nFighting the Drowned? No one loves every part of their job, I suppose.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_11_02">Poseidon's Curse</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_11_02">Found in The Rise of Poseidon</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_11_02">I met a man who was hiding inside of the Poseidon after he had crashed onto Aeternum. I spoke with him and tried to help him, but for the first few moments of our meeting he was unintelligibly muttering about "Poseidon's Curse."\n \nAs I continued talked to him, he regained his wits. I quickly pieced together that he was on a ship that was struck by spires of Corruption, which seems quite common among survivors that wash ashore. He attributed this to a curse from Poseidon. I should report this to the Greyjacks, this is too common to be a coincidence.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_11_03">Notes from a Professional</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_11_03">Found in the Boar Infestation</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_11_03">Douglas,\n \nSometimes shipments from the settlement can be a little lean on meat, but these infestations of Boar here can be controlled and maintained like livestock. If you're ever hungry between shipments, this infestation should make a great source of food in between. I'll see what I can do about getting some meatier shipments.\n \n-Saville</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_12">Warwick's Fishing War</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_12_01">The One That Got Away</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_12_01">Fish Escapee</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_12_01">Out by the coast she still lurks, evading me at every turn. I know I had her on my hook once or twice, for her favorite bait is glowworms and I have them in great supply.\n\nI know it's the same Ray-Finned Barb. I've taken to calling her 'Nibbler' for the way she toys with my bobber before I can properly hook her. This one is too smart for her own good. Nibbler must be a lady, for you see it is the female Barb who hulks over the male in size, and her wit is mighty quick.\n\nBut I shall not let her outswim or outsmart me. I'll get her one day, and mount her on my home wall. One day, Nibbler, you shall be mine...</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_12_02">Food Rations</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_12_02">Feeding an Army</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_12_02">If you give a man a fish you feed him for a day, but if you teach a man to fish you feed him for a lifetime. Or at least that's what Papa said.\n\nThat is why I taught all my subordinates in the army the essential skill of fishing. It's why I continue to teach fishing even in my retired living. It is not only a pleasurable hobby but a means of survival here in Aeternum. Fish are food, and food is life.</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_13">The Huntsman's Stench</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_13_01">Note for Stinky</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_13_01">Tucked in the outhouse door of the Devil's Pit</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_13_01">Stinky,\nWe were hoping you'd join our hunt, but your odor is spooking all the game.  So we're heading out on our own.\nDon't know what you've got spoiling in them guts of yours, but you can expel it in solitude. We've had enough of it!\nOnce we've bagged a bear or two, we'll be back to let you out.  Hopefully, your arse will have said its piece by then.</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_14">Monarch's Wreckage</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_14_01">Capili's Coronation: Roster</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_14_01">Found in Capili's Coronation</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_14_01">Captain Capili\nFirst Mate Tupu\nChief Technical Officer Salesa\nSecond Mate Hoapili\nNavigator Eketone\nBoatswain Arona\nRigger Hamakua\nSurgeon Kekai\nEngineer Lavea\nGunner Fiso\nQuartermaster Sapani\nCook Rata\nMessman Pihopa</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_14_02">Manifest of the Coronation</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_14_02">Found in Capili's Coronation</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_14_02">- Three crates of bullion\n- Hardtack rations\n- Two reels of parchment\n- Thirteen hatchets\n- Fifteen bows\n- Five crates of arrows</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_14_03">Capili's Coronation Log Day 13</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_14_03">Found in Capili's Coronation</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_14_03">Day 13:\nMutiny is upon us. Boatswain Arona has gotten it into everyone's heads that the ship would be better run by him and the whispers of dissent have grown to a dull roar belowdecks. I will have to reinstate my authority by any means necessary if we are to reach our destination in time.</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_15">The Cannonomicon</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_15_01">THE CANNONOMICON</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_15_01">BOOK OF DAWN</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_15_01">In th' beginning, there was naught but formless energy. \n\nA material energy, though sublime. \n\nAn ethereal fire. \n\nWithin the fire was contained all life, every thought, every impulse. \n\nWhen bullet or lead ball be fired, therein do an infinite power of impulse reside. A single second, betwixt thy click of a hammer and thy mighty spark's ignition be where secrets of the universe hide. \n\nThe Island has given me sight. Every death and every return, I see our purpose yet clearer. \n\nListen to me true story, and believe! \n\n-          &lt;i&gt;Master Cannoneer Jennings&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_15_02">THE CANNONOMICON</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_15_02">BOOK OF DAY</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_15_02">In the Before, was I a humble pirate warlord. \n\nMy ships numbered hundreds and every nation was afeared. How little did I know, me true path had yet been revealed. \n\nMe First Mate, family on th' high seas, had raised mutiny. I had no choice. So sadly, had I no choice but to execute the poor soul on sight. Without a sea breeze of a second, I barely thought and fired. \n\nA click. \n\nAn explosion. \n\nThe cool sizzle of th' exhausted barrel. Saw the universe explode before my very eyes! That was the day, I always say, that I became a Master Cannoneer.\n\n -          &lt;i&gt;Master Cannoneer Jennings&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_15_03">THE CANNONOMICON</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_15_03">BOOK OF DUSK</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_15_03">I once felt the life in my veins. Was electric. But to be truly Lost... is electricity and a strange numbness at the same time. With every death, me spark mixes with something alien and divine. \n\nAnd when the dream ends, ye wake up on th' shores of yer long-lost passing. Again and again and again. Every journey be breathless and infinite! Every moment awake is a gift! And a poisoned fruit. \n\nI've seen the end though! \n\nI've seen when the spark gives up! There be nothing left but formless energy! \n\nEthereal fire! \n\nIt only takes time! And time, I think, is all we have.\n\n-          &lt;i&gt;Master Cannoneer Jennings&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_15_04">THE CANNONOMICON</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_15_04">BOOK OF NIGHT</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_15_04">Loyal comrades! Faithful friends!\n\nJoin! Submit to the Cannon. Submit to th' bullet, gunpowder, and musket. \n\nJoin and be shown yer truest path. Path to enlightenment, and th' only way we ever escape this godforsaken Island. \n\nJoin and I shalt carry ye beyond thy veil. Through dusk and moonlight's peak, where we may all rest… Join me and find eternal freedom!\n\n-          &lt;i&gt;Master Cannoneer Jennings&lt;/i&gt;</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_16">Monarch's Bluffs Legacies</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_16_01">I Know What She's Hiding</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_16_01">Found on the Road out of Monarch's Bluffs</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_16_01">Laikina,\n\nI left town at twilight, to avoid a scene with Constable Saville. But she was there, waiting at the gate, like she knew my thoughts. “Such a shame to see you go,” she said. “Monarch's Bluffs will surely miss you.”\n\nA perfectly normal thing to say. For the hundredth time, I wonder if the things I saw Saville do that night were just a nightmare. I can hear your voice, telling me that I'm being too paranoid.\n\nI find myself watching her. She seems so normal, wrapped up in the petty concerns of the settlement. But sometimes…I catch a flash of it in her eyes, when she looks at me. Maybe it's always been there. Or maybe she sees me as a threat, now.\n\nI'm coming to Windsward. If I head straight east all night, I should be able to get there by daybreak. The terrors of the nighttime wilds are nothing, compared to what I'm leaving behind.\n\nI'm looking forward to a fresh start.\n\n-Christopher\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_16_02">Missing Persons Report: Christopher Ward</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_16_02">Found at the Constable's Desk in Monarch's Bluffs</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_16_02">From the desk of Constable Saville:\n\nChristopher Ward has vanished from Monarch's Bluffs. His house was found emptied of all belongings. His soul has not returned home. None of the other settlements, nor any of the Watchers, have seen hide nor hair of him. \n\nI must note Christopher had been acting strangely in the days leading up to his disappearance. He seems to have fallen victim to some kind of paranoid delusion. I even caught him peering into my window late at night.\n\nDisappearances are, of course, nothing new in Aeternum. There are many dangers that await the underprepared and the overly-curious. Still, as the Constable of this settlement, I feel somewhat responsible. In the end, Christopher simply wouldn't heed my warnings.\n\nUnless further evidence turns up, Mr. Ward is presumed Lost or Corrupted. I'll ask Adjudicator Owgan add his name to the Covenant prayer list of wayward souls.\n</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_17">King Arthur’s Arrival</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_17_01">The High King</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_17_01">Letter to Lord Darius</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_17_01">--gave me news of this “High King’s” arrival. I am told it was nothing short of miraculous. His vessel seemed undamaged and of a strange design. It was said to shine with a blinding light. I doubt this to be true but these stories are spreading.\n\nWhoever he fancies himself to be, he will no doubt prove a threat to your lordship’s dominion over these lands. I counsel you to gather your warriors and go to meet this potential usurper. I shall send word to the other lords. Perhaps united we can prevent calamity-- \n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_17_02">The King’s Magician</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_17_02">A Master of Azoth</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_17_02">The High King’s magician has knowledge of an incantation that gives him mastery over the strange power of this land. I have never witnessed such a thing. Could he have discovered the secrets of the Ancients? How did he accomplish this so quickly?\n\nOnly a few words are known to me. It’s ancient Celtic. It speaks of a “serpent’s breath” and a “twilight realm” and of “folk of light and shadow.” \n\nI must learn the secrets of this charm. With its power I could change our fortunes.\n\nAmaranth the Raven-Haired\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_17_03">A Legendary Weapon</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_17_03">The Eternal Blade</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_17_03">I held the Eternal Blade in my hands. I could not identify the metal. It was lighter than steel and glittered like polished silver. I would swear it hummed. \n\nThe High King bid me strike an old anvil with the edge. I dared not until he commanded it. Gripping it firmly, I smote the anvil and sheared away its heel in one stroke.\n\nThe Eternal Blade bore no mark. Its edge remained keen as a razor. By God, I will never see its equal. \n\nMaster Auric</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_17_04">Uniting the Land</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_17_04">The High King’s Call</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_17_04">Dearest Maeve, \n\nIt is my hope that this finds you in good health.\n\nThe High King’s call has gone out. He summons all to his banner, to build a great kingdom where all may prosper.\n\nEven though I possess no great strength of arms or cunning with magic, even the mightiest warriors and wisest wizards will have need of tables, chairs, and beds when they are weary from their toil.\n\nIf the High King can keep us safe from the horrors that roam this land, I will gladly pledge myself to him.\n\nIt is my fervent desire, my beloved sister, that you will choose to join me in this worthy cause.\n\nCullum</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_18">The Reign of the High King</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_18_01">Defending the Realm</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_18_01">Fortifying the Wall</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_18_01">Our work on the Great Wall continues. I have met master masons from every known land. The collection of knowledge and skill assembled here astonishes me.\n\nThe High King’s wizard uses his craft to help us rebuild and fortify these ancient stones. He speaks of an evil that gathers in the north. We have seen more of those crimson demons. We must be ready for what is coming.\n\nConnor Hewer, Master Mason\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_18_02">The Art of Magic</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_18_02">Staves of Power</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_18_02">The High King’s wizard fancies himself Taliesin of the old legends. He is cunning to be sure, and possesses knowledge of the Ancients unknown to us. He wields a staff of intricate design that allows him to manipulate the magic of this land. He claims he will pass on this knowledge to others. He has already taken on many apprentices.\n\nI believe he harbors a secret desire in his heart. The people give him their trust but I feel this wizard will bring doom to us all. The evil of this land will taint him. I must learn his secrets before it is too late.\n\nAmaranth the Raven-Haired\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_18_03">Searching the Stars</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_18_03">An Astronomer’s Observation</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_18_03">The High King has commanded that the stars be carefully measured and charted. I will do my part in this endeavor for I believe the answers to this world’s mysteries can be found in the heavens. The Sumerians, Greeks, and Persians knew this to be true. The Ancients knew this as well as evidenced by their study of the stars.\n\nBut Myrddin advises caution. He claims that just as we gaze out into the vast darkness, so too does it gaze back at us. He warns us to be forever vigilant for evil does not sleep.\n\nEstere\n</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_19">The Fall of the High King</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_19_01">The Fall to Darkness</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_19_01">A Wizard Corrupted</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_19_01">Myrddin cast me out of the Order. He accused me of deceit and of sowing the seeds of discord. But I have spoken the truth. I know the evil that has taken root in his mind. I see what he is becoming.\n\nThe others will not heed my warnings. Fools! The fall of the High King will be on their heads! I do not possess the strength to challenge Myrddin directly, but I must try to foil his purpose for the sake of us all.\n\nI will plead my case directly to the High King. I have found the “Folk of Light and Shadow.” They may prove to be allies. It is my fervent hope the High King is as wise as they say.\n\nAmaranth the Raven-Haired</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_19_02">The Corruption Surge</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_19_02">The Final Stand</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_19_02">God’s blood! Waves of demons crash upon us with the fury of a storm. They strike where we are weakest. We cannot hold them! Our fortifications crumble!\n\nWe’ve been betrayed! The Crimson Sorcerer has revealed himself. It is said he commands the infernal hordes. God in heaven, we are lost!\n\nThe High King has retreated to the shore. They say the Raven-Haired fights by his side. May God see him safely away from this accursed island! And may He have mercy on our souls…\n\nCaptain Ulfric</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_19_03">Darkness Falls</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_19_03">A Desperate Prayer</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_19_03">The demons have overrun the land, slaughtering every living soul. A lucky few may have found the peace of eternal death. The rest have joined the ranks of the Withered or been twisted into fell shapes.\n  \nWe have taken refuge here but it’s only a matter of time before we are discovered. Even if we are not, our stores of food and water dwindle. A few of us shall have to venture out in a few days.\n\nHow could we have come to this? The High King’s promise of a fair world has been shattered. This land exists under a curse which cannot be lifted. I dared to hope and dream. Now, I pray I can forget…\n\nCullum\n</string>

<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_21_03">A Reassurance of Love</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_21_03">A Final Request for Forgiveness</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_21_03">I’ve not been a good father, Olive. I never should have raised my hand to you. I’d cut off that hand if it meant you’d forgive me, come back to me.\n\nLife hasn’t been easy without your mother. She was always the smart one. Every decision I make without her scares me.\n\nBut I don’t love crafting glass more than I love you. Crafting glass was just easier. And I am a lazy fool. I took the easier path. Maybe you were right to leave. But would you come back and forgive your ailing father?</string>