<string key="Topic_02_Brightwood">Tales of Brightwood</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_02_Brightwood">A mystical forest home to the Azoth Tree and countless abandoned homesteads</string>

<string key="Topic_Alchemist">Havelock's Diary</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_Alchemist">Personal Musings of M. Havelock of Queensport, Alchemist</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Chapter_01">Havelock's Diary</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_01">Aeternum's Fate</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_01">01 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_01">Every day, there is more news from the north, none of it hopeful, none of it promising victory. The Corrupted are massing in greater numbers, and where once a few groups might be seen once a year, now they swarm from the Cleave almost every season. Two days ago, there were rumors that the Great Bridge has fallen.\n\nWe cannot fight these beasts if we do not understand them – and I believe the secret to stopping this foul tide is in curing the red sickness that afflicts them.\n\n-M. Havelock, Archminister</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_02">For Family and Aeternum</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_02">02 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_02">Genevieve, and even little Simon, have both been supportive of my efforts - perhaps more so when I suggested we move from the developing settlement and pursue our lives where we were less likely to be caught in the middle of a company's feud.\n\nI made mention of an isle in the midst of Brightwood Lake, where we might find some manner of peace from the growing unrest on the rest of the isle… and at this, both of them seemed relieved. They have not been deaf to the rumors in the North, and I think they share the same fears as I do and wish to be far from any troubles that come.\n\nI did not tell them of the letter sent and my request – if it is not honored, I shall find another way. I only seek the safety of family – and a cure for this affliction that besets those that come to Aeternum!\n\n-M. Havelock, Archminister</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_03">Brightwood Lake</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_03">03 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_03">The isle is beautiful – the sight of the destination did much to quell my family's doubts on the wisdom of our relocation. I did not mention the cages that would soon be shipped to the isle, nor my equipment. I imagine the cages were doing the settlement little good – even criminals are being enlisted for the conflict in the North, if rumors are to be believed.\n\nI did not mention to Genevieve my thoughts on the Corrupted, nor on who I believe to be their cousins: The Withered. We shall see if there is a link, and if so, test it!\n\n-M. Havelock, Archminister</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_04">An Answer</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_04">04 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_04">Genevieve was surprised as I to find a woman at the door – a Captain (a former Captain), no less, carrying a letter and saying that she was here at the Magistrate's request and that she was to assist in my efforts. Her name was Madelaine (Maddy), and insisted I not use the title of Captain when speaking to her, as her arrival on the shore of Aeternum did not deserve the title – nor did the crew she had lost.\n\nGenevieve was suspicious, then upset, and she asked me many questions – about Maddie's presence, to the alchemical equipment, and most of all, the cages, which alarmed her greatly. What manner of beasts were they to hold, she asked?\n\nNot “hold” but what manner of beasts we may SAVE, I replied. As I attempted to explain, she suddenly stood and left, and I knew the conversation to be over.\n\nIt seems I shall sleep in the workshop this night – and not by choice.\n\n-M. Havelock, Archminister</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_05">Our Research Begins</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_05">05 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_05">Maddie begins hunting today – as I suspected, the lake is surrounded by clusters of Withered from the settlements that used to border it.\n\nI have not shared this knowledge with my family – there is no need for them to know what happened to the settlers. It is enough that they know to keep to the island and do not wander far from the house.\n\n-M. Havelock, Archminister</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_06">A Modest Success</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_06">06 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_06">I have had a breakthrough, however slight, in no small part to Captain Madelaine – Maddie. She has taken to capturing the Withered with a focus I have rarely seen – I suspect it may have to do with someone that she has lost, for she will only take enough coin to sustain her, little else. She does not tire, and my cages remain full for my experiments.\n\nMy family does not call me to join them for meals, nor for sleep – I sleep in the workshop now. But the alchemy, it works – the Watchers (the ones willing to still serve as test subjects) report that upon consuming my latest mixture, that the Corruption does not eat at them as it used to, and they retain their strength as they venture north! I have passed along the recipe to the Magistrate, and keep records here as well.\n\nI cannot rest on this success, however – I must continue my research. A half-victory is not enough – the formula only slows the affliction, it doesn't cure it. We must drive it out completely! And I will be the one to make it happen.\n\n-M. Havelock, Archminister</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_07">Captain Madelaine's Dismissal</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_07">07 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_07">The “Captain” – Maddie returned empty-handed today. She interrupted me in the workshop and when I saw no new Withered in the pen, I inquired – rather sharply – as to why she was disturbing me.\n\nShe told me she had spoken to my wife, seen the eyes of Simon, and she has taken their side. She tells me she refuses to capture more Withered for my “experiments” – and then the woman had the NERVE to lecture me, ME, that I have become too narrow of purpose on the Corrupted, that (and I got quite angry at this) my attempts have begun to erode my common sense and are causing both me and my family suffering.\n\nI told her I have no need of her services any longer. If she feels my work is done, then her work is done as well, and there is no reason for us to speak again. She left without a word – good riddance, I say.\n\n-M.H.</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_08">Empty Cages</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_08">08 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_08">In my haste to dismiss Maddie, I remember my cages now lie empty.\n\nI need one - or two - more specimens. It is no trouble, I have observed Maddie's techniques enough that I may capture my own. The Withered are little more than animals – sick animals, but animals to be sure.\n\nI know where some can be found. Though dusk is close, I shall set out at once.\n\n-M.H.</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_09">Success!</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_09">09 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_09">It is a near thing, but the cages have two more captives – though it is strange – for these Withered bear the markings of the settlement to the south – can these have been the settlers there? They smell of a strange sort of rot… sickly sweet, much like if the scents of a corpse and a flower were mixed.\n\nI wonder why they wandered so far – my efforts are more important than ever if the Corruption is making its way this far south. I cannot help but now notice they are caged, these Withered are more eager to return to what might have once been their homes, and they claw at the pen with an unusual strength.\n\nWell, I will not allow it – the only thing they shall find is the mercy of my scalpel and the salvation of my curatives. If they should perish like the others, then when they arise, I shall test them again!\n\nTo work!\n\n-M.H.</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_10">I Have Been Tested</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_10">10 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_10">I labored long into the night – and awoke to screams. I made an error in my methods… my family has paid the price.\n\nBoth Withered I had caught died upon the table. Yet… and I see my mistake now… when I had taken the second Withered from the pen, I did not lock the gate – and when they rose again hours later, they found the cage unlocked.\n\nThen, they found Genevieve. They found Simon.\n\nThe first beast was still skulking outside the house – all I could see was red. I planted a hatchet in its skull, and it turned to ash. The second one soon followed… but as their corpses vanished, the corpses of my wife, my son… they remained.</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_11">The Burial</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_11">11 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_11">I finished burying them this morning.\n\nI forgot to say farewell, but I do not think I will – we no longer talked in life, there is no need to do so now they are dead. I think they wanted to leave the isle, leave this place… leave me… so completely, that the isle honored their wishes and let them sleep.\n\nAfterward… I returned here, to the workshop, to put down my thoughts while they were clear in my mind.\n\nI failed them, yes. But they did not die by my hands, and I will not fail others. No other family will be lost to the Corrupted. All we sought on this isle shall not be lost with them.\n\nThis tragedy has only renewed my purpose. I shall bring every Withered beneath the knife, see them exposed to every formula, and I shall see their sickness driven from them. Then, the isle shall know peace. I shall know peace.\n\n-M.H.</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_12">Abandoned</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_12">12 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_12">The last few visitors – they spoke of the trouble in the North. That the Cleave is nearly abandoned now except for some scattered outposts. When I insisted they take my research, they looked at me as if quite mad – and told me the isle is fragmented, they say, the settlers at each other's throats over azoth.\n\nThe days have bled together. The Withered seem to know my approach, but do not run – as if it is simply the cycle of the day. At times, it seems like they are welcoming me – as if someone familiar, as if family.\n\n-M.H.</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Title_01_13">At Last</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Subtitle_01_13">13 Subtitle</string>
<string key="Alchemist_Body_01_13">A breakthrough – and only I know of it.\n\nThis latest formula works, I am certain of it. But without a subject, the only one who may test its properties - is myself.\n\nBut if that is what is required, then so be it.\n\nI write now of my symptoms, yet I feel it may prove useless. I will not suffer the Corruption, but in so doing, I have ended my own life, I feel it. My blood seems to flow to unfelt corners of my body, and I can feel the rupturing of every blood vessel – and I can see my eyes bleeding red in my reflection in the Lake's waters, and I have no idea how I crawled to the lakeshore… or if I am imagining it.\n\nI will not surrender. This is my home. This is where my family died. I shall NOT die here with them.\n\nMy work will live on. I will live on.</string>

<string key="Topic_AzothTree">Merchand's Chronicle</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_AzothTree">By and about the Merchand Company</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Chapter_01">Merchand's Chronicle</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Title_01_01">A Tree, What of It?</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Subtitle_01_01">A Letter from Bertand</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Body_01_01">So Merchand and his band of drunken loons were at it in the inn again, enjoying the adoration of the crowd, telling their usual round of wild tales. I thought they'd draw every beast a mile round to our walls – or perhaps drive them away, which would be the best to be had this night. “The First and Finest Company of Aeternum's Shores,” they've taken to calling themselves, when I think “Fermented” would be best tossed in there as well.\n\nIt was the usual tales of the azoth they've uncovered, the horde of Withered they've butchered from the Cleave and back (which might number three in all, if the claimed bounties are to be believed). Then the drunken shouts and boasts of the rabble turned to how quick one would fell a tree, of all things.\n\nYet one in the crowd spoke up, most carelessly, and said he knew of a tree that none could fell.\n\nThey inn got quiet at this, and Merchand demanded where this tree was. The man – no doubt regretting his unintended challenge – said he had seen it on the Eastern edge of Brightwood, but curiously, it had not always been there – it had risen from the earth not long after the Night of Blue Lanterns. Many in the inn to make the sign to ward off evil.\n\nMerchand, on the contrary, seemed invigorated by this (perhaps seeing a tree as easy prey), and said he would go at once to this tree and “true to his word” (true to his boast more like, and with none but the First and Finest to bear witness) chop it down and bring back its lumber to shore up the walls.\n\nIt has been a week since their departure – and while there's been scattered talk of going to find them, none has volunteered for the task.\n\n- Bertand</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Title_01_02">First, Finest... No More</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Subtitle_01_02">A Letter from Bertand</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Body_01_02">I inquired of the tradesmen in the outpost, and of the “First and Finest” I caught not a word. If they had gone to the great azoth tree in eastern Brightwood, they had not made it this far, even to resupply. More telling of the truth of this was the untapped kegs in the outpost – had they lain empty or shattered, I would have known that Merchand and his band had surely come this way.\n\nI think upon the Night of Blue Lanterns and the rumors of the tree's sudden appearance, and I am uneasy. Perhaps Merchand came upon… not a tree to cut down for its azoth-soaked wood, as he'd hoped, but something that cut him down instead.\n\nThe fact he and his band have not been seen since… perhaps he was not one of the blessed of the isle after all, reborn to try to fell the tree again. Whatever his company's end, this much is clear – none are eager to travel to this so-called azoth tree. For if it had the strength to end Merchand's boasts and make him swallow his pride when he could not, it could certainly silence other bold travelers seeking to follow his footsteps, and quickly, too.\n\n- Bertand</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Title_01_03">Day One</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Subtitle_01_03">Chronicle of the Merchand Company</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Body_01_03">It is I, Yorke, that writes this chronicle, feigning to record Merchand's nightful boasts for “posterity,” and I have not the ink, the parchment, nor patience for all of Merchand's rambling. It is fortunate he cannot read this chronicle, for writing the truth of his adventures is one of the sole joys of his company.\n\nIt is plain to see he and the fellows have some regret for striking out for the “azoth tree” (a fool's errand – what manner of tree suddenly sprouts from the earth, and why would one risk crossing deity or devil for it, esp. seeing what azoth has done elsewhere!). Laying sight upon it, they seemed not driven for fame at cutting down the tree, but confusion as to how they might set about dismantling and hauling it away. None had thought to bring a wagon big enough for the task.\n\nI, for one, do not like camping here. I find the coincidence of the Night of Blue Lanterns and the sudden appearance of this tree to be a warning most clear, not another feat fit for a rabble who playact at a “task worthy of Hercules.”\n\nAs night fell, the Blue Lanterns of the highway seemed to glow brighter, and even the ones in the distance seemed most sharp to my eyes. I write these final lines as Merchand has gone off to slumber, and I'll make up words “worthy of the myth” tomorrow… unless he decided to tear up the parchment in anger, like he has for half of our expeditions that fortune did not favor.\n\n- “The Great Merchand” (i.e., Chronicler Yorke)</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Title_01_04">Day Two</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Subtitle_01_04">Chronicle of the Merchand Company</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Body_01_04">I did not sleep. I felt as if something was watching us as we camped beneath the tree. Yet when the light of dawn touched the camp, I felt relief, and my fears were dispelled – and the day brought a new joy: Merchand's humiliation!\n\nIt is with no small amusement that I chronicle this – I watched Merchand, then his men, one by one – then in tandem, and finally a half-dozen, all take their hatchets to the tree, and the wood remained untouched! Merchand, finally, his face red, sought about seeking to chop the tree down with curses, to pry at the branches with hatchet and chop at it with sword – but to no avail.\n\nHad he not been so angry, I would have laughed, but the unease I had felt earlier in the day became stronger as night drew on and bid me to keep my tongue. More to my unease, I noticed that Merchand had made no signs of packing up camp – it seemed as if he would work in the light of the moon and the glow of the tree.\n\nYet… the blue light within the tree's wood seemed sharper to my senses as he hacked at it, as if what was within was resisting his efforts. It may have been the trick of the light… but it seemed to grow stronger, pulsing like a heart after every stroke. Turning from the tree, I scanned the growing darkness, but saw naught but the blue lamps burning… except some… seemed moving, as if carried by men.\n\nWhat manner of men carry a flame of azoth to their chest?\n\n- “The Great Merchand” (i.e., Chronicler Yorke)</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Title_01_05">The Tree Untouched</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Subtitle_01_05">Chronicle of the Merchand Company</string>
<string key="AzothTree_Body_01_05">Be warned, traveler – there is a great tree, but do not seek shelter beneath it – others who came before sought to do so, and their bodies lie spread across its roots. I did not bury the ones I saw, for a corpse in Aeternum is an unusual thing if it does not rise, and there was still hope the corpses would vanish in the light of the sun – but it seemed as if they had been there for some time, which was as unsettling as the tree itself.\n\nThe tree seems a lesson in that Aeternum takes its own, and leaves others to rot in the sun. On the crest of one's shield, I recognized the mark of the “First and Finest Company” – Merchand's band of opportunists – yet the shield had been cleaved in two with a sword sharper than the crest that defended its owner.\n\nAround the Company, I saw tracks, not unlike those I'd seen at the ruins where Grenville's curiosity had led him (how many fools does this land inspire?). The Ancient Keepers had come for Merchand's band, one and all.\n\nThe tree is a thing born of azoth, born of the blue light in the lanterns. And where the dead walk with azoth burning in the orbs in their chest, I fear these men now walk with them.\n\n- Maddie</string>

<string key="02_Brightwood_Chapter_04">Park's Research Notes</string>
<string key="02_Brightwood_Title_04_01">Egede Serpe and Azoth</string>
<string key="02_Brightwood_Subtitle_04_01">The Legendary Catch</string>
<string key="02_Brightwood_Body_04_01">It is said that there is a catfish whose skin is lined with azoth.\n\nDubbed 'Egede Serpe' after a traveler saw it, to catch a Serpe is to peak as a fisher here in Brightwood. If only I could reel in this mysterious creature and perform experiments...\n\n-Park</string>
<string key="02_Brightwood_Title_04_02">Swordfish</string>
<string key="02_Brightwood_Subtitle_04_02">Mercurial Findings</string>
<string key="02_Brightwood_Body_04_02">Mercury, what can't it do? Used in skin treatments and mood tinctures in the Old World, it can also most readily be extracted from the Swordfish that circle Aeternum. Used ubiquitously by healers across the globe Mercury can be administered in its liquid or solid salt form. The mercury content of the Aeternum swordfish seems irregularly high, but I cannot compare it to an Old World fish without returning home, which is impossible with the storms that haunt the coast.\n\nFor now I must rely on anecdotal evidence from the other alchemists who have seen Old World swordfish, as unreliable as those observations can be.\n\n-Park</string>