<string key="Topic_99_MSQ">Tales of the Soulwardens</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_99_MSQ">Notes, journals, and records related to the mysterious Soulwardens</string>

<string key="99_MSQ_Chapter_01">Go On Without Me</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Title_01_01">Soulwardens' Flight</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Subtitle_01_01">A crumbling journal page flecked with rust-colored stains</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Body_01_01">Journal of Warden Alazar\n\nVII.XXVII.MLX\n\nIt's as I feared. My leg is useless, broken in the battle. Pravin and Michael carried me to Arcturus Tower, but I can see that my weight is a burden. They're already exhausted…there's still so much further to run. \n\nI told them to leave me behind. I knew they'd get farther without me. They refused, like I knew they would. Michael swore the loudest. But in the end, even he couldn't disobey my orders. \n\nI've barricaded the doors and lit a bonfire on the roof. The enemy can't fail to see it. Hopefully, they'll take the bait. If I can buy enough time for the others to escape, I don't care what happens to me.</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Title_01_02">Final Entry</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Subtitle_01_02">A crumbling journal page that ends in a sudden smear of ink</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Body_01_02">Journal of Warden Alazar\n\nVII.XXVIII.MLX\n\nThis will be my last entry. It's just me and the stars now. To the south, my Soulwardens are running. From the north, Corruption's army comes. Only I can see them both, from up here. \n\nSome people live their last moments in a dungeon. I'm lucky to have the stars for company. \n\nThey've reached the foot of the tower. I, Yonas Alazar, am honored to have served as the Soulwarden Commander for all these \n\nWait. One of my Soulwardens is coming back. What is Michael doing? I ordered them all to run! \n\nThat stubborn LUNATIC is going to get himself Corrupted!</string>

<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Chapter_2">The Soulwarden's Oath</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Title_2_01">Soulwarden's Burden</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Subtitle_2_01">An inscription on a weathered plaque. Only the first third is still legible.</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Body_2_01">When Corruption comes to smolder \n\nIn the furnace of men's souls \n\nWe, the deathless shields, will shoulder \n\nAll the fires the future holds</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Title_2_02">Soulwarden's Call</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Subtitle_2_02">An inscription on a weathered plaque. Partly buried by sediment.</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Body_2_02">Join our battle, share our fire \n\nMeet us on the barricade \n\nWhen dark rises, we rise higher \n\nIronclad and unafraid</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Title_2_03">Soulwarden's Duty</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Subtitle_2_03">An inscription on a weathered plaque. The first two thirds are covered with vines.</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Body_2_03">Chains of duty, chosen freely, \n\nNever rust and will not break \n\nAll Aeternum can sleep deeply \n\nThe Soulwardens are awake</string>

<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Chapter_03">Soulwardens' Epitaph</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Title_3_01">Soulwarden Epitaph</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Subtitle_3_01">A rough epitaph on a stone tomb, carved in a hurry</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Body_3_01">VIII.II.MLX \n\n\nHere, the last of the Wardens are laid to rest \n\nNo corpses to bury, hearts and souls sacrificed long ago \n\nMemories may fade, but this testament to courage shall remain.</string>

<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Chapter_04">Isabella's Fall</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Aeternum_Title_4_01">Isabella's Fall</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Chapter_04">Isabella's Fall</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Title_01_03">She Must Be Stopped</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Subtitle_01_03">A faded letter, stained with salt</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Body_01_03">LaCuran, \n\nI've gone on the run. I am so sorry to leave you to face Captain Isabella's wrath alone. Whatever she does to you will be less horrible than what she had planned. Perhaps that's some small comfort? I hope so. \n\nI couldn't let her go through with it. I couldn't let her become the monster she wanted to be. \n\nMy final request of you is to distract her until I can escape the island with the box. She will certainly kill you for it, and maybe worse; still, I must ask, for the sake of our long friendship. If that's not enough, for the sake of every living thing in this world. Even now, I fear it is too late for I hear the Heretic's laughter. Hellish echoes that plague my waking thoughts and haunt my nightmares. \n\nI must flee. Go with God, friend, if you can still find him. \n\n- &lt;b&gt;Father Dante&lt;/b&gt;</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Title_01_04">The Love of a Madman</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Subtitle_01_04">A scrap of a letter, stained with salt</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Body_01_04">I heard the Heretic's voice again last night, in Isabella's quarters. They were discussing something. I ran in, crucifix in hand, but Isabella was alone. She watched as I searched the room, smiled as the crucifix fell from my fingers. I let her embrace me, and felt her body shake with silent laughter.\n\nDid I imagine it? Was I finally going mad? The Devil is certainly within his right to play tricks on me. Only a madman could think a wooden crucifix capable of saving Isabella's soul. Only a hypocrite could love her.\n\nI had to leave her. I couldn't leave her. Not until what I discovered tonight. \n\n- Dante</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Title_01_05">Soul Thief</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Subtitle_01_05">A faded letter, partially burned</string>
<string key="99_MSQ_Body_01_05">My Isabella, \n\nAs you struggled in the fever's grip, I invoked the ancient rite. I would not see your soul damned to the Pit even if it meant condemning my own. When your fever finally broke, I hoped for an instant that God had returned you to me. \n\nBut it's the Devil that delights in the hopes of weak men. I finally see that the creature that came back is not the woman I loved. \n\nThe truth is, until tonight, I've never done a single thing worthy of reward. Saving your soul was never within my power. The only thing left for me to do was steal it, and save the world from what you've become. \n\nWe will not meet in Heaven. I hope that we never meet again. To spend my life guarding this box…to grow old, to die alone, imagining the hate you feel for me…that will be my reward. \n\n\nGoodbye, my love. \n\n- Dante</string>