<string key="Topic_10_CutlassKeys">Tales of Cutlass Keys</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_10_CutlassKeys">A sandy shoreline harassed by the undead pirate menace of Aeternum</string>

<string key="Topic_DrownedPages">The Drowned Pages</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_DrownedPages">Loose letters and journal entries pertaining to The Drowned</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Chapter_01">Wynn's Diary</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_01">Backstabbers</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_01">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_01">Ol' Irontoe has really gotten us into something this time! Why did he think this was going to be such a good idea?! We knew not to trust those backstabbers. How many times are we going to let them play us for fools?\n\n-Wynn</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_02">Stranded</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_02">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_02">They struck as soon as the parley had finished. The lying cowards! And now this god-forsaken storm has doomed us all. We have salvaged as much as we could from the wreckage… but there is no sign of the others. Hopefully the seas have claimed them for good.\n\n-Wynn</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_03">Routines of Life</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_03">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_03">It's bizarre how life, even in this place, can become so routine. Now that the bulk of construction is complete, the captain has lost a bit of his edge. It turns out this place may end up being what was promised after all, despite the struggle of the last few years.\n\n-Wynn</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_04">The Stranger</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_04">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_04">I don't trust that stranger, no matter what Irontoe says. Where did he come from? How long has he been watching us? Why is it he only shows up after we have completed all of the difficult work of building this place? \n\nSomething is not right. He stinks of death.\n\n-Wynn</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_05">A Familiar Face</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_05">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_05">I may have been wrong. Edward is not what I feared. His knowledge of this place has helped us avoid many potential catastrophes. But I still can't shake the feeling that I have met him somewhere before… and I was not wrong about his stench.\n\n-Wynn</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_06">Hope Lives</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_06">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_06">Ol' Irontoe has fallen gravely ill. Edward is tending to his needs, but I don't hold out hope that he will last the week. I've seen this before with my own father. But the way Edward speaks, he instills hope, even in the dying.\n\n-Wynn</string>

<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Chapter_02">Perchal's Fishing Follies</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_02_01">Maintenance Update</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_02_01">Tangled Lines</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_02_01">Perhaps Warwick may have had a point about rigorous storage cleanliness.\n\nToday I went to the settlement to get another pole from storage, only to find it had tangled itself up with a spear! It took hours to untie, being that fishing line is precious and I did not want to cut it free. Missed the perfect golden hour for fishing, so the day's wasted now. What a mess.\n\n-Perchal</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_02_02">Competition</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_02_02">Favorite Spot Stolen</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_02_02">I remember my mother had a chair in our old home that no one else was allowed to sit in. She never explicitly told us this, but it was understood that mother's chair was a sacred place.\n\nThat's how I feel about my spot, my secret fishing spot here in Aeternum. None are to disturb me there.\n\nWhen I walked out to the spot with my gear last night, though, I saw a man fishing there I had never seen before. We got into a row about whose spot it was, and thanks to the rapier I have on me I won that one. Saw him again the other day in the settlement grumbling about dying. Serves him right.\n\n-Perchal</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_02_03">Glowing Gnufish</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_02_03">Scales and Scars</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_02_03">I saw something the other day that no one will believe. It has begun to drive me mad.\n\nI thought at first someone was trying to steal my fishing spot again, but upon closer inspection this 'someone' wriggled off into the water with a screech. It was using a tool to get chunks of loose earth from my spot, I know it to be true. I will see you again, Glowing Gnufish, and next time you will be mine.\n\n-Perchal</string>

<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Chapter_03">Touched Coin</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_03_01">Bad Luck</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_03_01">Rumors</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_03_01">Note from Sailing Master Trost\n\nTaking this coin was a terrible idea. \n\nWe've had nothing but bad luck ever since it came aboard our ship.\n\nFirst we had a month with no merchant ships crossing our paths. \n\nThen we lost our captain to a storm that came out of nowhere.\n\nAnd now the Vernal Bounty has crashed into this place.\n\nIf only we'd never seen the Touched Coin.\n</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_03_02">Worse Luck</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_03_02">Rumors</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_03_02">Note from Boatswain Gibbons\n\nTrost keeps muttering on about that stupid coin.\n\nI, for one, don't put much stock in superstitions, but maybe he's on to something.\n\nThere is something wrong with the crew, they are forgetting themselves.\n\nI think it is this place, but Trost is convinced it is the coin.\n\nSaid he was going to do something about it.</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_03_03">Lost and Found</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_03_03">Rumors</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_03_03">Note from Gunner Marlowe\n\nThat blasted coin keeps reappearing. \n\nTrost swears he threw it into the bay, but it's back.\n\nI thought someone is playing a prank on the poor fellow. \n\nFollowing him, retrieving the coin when he isn't looking, that sort o' thing.\n\nExcept, today I was walking along the beach and saw it myself.\n\nThere is something wrong about that shiny piece o' metal, make no mistake.\n</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_03_04">Rising Tempers</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_03_04">Rumors</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_03_04">Note from Boatswain Gibbons\n\nA fight broke out over the coin this morning.\n\nTrost wasn't involved, which surprised me, but then I realized he was gone.\n\nSearched his quarters and found a note, something about leaving this cursed place.\n\nI think he may have the right idea.\n</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_03_05">Unbound At Last</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_03_05">Rumors</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_03_05">Note from Gunner Marlowe\n\nRumors of the coin seem to be spreading.\n\nAnother group o' pirates came to take it from us.\n\nWe didn't stand a chance, they had some big brute of a fellow, that one enjoyed doling out pain.\n\nBenjamin I think his name was. I remember he used to sail on the Fair Weather Friend.\n\nHe took the coin and set out across the water.\n\nGood riddance, I say. Maybe we can finally get some peace.</string>

<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Chapter_04">Swampy's Cookbook</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_04_01">Sea Dog Brew</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_04_01">Beverages and Brews</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_04_01">Recipe for Sea Dog Brew\n\nGood for any time you need to find your sea legs.\n\n Tequila\n Juice of two Limes\n Dash of Clam juice\n Garnish with Salty Marsh Fibers</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_04_02">Bitter Squall</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_04_02">Beverages and Brews</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_04_02">Recipe for Bitter Squall\n\nIt's the dregs that will get you.\n\n Barrel-Aged Gin\n Grapefruit Bitters\n Ground Zedoary Root\n Splash of Salt Water</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_04_03">Stormsurge Surprise</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_04_03">Beverages and Brews</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_04_03">Recipe for Stormsurge Surprise\n\nA pleasant surprise from the first sip.\n\n Spiced Rum\n Juiced Cranberries\n Juice of one Orange\n One pureed Sugar Beet</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_04_04">Cutlass Quiche</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_04_04">Pies and Pastries</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_04_04">Recipe for Cutlass Quiche\n\nSure to start a fight over who cuts the last piece!\n\n Four Turkey Eggs\n Heavy Cream\n Brined Cheese\n Crab Meat\n Leeks\n Fatty Bacon</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_04_05">Disaster Stew</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_04_05">Soups and Stews</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_04_05">Recipe for Disaster Stew\n\nFor when your ingredients are scarce, and company is scarcer.\n\n Salt Water\n Chopped Onion\n Potatoes or Turnips\n Half a head of Cabbage\n Diced Sausages\n A mess of Kidney Beans</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_04_06">Brined Biskets</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_04_06">Bread and Biskets</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_04_06">Recipe for Brined Biskets\n\nThese biskets last years with no sign of mold!\n\n Salt Water\n Wheat Flour\n Anise Seeds</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_04_07">Sailor's Delight</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_04_07">Sauces and Syrups</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_04_07">Recipe for Sailor's Delight\n\nThis red sauce is sure to add flavor to anything!\n\n Fermented Anchovies\n Fermented Oysters\n Peppers\n Mace\n Salt</string>

<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Chapter_05">The Stone Skull Charter</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Title_05_01">Article I</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Subtitle_05_01">HEAR YE! HEAR YE!</string>
<string key="10_CutlassKeys_Body_05_01">By order held of the Skullworm Court\nAbided by the Thalassocratic Captain-in-Command\nEnforced by the Dispenser of Justice\n\nLet it be known\nThe Stone Skull Charter hereby is decreed Code of the Law:\n\n(1)    " Cruel and unjust treatment shall be punished. Crew or Captain, all those against whom worthy Complaint was made shall be executed. Any honest Fellow that never abused any Sailors shall be freed. \n\n(2)    Plunder and loot shall be divided equally amongst those judged Honest and Fair.\n\n(3)    Authority of the Captain-in-Command only be challenged by a Common Cause, delivered and judged by a Court of elected officers.\n\n(4)    All those who seek to join the Crew shall be given the opportunity to do so, at their Peril and the Judgement of the Captain-in-Command.\n\n(5)    The Dispenser of Justice shall be an elected officer appointed by the Captain-in-Command, and whose duties be the Fair and Swift distribution of Justice.\n\n(6)   Any and all those who oppose the Code of the Law are as flotsam on the sand, and their Souls shall be scattered midst the four corners of Aeternum. So be it. "\n\nAs Decreed, and Duly Signed,\nGoldstein the Equalizer, Captain-in-Command!</string>