<string key="Topic_VarangianKnights">The Varangian Knights</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_VarangianKnights">A new threat arrives on the shores of Aeternum</string>

<string key="VarangianKnights_Chapter_01">Tenacious Rose</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_01_01">Orders from Attalus</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_01_01">An official scroll, bound and stamped with an unfamiliar sigil</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_01_01">Sir Ulfar,\n\nI gift you with orders and tidings of glory grim. You are hereby tasked to take Stonereach Keep at all costs. Establish a base to stage further campaigns.\n\nSir Rulav is to remain at the beach camp to coordinate the arrivals of new forces. He is the key to this entire initiative, though only he is entrusted with the finer points of this.\n\nI will arrive shortly. I expect a well-garrisoned keep waiting. Failure is the only sin, and I will be your most devoted confessor on some soon morrow. We are the Varikulaki. We are His fists.\n\nFor the glory of Iznovgorod!\n\nLord Commander Attalus</string>

<string key="VarangianKnights_Chapter_02">Threat From Afar</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_02_01">The Scout's Report</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_02_01">A report from a scout of First Light, spattered in blood</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_02_01">Survivalist Riches,\n\nThey give chase. Barely escaped.\n\nYour visions of ships and dark riders prove wise. Armor-clad warriors infest these lands for some dread purpose at the behest of some Lord Commander.\n\nThese ‘Varangians’ are brutality incarnate. I was captured and tortured. Their methods were... dear God...\n\nThe hulking fiend named Sir Rulav was worst of all. His laughter will haunt me like a wraith.\n\nThe violence to my flesh tore a hole in my soul. I feel all that is me spilling out an ounce at a time. It will not be long before I join the Lost.\n\nI tried to speak familiar names, and all I heard were moans...\n\nIf indeed my fate is to enter the damnation of purgatory, I hope some figment of my life in your service echoes in my cold mind and heart.\n\nSemper Servus,\n\nScout Desdemona</string>

<string key="VarangianKnights_Chapter_03">Sir Rulav the Jovial, Porta Maris War Camp</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_03_01">An Easy Conquest</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_03_01">Letter to Sir Bertram</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_03_01">My Bright One,\n\nThe warriors in these lands have grown soft since last we walked here. These cowards are no true knights. Their weapons are brittle, their armor inferior, and their skill at arms laughable. We will have little trouble claiming these lands from the men who hold them. \n\nThe Crimson Sickness still persists, however, and the restless shades of the dead exist in vast numbers. Myrddin’s secrets must be found and secured if we are to meet these challenges effectively. The Lord Commander assures me we are close to discovering the old sorcerer’s lair. Kari’s wisdom has been most beneficial in this regard.\n\nSoon we shall be reunited, my beloved. I long to hold you in my arms and feel your warm breath on my face. We shall have a new home here. I have my eye on a few keeps. We shall decide which shall be ours together. \n\nUntil then, I shall dream of you and remember the intoxicating taste of your lips.\n\nSir Rulav  \n</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_03_02">Interrogation Orders</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_03_02">Show No Mercy</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_03_02">The Lord Commander has been very clear about the treatment of prisoners. Anyone captured by our troops is to be interrogated using the most extreme methods available. There is to be no regard for the prisoner’s age, sex, or trade. If after interrogation the prisoner has revealed nothing, they are to be immediately executed and their bodies burned.\n\nThese measures may seem cruel but the urgency of our task demands no less. There will be peace once we have fulfilled the wishes of our Great Lord. It is He who dispenses mercy, He who heals and unites. \n\nWe are Varikulaki and we obey His will in all things.\n\nSir Rulav\n</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_03_03">Various Sundries</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_03_03">War Camp Supply List</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_03_03">-barley, 8 sacks\n-flour, 6 sacks\n-pickled pork, 5 barrels\n-ale, 12 barrels\n-water, 8 barrels\n-rope, 400’\n-iron pincers, 4 pairs\n-bellows, 2\n-iron pokers, 6\n-gibbets, 4\n-pears of anguish, 3\n-spiked collars, 6\n-coffins, 8\n</string>

<string key="VarangianKnights_Chapter_04">Sir Ulfar the Wall, Stonereach Keep</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_04_01">A Matter of Honor</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_04_01">A Promising Development</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_04_01">To my right worshipful and well-beloved mother,\n\nI am grateful for your guidance and have taken your wise words to heart. But I fear my current circumstances do no allow me to act upon your counsel. For the moment, our Lord Commander has given his favor to Sir Rulav. A strong bond exists between the two as a result of their parts in securing the rise of Iznovgorod. Such a bond would make my petition for advancement fall on deaf ears.\n\nFortune, however, has smiled upon your son. I have been given command of a fortress vital to establishing our position here. It is my belief that such an appointment shows that my time may come soon. Rulav is a formidable opponent on the field so a direct challenge would be foolhardy. I will instead do as my right noble and valorous father always advised and bide my time. I will know when the iron is hot.\n\nI remain your devoted and loving son.\n\nSir Ulfar\n\n</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_04_02">A Dark Invocation</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_04_02">Protection Against Harm</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_04_02">I beseech you, Mother of Night, to keep me from harm and grant me victory on the field. I ask you to shatter the blades of my foes, split their shields, weaken their limbs, and blind their eyes. \n\nFor the sake of this request, Dark Lady, I offer you the blood of my enemies as your sacred libation. Be benevolent and propitious and shield me in your eternal shadow.</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_04_03">The Troubadour</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_04_03">My Garden</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_04_03">How my talents are wasted on such base, brute butcher work! Mine is the grace of subtle swordsmanship, not heavy-handed cleaving. Mine is the ecstasy of penmanship, not this rote boorish torture. Ah well. All to the greater glory.\n\nI am a warrior, it is true, but I fancy myself part of the ancient tradition of the troubadour knight. I therefore must scriven to keep my mind sharp during these bloody doldrums.\n\nIn a half hour, I must rend a knave’s flesh until he offers up the truth. But for now, I will try my hand at romantic verse.\n\nMY GARDEN\nBefore you, my passion was a root-bound garden choked with weed.\nBefore you, love was a cemetery devoid of seed.\nBut now your name bestows joy to the gloom.\nYour name, once uttered, brings my garden to bloom.\nFor you, O celestial daughter\nI water my garden with the wine of slaughter.\nRomance by the blade,\nMy enemies unmade.\nIn every cold ear, I whisper your name.\nAnd so you haunt the hearing canals of the dead.\nLike the sea in a shell in a sandy bed.\n\nI do believe this is my finest verse yet.\n\nSir Ozur</string>

<string key="VarangianKnights_Chapter_05">Sir Frelav the Flame, Las Torres War Camp</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_05_01">A Common Knight</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_05_01">Conqueror of Mud</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_05_01">Requisitioned a new spade. Again. Soon I’ll be digging with just a stick. That’s my lot now, digging up worm-eaten things or digging a hole to put in things for the worms to eat.\n\nA soul needs a good confessor, whether the ear of a trusted comrade or a good barkeep. Lacking both, I’m practicing my letters to keep my head straight. Used to be mocked for being decent with my letters, back in the village. I caved their heads in but good.\n\nAll the wealthy knights keep playing their chess games up above. Rulav and Ulfar circle each other for a drop of Attalus’s love. He in turn pines for our Lord and Master. But all the toil comes trickling down to us common foot soldiers.\n\nIt’s all about finding damned relics and mystical baubles now. These quarrelsome knights slaver over the prospect of finding such things like starving hounds. We chase rumors of the comings and goings of magicians and conjurers.\n\nI’ve dug up things that could plant a madness in your skull. But I don’t got time for that rot. I just keep digging. I’m the conqueror of mud.\n\n</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_05_02">Wonders of a New Land</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_05_02">An Opportunity</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_05_02">We came to this land to conquer, but it is wise to observe those we conquer. The customs, fashions, and speech are a strange mix. Some are alien. Others are familiar. Rumors among the lower ranks have gone so far as to posit that this was once our home. The Lord Commander has ordered that such talk be silenced.                                                                                                       \n\nWhere others find disquiet, I myself find opportunity. With such a bounty of variety around us, we might pick and choose that which we might bring into our own culture and thereby be strengthened. In fact, I took this notion from a soldier whom I bested in combat. He wielded an arquebus of magnificent design. I daresay it was superior to our own firearms. There is much we can learn here.   \n\nSir Yasen\n\n</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_05_03" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">A Formal Challenge</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_05_03" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">Trial by Combat</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_05_03" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">Sir Vadislav,\n\nBy Varangian law and the rites of Lord Varik, I hereby formally challenge you to ritual combat.\n\nLong I have borne your thousand tiny injuries, but now you have ventured upon insult, and I will have satisfaction. If there is courage in your heart to match the venom in your words, you will arrive at the site of our landing within three days to answer this challenge. If not, you forfeit your valor and your place in our order, under Lord Varik’s Law.\n\nBy blood, by stone, by marrow and bone, I challenge you. Steel is the only sacrament. Victory is the only god. \n\nEver the praises to Iznovgorod. Ever the praises to the Hammer.\n\nAwaiting at your pleasure,\n\nSir Anton\n</string>

<string key="VarangianKnights_Chapter_06" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">Sonechka the Pale, Myrddin's Camp</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_06_01" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">The Rat's Cheese</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_06_01" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">Personal entries from the journal of Sonechka the Pale</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_06_01" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">Day 78\nThe men found some sort of scavenger skulking around the camp, and brought him to me for questioning. Not one for talking, but with a bit of... convincing... he gave us enough. Some kind of treasure hunter, one of those mongrels who searches through ruins to find anything worth selling. One of the guards saw where he dumped his pack in his escape, and is bringing it to me now. Given his appearance, I expect nothing more than a few shiny rocks and some polished wood.\n\nDay 79\nEither this fool is lucky beyond belief, or knows far more than he is telling! In that rat's pack, he actually carried one of Myrddin's relics... I can hardly believe it. I never would have known if I hadn't brought it close to the barrier! It started sparkling and twinkling, some kind of sympathetic magical reaction. From that scavenger's notes, he found it somewhere far to the north. Perhaps...\nThe relic is to be sent away for further study, but Sir Vladislav has plans for the notebook. Messages have come in from Sir Anton in the southlands, and our Lord is preparing to take his retinue south in response, along with the notebook. I believe he may try to win Sir Anton over to the cause, and form an alliance of our two banners. He may be brutish at times, but Sir Vladislav understands how to seize an opportunity. I can only hope that Sir Anton is equally intelligent.\n\nDay 82\nDamnation! That stupid rat tried to escape again, tried to get the guards to kill him outright. This island's power makes imprisonment difficult... but not impossible. I'm sending him north to Riverside Keep under heavy guard. Sir Inegeld knows how to handle problematic cases like this one. Our little friend will be begging to spill his guts. If not, the Dark Lady's ways will bring me the information I need.</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_06_02" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">That Cursed Barrier</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_06_02" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">A tattered note, penned by an obviously angry hand</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_06_02" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">Given the proximity of this site to the nearby ruins, I am certain that Myrddin conducted at least some part of his research here. This barrier was obviously created by him, and must be protecting something of great importance. We will not be abandoning this site because of the incompetence of the work crews you have assigned me.\nSo no, I do not care how difficult it may be! Too much time has been wasted attempting to breach this barrier. Find some of the powder the others on this island use for their weapons, I will pack it into the rock surrounding the barrier and light the fuse myself! Better yet, have Inegeld bring down one of those cannons he is so proud of capturing and I'll put it to proper use!\n\nSonechka the Pale,\nMagister Magica, Vorongard</string>

<string key="VarangianKnights_Chapter_07" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">The Scarecrow's Travels</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_07_01" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">Help!</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_07_01" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">A scribbled note tucked in a wall around Myrddin's Camp</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_07_01" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">To the one who finds this:\nI have been taken by the Varangians, those cretins who seek to unlock the mysteries of Myrddin's experiments. Given my treatment at their hands, they won't use them for anything good.\n\nI overheard the guards when they thought I was asleep, and they intend to move me north to someplace called Riverside Keep. The leader here, Anton, is leaving tomorrow to go south, along with the notes of my travels. Damn me for a fool, but if they follow the trail back, they may locate what I think is Myrddin's true workshop.\n\nYou must head south. There is a woman there, Caoimhe, an apprentice to an Antiquarian. She is an ally, and familiar with the magics of the island. If these bastards have passed anywhere near her, she will know about it and be able to guide you. You must recover my notebook and give it to her.</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_07_02" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">A Parley, A Challenge</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_07_02" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">From a crumpled ball of rough paper outside Knight's Hideaway</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_07_02" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">Bah, Vladislav thinks he will be able to cow me into joining his little band, searching for trinkets and magic words in the rocks! There is no honor, no glory, no victory in that. We, the Kinjalgard, will take his baubles and mount them on our walls as trophies.\n\nI will not strike down one of our own in cold blood. I have prepared a challenge in the ways both old and new. Vladislav will accept. To do less would require his own men to strike him down as a coward. Then the Kinjalgard will be the blade that splits the ribs of these soft islanders, to prepare for the coming of the Lord Commander, and the rivers of blood will dye his boots red as he touches the sands.\n\nFor the Kinjalgard! For the glory of Iznovgorod!</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Title_07_03" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">Record of Romac's Travels</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Subtitle_07_03" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">A weatherbeaten journal filled with maps, notes, and sketches</string>
<string key="VarangianKnights_Body_07_03" rel_version="AI_Evil_Knights_P2">I've followed the clues, these scraps of knowledge and rumor and folklore, as far north as I dare go. Over the rocky spires ahead of me, I see the dusky smudge of Corruption that persists above the broken mountain.\nVine and stone and branch move here, some strange power binding their forms together - I've heard tell of them, but this is my first time seeing them for myself. Wonderous. A traveler stepped from the path and passed some invisible boundary to cause offense - these creatures appeared to tear that poor fool asunder. Deadly.\nI shall be careful where I place my feet.\nTo the east, a pristine lake shimmers as the sun rises, and the light warms my back as I enter the cave.\n\n---\n\nA rockslide. Of all things to be stopped by, a damnable rockslide should be the least of my worries. A small chamber, no more than a half dozen paces deep, illuminated by the light of glowing crystals. This must be the place... at least, behind these rocks. Unless I reveal the location to others, I fear I shall never see what secrets await. Myrddin's workshop has been sealed by the island itself.\n\nI did not come away emptyhanded. Buried in the dust at my feet, I found a... I'm not certain what it actually is. When I picked it up, it sparked and tingled with energy. It is small, possibly stone, fist-sized. Carved on every surface appear to be runes, words, symbols of some fashion. Some of the ancient tales of Myrddin mentioned magical stones, granted to individuals to allow safe passage into dangerous areas. I wonder if this may be one of those keystones?\n\nIt is time to return to safer pastures. I feel the eyes of the trees watching me far too closely here.</string>