<string key="Topic_HouseofGiacomo">Houses of Giacomo Altoviti</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_HouseofGiacomo">An architect's plans to transform the island</string>

<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Chapter_01">Futures of Aeternum</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Title_01_01">The Traitor's Path</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Subtitle_01_01">Rough pulp paper, discarded near a campsite</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Body_01_01">Too many eyes in the settlement, too many who might know him. I need time to figure out that gullible fool's notes. If he was right, we'll rule like kings on this island!\nI'm moving ahead to get everything ready. Wait for a few hours, then follow to the second camp. I'll leave more instructions for you there.</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Title_01_02">Burning Greed</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Subtitle_01_02">A scrap of paper, partially burned</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Body_01_02">......................at fool thought he coul.......... power of these\nAncients, .... think he was on to something. We just need to sta......\nof him, ............... particulars and get the ........ne built. Once\neveryone knows we're ............. that can provide safety, ..........\nflock to us - gold, azoth, women, power... everything will be ours for\n... taking! Meet me at the camp near Chason Steep, we'll divide ......\n......... plan our next move.</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Title_01_03">Defense Against the Withered</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Subtitle_01_03">From the notes of Albert Riches, First Light</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Body_01_03">- 2 parts water from a flowing source\n- 1 ground bone of Withered\n- 3 pinches of beach sand\n- Ashes from 1 long deck plank (cedar)\n- 1 bunch of hyssop\n- 2 vials of blood of Withered\n- 2 pinches powdered silver</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Title_01_04">Voices in the Wind</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Subtitle_01_04">A letter written in a rough hand, from a tent in Highpass Mining Camp</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Body_01_04">Arrived here yesterday, Airic said this place had what's needed for the plan. With all we're collecting, think we'll need to up the cost to stay in one of our little safehouses... maybe we could even charge azoth! Wouldn't that be something! Few years time, we'll need to start finding places to stash away all that profit!\nHeading to the caverns tomorrow, going to rest for a while. Strange... nobody's around, but I hear voices. Whispers. Must be the wind through the cliffs.\n\n...\n\nDamned creatures almost took my foot off! Patched myself up, but I'll be stuck here a bit. Just going to rest, listen to the voices in the wind.</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Title_01_05">Chasing the Ancients</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Subtitle_01_05">A loose page from a journal, found near a camp in Sunadire</string>
<string key="HouseofGiacomo_Body_01_05">Only one piece left, and I'll be done. Ichor and water, just need some of those stones... then I'll be set. Haven't heard from the others, no messages anywhere. Guess that means I don't have to share!\nHeading to Grus tomorrow, should find what I need there, then keep north. Maybe being away from these ruins will stop this buzzing...</string>