<string key="Topic_Description_WinterConvergence" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">A time of jolly cheer and ghastly grim tidings</string>
<string key="Topic_WinterConvergence" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Winter Convergence</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Body_01_01" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">It is time to make merry. Best not to tarry! &lt;i&gt;Roh-de-lay-ho-ho-ho!&lt;/i&gt;\n\nWhen the crisped air makes ghosts of your breath and the trees all dream in death, look for the signs of the Wanderer.\n\nWhen the stars burn brighter, when bleeding colors paint the sky in awe, when the Gleamite stars fall, look for Winter’s Father.\n\nWhen the Frigid Folk chuckle and the Ice Trolls cackle, huddle closer to the flames and the crackle, and look for the Frost Lord.\n\nO, darling. O, deario. It is time to make merry. Best not to tarry! &lt;i&gt;Roh-de-lay-ho-ho-ho!&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Body_01_02" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Sing a carol, now, to the Winter Wanderer.\n\nWhen the sky fills with celestial light and winter blankets the earth, the Wanderer comes forth! Know him by his First Aspect. Call him Yulnir. Call him Father Winter.\n\nHe comes with a benevolent twinkle in his eye. He comes wrapped in a cloak made from the multi-colored sky.\n\nEvery home he visits. Every hearth he blesses. On the coldest nights, he brings feast and bounty. He feeds body and soul with a warmth that lasts from season to season. The hearth of the heart!\n\nBut Father Winter only gifts those who have offered love and warmth to their fellows all the year round.\n\nO, darling. O, deario. It is time to make merry. Pray do not tarry! &lt;i&gt;Roh-de-lay-ho-ho-ho!&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Body_01_03" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Sing a carol, now, to the Winter Wanderer. \n\nWhen the days shrivel to nothing, and you fathom the bottom of your bowl, and you enter the long night of the soul, the Wanderer comes forth! Know him by his Second Aspect. Call him Jotunir. Call him Lord Frost. Call him the Winter Warrior! \n\nHe comes cloaked in a patchwork coat stitched from all of our nightmares. He comes with a prerogative of vengeance. The hearts of the selfish and vain are his food. Merrily, merrily he goes about his terrible business. He stalks the wild places, stands in shadows, and you may not even notice when he drinks your misty breath. \n\nO, darling. O, deario! It’s past time to make merry. Did you dare tarry? It may already be too late. &lt;i&gt;Roh-de-lay-ho-ho-ho!&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Body_01_04" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Sing a carol, now, to the Frigid Folk. \n\nCall them the children of the Frost Lord. Call them holy mischief. Call them merry mayhem. They all grin with demented joy. They know the names of every child who fell through the ice. \n\nThey bring gifts of festive chaos. They gather souls for the army of their lord. Best to leave out something sweet, lest they find something else to nibble and eat. \n\nO, darling. O, deario! You better make merry. The alternative’s quite scary. &lt;i&gt;Roh-de-lay-ho-ho-ho!&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Body_01_05" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Sing a carol, now, to the Ice Trolls. \n\nCall them minions of the Winter Warrior. Call them the grunts of the army of Forever Winter. The Frigid Folk caught these unfortunate souls and ate their names. That is alright. They won’t need their names anymore.\n\nO, darling. O, deario! You better make merry. Make merry! &lt;i&gt;Roh-de-lay-ho-ho-ho!&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Body_01_06" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Sing a carol, now… \n\nNo. There are no carols now. There is only silence and the wind and the groan of ice. \n\nCall it Lord Frost’s victory. Call it Winter Warrior triumphant. Call it Forever Winter. Everything rests in the belly of a blizzard, and the Winter Warrior holds illimitable dominion for all eternity. \n\nO, darling. O, deario! It was time to make merry. You wretches did tarry. It is far, far too late. &lt;i&gt;Roh-de-lay-ho-ho-ho!&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Body_02_01" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">It’s that time. I tend to know it before just before the graying skies and snowfall. Old war wounds ache just a little more. \n\nMany folk are already setting up their decorations, dashes of color in the winter gloom. I’ll be joining them. The way the stories go, we do this to appease the Winter Wanderer, keep him in his jolly aspect. We avoid the punishment of the second aspect. Is all that true? I don’t rightly know. I do know that to get through a hard winter, we need to make warmth and cheer. Why not drink? Why not dance? Why not set up festive decor?</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Body_02_02" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Come one, come all! \n\nIt is the time of the Celestial Binding. The Winter Convergence is here! \n\nTonight begins the great Gleamite hunt. \n\nTrack the glowing stones as they fall from the heavens. \n\nDecorate everything with their cheer. \n\nPrizes to the most Gleamite stones found!</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Body_03_01" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">&lt;b&gt;A Scholarly Note on the True Meaning of the Holidays  &lt;/b&gt; \n\nI say, but we have lost the thread of the true importance of the Winter Convergence. Now those two words drown in association with every possible holiday tradition brought from every corner of the world by the sailors who now call Aeternum home.   \n\nThe true import of the Convergence is lost on the layperson, jolly red noses festooned with exploding capillaries, betraying one too many imbibed cups of good cheer. What is important is that this is a celestial convergence, a very particular alignment of heavenly bodies. Ancient texts speak of this Celestial Binding. Understanding of these awesome forces could have profound impact on our sciences and esoteric arts. \n\nThe true person of learning must study the wonders that bend above us and say “Humbug!” to the slack-jawed revelers who would distract them.</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Body_03_02" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">&lt;b&gt;A Scholarly Note on This Festive Apocalypse&lt;/b&gt;\n\nAncient texts and drunken gossip seem to intersect on matters concerning the so called “Forever Winter”. Details vary, but both agree on some species of apocalyptic cycle, a catastrophic blizzard that either never ends or lasts so long as to bury living memory in frost. The more colorful yarns tell of this being an age ruled by some demoniacal aspect of the Winter Wanderer — a Winter Warrior, Lord of Frost, or holiday devil.\n\nI’ve come to no definitive conclusion on any of these claims. However, the power of the Celestial Binding, at this time of year, in this place, could potentially have an awful (and I do stress the word “awe”) on both the stratosphere and the climate.</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Body_03_03" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">&lt;b&gt;A Scholarly Note on Jolly Customs Born of an Evil Tree&lt;/b&gt;\n\nLet the record show that I do not, at this time, subscribe to the following story. However, it was relayed to me, and I trap it on the page now, like a pinned moth, so that I might dissect it later.\n\nIn the Long Ago of Aeternum, a dark sect worshiped the terrible Second Aspect of the Winter Wanderer. They performed profane rituals before a blessed tree. They danced naked in the dark with the Frigid Folk, yet frostbite touched neither their limbs nor their nethers.\n\nOne day, a group of brave Aeternumites confronted these holiday diabolists and chopped down the wicked tree. They promptly displayed their arboreal trophy in town. The tradition became a mainstay of the holiday, symbolizing a triumph over evil. Over time, the particulars of the symbolism of this act was absorbed into every aspect of the holiday.</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Chapter_01" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">The Winter Wanderer</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Chapter_02" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Festive Sundries</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Chapter_03" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Scholarly Notes on the Season</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Subtitle_01_01" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Pages from a book of fables</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Subtitle_01_02" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Pages from a book of fables</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Subtitle_01_03" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Pages from a book of fables</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Subtitle_01_04" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Pages from a book of fables</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Subtitle_01_05" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Pages from a book of fables</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Subtitle_01_06" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Pages from a book of fables</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Subtitle_02_01" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">From a journal of holiday observations</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Subtitle_02_02" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">A battered flier</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Subtitle_03_01" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Scribed in the book of a self-important scholar</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Subtitle_03_02" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Scribed in the book of a self-important scholar</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Subtitle_03_03" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Scribed in the book of a self-important scholar</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Title_01_01" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">A Seasonal Fable (part 1)</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Title_01_02" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">A Seasonal Fable (part 2)</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Title_01_03" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">A Seasonal Fable (part 3)</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Title_01_04" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">A Seasonal Fable (part 4)</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Title_01_05" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">A Seasonal Fable (part 5)</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Title_01_06" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">A Seasonal Fable (part 6)</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Title_02_01" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Of Decorations and Merriment</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Title_02_02" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">Come One, Come All!</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Title_03_01" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">The Celestial Convergence</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Title_03_02" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">The Forever Winter</string>
<string key="WinterConvergence_Title_03_03" rel_version="Event_WinterConvergence_Perm">The Tree of Light</string>