<string key="Topic_FTUEIsland">A New World</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_FTUEIsland">Documents and discoveries from when you first awoke after being shipwrecked</string>

<string key="Lore_Chapter_Commission">Commission</string>
<string key="FTUE_Title_SealedCommission">Journey to Aeternum</string>
<string key="FTUE_Subtitle_SealedCommission">Journey to Aeternum, Fragment 1</string>
<string key="FTUE_Body_SealedCommission">We sail west-northwest with the breeze from the west increasing steadily. Cloudy, with unending rain. 2 knots, steady. We are about 600 miles under sail. Unseasonal dampness and warmth threatens to spoil provisions. Crew is haggard and morale is low with none in command sleeping nigh three days. Have the alchemists of the Old World sent us to our deaths chasing a fairytale?\n“Mere Courage” Log 13</string>

<string key="Lore_Chapter_DeathAndRebirth">Death and Rebirth</string>
<string key="FTUE_Subtitle_lore1a">Journey to Aeternum, Fragment 2</string>
<string key="FTUE_Location_lore1a">Tidal Sand Flats</string>

<string key="FTUE_Title_lore1a">Journey to Aeternum</string>
<string key="FTUE_Title_lore1b">Regarding Azoth</string>
<string key="FTUE_Title_lore1c">Crash Landing</string>
<string key="FTUE_Title_lore1d">Almeda</string>
<string key="FTUE_Title_lore2">Captain's Revenge</string>
<string key="FTUE_Title_lore3">Ship Scrawling, October 11</string>
<string key="FTUE_Title_lore4a">Lay of the Land</string>
<string key="FTUE_Title_lore4b">Blue Lanterns</string>
<string key="FTUE_Title_lore4c">Alive At What Cost</string>
<string key="FTUE_Title_lore4d">Aeternum Sighted</string>

<string key="FTUE_Body_lore1a">The storm has become nigh unbearable. Gale winds, heavy bursts, roiling sea. The sleepless Captain insists we push ahead, his fixation on the vial of azoth onboard is too strong to combat. The substance is said to multiply the natural properties of all things, but the only thing I have seen it do is increase the Captain's possessive nature and secretive ways. He mutters to himself about a land of conflict, conquering, and endless azoth. None dare challenge him.\n“Mere Courage” Log 17\n</string>
<string key="FTUE_Body_lore1b">At the Captain's request I have made a study of this strange vial he carries.\nWhat lies within is neither mineral nor liquid, defying all known properties of matter. It glows a haunting blue, and seems almost to hum when held by human hands.\nAll who make the perilous journey to Aeternum seek this azoth, but few understand it. I hope I am able to study the wellsprings of this substance said to be found on this strange island, and hope even more that I can send my research back to the Old World.\n\nAlmeda Umber\nScholar and Naturalist to the Capital Survey Expedition's “Mere Courage”\n</string>
<string key="FTUE_Body_lore1c">I am two hours now wading amongst the wreckage. High water is coming and like to dislodge the ruins of the great ships grounded here. Some look ancient, while our galley appears to be the newest addition to this graveyard of expeditions. I cannot stay, but will forge inland to seek an overlook to make a signal and spy for other survivors.\n\nJoan Caron\nCartwright to the Capital Survey Expedition\nSurvivor of the wrecked ship “Mere Courage”\n</string>
<string key="FTUE_Body_lore1d">I swear today I saw Almeda, speared through the chest with a timber, same as I witnessed him thrown overboard six days ago. There he was—pale, water-bloated, hissing, incoherent, and yet the same Almeda I shared mess with. I fled from his ghastly visage as he swiped at me with hands decaying. I do not know what shore we have encountered, but it is not the promised land of our dreams. Only purgatory, only a promise of unholy punishment.\n\nJoan Caron\nCartwright to the Capital Survey Expedition\nSurvivor of the wrecked ship “Mere Courage”\n</string>
<string key="FTUE_Body_lore2">A foul, rotting thing bearing resemblance to our Captain struck at me from the ruins of a sloop. I drove a splintered oar through its neck, but not before it pierced my stomach with its rusted sword.\nCannot stop the bleeding. Shelter here. Must rest.\n\nJoan Caron\nCartwright to the Capital Survey Expedition\nSurvivor of the wrecked ship “Mere Courage”\n</string>
<string key="FTUE_Body_lore3">Nothing dies</string>
<string key="FTUE_Body_lore4a">I am beginning to understand why only a few vials of the potent azoth made it back to the Old World. It seems all who crash here are stranded with no hope of sailing out into the persistent storm surrounding the island. Even if I were to find a crew and repair a ship I doubt we would be able to get further than the horizon before being smashed to bits by a choppy and unforgiving sea. \n\nJoan Caron\nCartwright to the Capital Survey Expedition\nSurvivor of the wrecked ship “Mere Courage” \n\n</string>
<string key="FTUE_Body_lore4b">There must be other survivors of the wrecks, though I cannot see them. I see the marks of their presence, footprints tinged with azoth in the sand leading my way forward. I follow these tracks and the strange blue flames that occupy the repurposed ship lanterns along the path. I pray I find some kind of refuge walking in the footsteps of those who came before me.\n\nJoan Caron\nCartwright to the Capital Survey Expedition\nSurvivor of the wrecked ship “Mere Courage” \n</string>
<string key="FTUE_Body_lore4c">Awoke at camp, injury healed. I cannot judge how much time has passed but it was not the month of recovery that I needed for such a wound. I am restored, but… incomplete. I cannot return to the shore for fear of what I might find there—the carcass of my former self. This place will not let me die, as it has not released any sailor who drowned, only to wash upon these shores. The reaper claims no souls here, and the dead wander.\n\nJoan Caron\nCartwright to the Capital Survey Expedition\nSurvivor of the wrecked ship “Mere Courage” \n</string>
<string key="FTUE_Body_lore4d">In the distance I have spotted two grand statues of fine craftsmanship standing against the waves. The tide has receded and there is nothing for me in the muddy grave behind me. Ahead, there is a bar of sand leading to the main land of Aeternum. I know not what I will find there, but it must be better than this.\n\nJoan Caron\nCartwright to the Capital Survey Expedition\nSurvivor of the wrecked ship “Mere Courage” \n</string>
