<string key="Topic_AnonymousManuscripts">Anonymous Manuscripts</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_AnonymousManuscripts">Various letters, diaries, and other writings of authors unknown</string>

<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Chapter_04">Squash Farmers</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Chapter_05">The Fall</string>

<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_04_01">The River Provides</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_04_02">The Community Grows</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_04_03">A Sudden Turn</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_05_01">Up to No Good</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_05_02">Violent Storm</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Title_05_03">On the Banks of the River</string>

<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_04_01">A Farmer's Words</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_04_02">A Farmer's Words</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_04_03">A Farmer's Words</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_05_01">A loose letter from an unknown author.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_05_02">A loose letter from an unknown author.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Subtitle_05_03">A loose letter from an unknown author.</string>

<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_04_01">This 2nd year harvest proves our stubbornness was justified. Already more are clamoring to join our budding community. The soil is rich and the river provides. \n\n- F. Sneed</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_04_02">It is wonderful to now have neighbors! Our shared toil has enriched the lives of us all. 4th year harvest is just around the bend and my heart soars.\n\n- F. Sneed</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_04_03">Something peculiar has been discovered in the fields. We have lost a good portion of our harvest to a rot that appeared, quite literally, overnight. We have seen no worm or fly, yet the fruit is blackened and bruised. And the soil reeks of death. \n\n- F. Sneed</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_05_01">Jonas was with those hooligans again. I saw them on the bridge and the following morning his face was a mess. I don't like how this place is changing him. He is not the boy I once knew.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_05_02">There was a great commotion several nights ago. Several fevered shouts could be heard from the crest of the waterfall. The precise words were lost to the tumult of the falls themselves. But there were several figures silhouetted against the storm tossed sky in what appeared to be a violent struggle. A thunderbolt forced me to avert my gaze for but an instant and they were gone. I've heard nothing since.</string>
<string key="AnonymousManuscripts_Body_05_03">More flotsam has washed upon the riverbank this morning and amongst it was a great clump of human hair, matted and bloodied. I fear it belongs to Jonas.</string>
