<string key="Topic_DrownedPages">The Drowned Pages</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_DrownedPages">Loose letters and journal entries pertaining to The Drowned</string>

<string key="DrownedPages_Chapter_01">Wynn's Diary</string>

<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_01">Backstabbers</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_02">Stranded</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_03">Routines of Life</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_04">The Stranger</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_05">A Familiar Face</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Title_01_06">Hope Lives</string>

<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_01">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_02">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_03">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_04">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_05">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Subtitle_01_06">A Page from Wynn's Diary.</string>

<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_01">Ol' Irontoe has really gotten us into something this time! Why did he think this was going to be such a good idea?! We knew not to trust those backstabbers. How many times are we going to let them play us for fools?\n\n-Wynn</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_02">They struck as soon as the parley had finished. The lying cowards! And now this god-forsaken storm has doomed us all. We have salvaged as much as we could from the wreckage… but there is no sign of the others. Hopefully the seas have claimed them for good.\n\n-Wynn</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_03">It's bizarre how life, even in this place, can become so routine. Now that the bulk of construction is complete, the captain has lost a bit of his edge. It turns out this place may end up being what was promised after all, despite the struggle of the last few years.\n\n-Wynn</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_04">I don't trust that stranger, no matter what Irontoe says. Where did he come from? How long has he been watching us? Why is it he only shows up after we have completed all of the difficult work of building this place? \n\nSomething is not right. He stinks of death.\n\n-Wynn</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_05">I may have been wrong. Edward is not what I feared. His knowledge of this place has helped us avoid many potential catastrophes. But I still can't shake the feeling that I have met him somewhere before… and I was not wrong about his stench.\n\n-Wynn</string>
<string key="DrownedPages_Body_01_06">Ol' Irontoe has fallen gravely ill. Edward is tending to his needs, but I don't hold out hope that he will last the week. I've seen this before with my own father. But the way Edward speaks, he instills hope, even in the dying.\n\n-Wynn</string>
