<string key="Topic_Expedition">The Expedition</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_Expedition">Pages and Journals of the great expedition of Captain Isabella</string>

<string key="Expedition_Chapter_01">Frederico's Letters</string>
<string key="Expedition_Chapter_02">The Captain's Log</string>

<string key="Expedition_Title_01_01">In the Morning</string>
<string key="Expedition_Title_01_02">Visiting the Church</string>
<string key="Expedition_Title_01_03">The Prisoner</string>
<string key="Expedition_Title_02_01">Comfort</string>
<string key="Expedition_Title_02_02">Rumors</string>

<string key="Expedition_Subtitle_01_01">This letter is faded with age</string>
<string key="Expedition_Subtitle_01_02">This letter is faded with age</string>
<string key="Expedition_Subtitle_01_03">This letter is faded with age</string>
<string key="Expedition_Subtitle_02_01">This page is faded with age</string>
<string key="Expedition_Subtitle_02_02">This page is faded with age</string>

<string key="Expedition_Body_01_01">I have informed Lady Isabella of the news. The loss of her brothers at sea the year before was hard enough for her to bear, but the passing of her mother and father has dealt a terrible blow to her spirit. I have not yet informed her of the debts in her father's name, as I am still going through the accounts. To lose what remains of her family and the fortunes within a year… it is a tragedy. \n\nThe debts seem given over heavily to one of the new companies, that of the “Red Sign”. I am unfamiliar with it, but both her father and brothers seemed to have paid quite an expense on their joint enterprise and exploration of the islands around the New World… it is rather confusing in parts, but I am parsing the information piece by piece.\n\nDespite the loss, she has remained strong. Each morning, she goes to the church on the grounds and prays. I have asked the local priest to visit her, and bestow what support he can.\n\n- F</string>
<string key="Expedition_Body_01_02">…we traveled there by coach over several days, and I was not privy to the visit. Isabella met the man in his cell alone, and spoke with him for hours before she finally returned. Her eyes were bright, and where the tedium of days had worn upon her, she seem invigorated with new life. \n\nI have seen this look before, and I do not like it. It was the light that burned in her brother's eyes – her father's eyes. Worried, I asked her how the conversation had gone, and she said, the treasure upon the man was not the Azoth, but the man himself.\n\nHe was living proof that the Fountain of Youth existed, and it could grant eternal life to those who found it. The isle of Azoth was no legend – it was true.\n\nI asked her what could be gained from such knowledge, and she laughed lightly and replied, “Because he says he can take us there.”\n\n- F</string>
<string key="Expedition_Body_01_03">Isabella claimed the isle the prisoner had spoke of was called “Vitae Aeternum”. Whether this was the prisoner's name or the translation bestowed upon his mad ramblings, I am uncertain, but the name has stuck – much like the prisoner's offer, I fear. Isabella has taken his knowledge as if it has lit a fire in her, and it has given her a frightening sense of purpose. I urge her to rest – cautiously – but she will not hear of it. The mere hint of the Fountain of Youth's presence has moved her to action.\n\nThe crown was not so understanding – and Isabella had the misfortune to speak of the source of the fountain. They had been willing to back her request to see the heretical prisoner, but a Fountain of Youth returned a different, more scornful answer. It turned out that she might have tried a different tactic, had she thought of it – but as it happened, her father's debts caused an unexpected result.\n\n- F</string>
<string key="Expedition_Body_02_01">I often seek comfort at the small chapel on the grounds. It is peaceful there, quiet, and I can hear myself think. I know the servants (those who remain) think I come here to pray… but I come only to listen to my thoughts, to sort through them, one by one so I might make sense of it all.\n\nWe held the services for my brothers here when they were lost at sea last year, and then again for Mother and Father less than a month ago. I expect even the meager services expended the last of the family “fortune,” which have never recovered from our numerous setbacks. Father proved to be in debt to many companies, and had risked a great deal in his enterprises… and now I am left to bear that burden. I wished I could have traded places with him and my brothers – not in death, but upon the seas, to be far from this place.\n\nNow I simply feel older than my years should allow. It is not grief, it is simply that I lack the compass for where I should go, what I should do – and what I can do. There are not enough years in one's life to do all that I wish to do – or had wished to do, and what status our family had is lost, squandered on fool's errands.\n\nYet in this simple church, I feel at peace, and take comfort in it.\n\nIsabella</string>
<string key="Expedition_Body_02_02">The local priest came to speak to me this morning as I sat within the church. I shared my thoughts with him, and he quoted Scripture to me. I had not exchanged more than a few words with him before, but the words came easily. I told him of the absence I felt of family – the fear of debt. And aside from the looming misfortune, there was the looming presence of age to contend with. My brothers had their lives taken from them by the sea, but Mother and Father… they deserved more years than they were granted. I told the priest my father had often spoke, quite passionately, of a Fountain of Youth, where he might take back his years and gain enough years to recover from the trials that life brought with it.\n\nThe priest was silent at this, then said, almost apologetically, that we were given this life, a requisite number of years because more… more might cheapen life's beauty. To wish to extend one's life – he seemed quite pained at this – was even considered offensive, heretical by the Church. He spoke as if he had heard heretics saying such, which piqued my curiosity. When I pressed him on it, he protested that I had misread his tone. Anyone speaking, let alone claiming to have proof of such nonsense, would be kept under lock and key so their madness might not affect others.\n\nHe knows of someone like this, I am certain of it. I will make inquiries.\n\nIsabella</string>

