<string key="Topic_KubikirisBurden">Kubikiri's Burden</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_KubikirisBurden">The penance of Kubikiri, bearer of dread Sensou no Ko</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_KubikirisBurden" xsi:nil="true"/>
<string key="Topic_Description_Kubikiri'sBurden" xsi:nil="true"/>

<string key="KubikirisBurden_Chapter_01">Sensou no Ko</string>

<string key="KubikirisBurden_Title_01_01">Kubikiri's Occupation</string>
<string key="KubikirisBurden_Title_01_02">Kubikiri's Rise</string>
<string key="KubikirisBurden_Title_01_03">Kubikiri's Fall</string>
<string key="KubikirisBurden_Title_01_04">Kubikiri's plea</string>

<string key="KubikirisBurden_Subtitle_01_01">Kubikiri in the old world.</string>
<string key="KubikirisBurden_Subtitle_01_02">Kubikiri's ascent to royal executioner</string>
<string key="KubikirisBurden_Subtitle_01_03">The kami enters Kubikiri's mind</string>
<string key="KubikirisBurden_Subtitle_01_04">Wherein Kubikiri begs for release.</string>

<string key="KubikirisBurden_Body_01_01">Here I leave the last testament of Kubikiri the Edge of the World, and Sensou no Ko, the demon Axe.\nPray you heed my woeful tale and stay far from the cursed blade, and never seek it out!</string>
<string key="KubikirisBurden_Body_01_02">When I was a young man, I turned my forester childhood toward learning the way of the headsman. I was efficient and clean, as good executioners are, and soon, my talents were recognized.\nI was given a gift! A badge of office.\n\nWoe to me, Sensou no Ko, the legendary executioners' axe was bestowed upon me.\nThus my curse took hold.</string>
<string key="KubikirisBurden_Body_01_03">The axe was more than a badge, or even a tool. The axe hides within it a demon!\nThe kami stirred as soon as I took hold of the thing, it filled me with a strength like I've never felt before!\nI was overtaken by a white-hot pride, and a terrible bloodlust.\nSoon my duties were not enough, and the kami Sensou no Ko - that demon blade - drove me to kill them all!\nI fled to sea, hiding on a trade-ship, but I could never escape fate.\nIt brought me here, for penance.</string>
<string key="KubikirisBurden_Body_01_04">I no longer even feel the eyes of my ancestors upon me, all have turned away.\nThe cries, the screaming, Sensou no Ko's victims clamor in my head.\nWorse though, worse is the hunger.\n\nEven killing doesn't slake it any longer, these hollow souls hardly count as deaths to the demon blade at all.\nSoon, I believe it will turn on me for sustenance.\n\nBy now I would welcome it.</string>
