<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_05_01">**The page is covered in strange symbols and markings, looking like no language you have ever encountered, yet somehow the sounds come unbidden into your mind. You recognize the circle-and-split-fork design used as the banner by the Corrupted across Aeternum. Could this be their language?** \n\nUbemabayib mit'enggâf fip'anda ambi. Ngo atwak fi 'av mifiwo ñâb. Wu p'â kuñ mip'ânfâp ag, p'â edendakti pad Aeternum ven af.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_05_02">**This page is covered with the symbols and markings you've come to know as the Corrupted language. The foreign sounds fill your head as you read. This page has a crude drawing of a smelter, and some liquid being poured into crucibles.**\n\nMiven pad fangok fi Aeternum yi kot'une ñân p'â ve urompi xapwing ambi. Âbtahâr pad azoth deñâñogambi euwângubda rongembi. Ngo xagimbi he akimbi ika'atku miwod itkâ âbtawungu 'ufoxo axo.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_05_03">**A page with the cramped symbols of the Corrupted language. Taking up much of the page is a sketch of skulls and bones being pounded to dust.** \n\nUbamabayib rugi impane 'adoh uwâkombe azoth kevambi yi detwek. Baguf xak'ov bab mi a p'ânvâboxo pab ambi. Xa xauwâñâb ñâna ko, ngo uwâkombe 'ami xaipix xa pab veh axo, he mip'âtweg ubaxahev xakong ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_05_04">**Another page with more of the Corrupted writing. This page has a drawing of miners digging ore from the depths, and what appears to be one of the Corrupted Cultists leading a ritual.** \n\nXafang bing Magmebeg umik'ig vetix at pa ngub a, fa nena pad miwonuykañ a atkifitorambi. Xayi miawi xa ñâtwap mi'anutu mip'u nguboxo.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_05_05">**Yet another page written by the Corrupted. Along the side of the page are images of trees being cut and dragged away for some unknown purpose.** \n\nXayup pad tif tid gufoxo ubatif mimak'â'a fi pab nero yi p'â ag 'umbi mi a. Bar vetimbi, uatkiguf panumbi heñ ika'atku axo he ngo ubaguf miwod kengâmbi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_06_01">To the attention of: General Alazar\nName: James Sexton, Soulwarden\nCurrent post: Eastburn Outpost, Great Cleave\nRequested post: Anywhere else\n\nAdd'l. Notes:\nI'll take whatever we've got. Send me to the front lines in Shattered Mountain, if that's what it takes. No battle can be more painful than the memories I have here, with her.\n-J.S.\n</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_06_02">Patricia, my love,\n\nThe tincture isn't working. My leg is turning black, and the ice is creeping toward my heart. I was in such a hurry to leave this place, I got sloppy. I let the Corrupted overwhelm me. Now, it seems, I'll never leave.\n\nHow ridiculous, to lie in the snow and wait for the end, to scribble my last words in the dark! I wish you'd ran away with me, all those times I asked. If only I'd found the right words then. \nMaybe this is for the best. When they recover my Heartgem from my corpse, they'll lay it next to yours.\n\nI'll be with you soon.\n-James\n</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_07_01">My followers have completed construction of the village, under my guidance. I have spent much of my time planning our future, and one thing concerns me: the Corruption to the north, past the Ancient gate. And while some called me a fool to do so, I set forth to see this evil for myself.\nI ventured north of the gate, able to avoid the attentions of the demons long enough to learn what I needed to. But, fate decided to set me on a new path. Climbing through the mountain passes, I slipped and found myself in a ruin of the Ancients. Inside, artifacts and riches filled the cave to the brim, but what drew me in were the murals on the wall. I did not recognize something specific in them at first, but having studied the spiritual paths of many, I should be able to recognize a ritual!\nFrom my loose understanding of the murals, I believe the Ancients had a way of sanctifying areas on the island, explaining why the settlements to the south are protected from attack. These murals showed me how to do the same! This may be the best way to protect my flock, to give them the peace that so many of them deserve.\nI claimed the artifacts in the cave, bringing back as many as I was able to carry, and have matched many to the murals. I must determine how this ritual was done so that I may perform it here for the village, and will not rest until I do!</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_07_02">&lt;i&gt;I have done it. I now understand how the Ancients performed their wonderful, terrible, ritual. I have already taken the first steps, distributing the tokens to each of the townsfolk.&lt;/i&gt;\n\nNo, I mustn't! It is wrong, it is foolish, it is evil! Their wills exterminated! I don't... I need, I must...\n\n&lt;i&gt;As the Herald of this flock, it falls to me to make the hard decisions for everyone. I held a meeting at the church and explained that the ritual would protect this hilltop... and all in attendance agreed that we must do whatever we can to protect ourselves...&lt;/i&gt;\n\nSomething in those ruins, unclear how... I am fighting for control, but I feel it winning. I have given my most trusted follower specific instructions on what to do. Being near the stone lends me strength, but I know it must be consumed in the ritual. This... will be the last time I have control, and I cannot stop the ritual. But... my flock, they will not be taken by Corruption. Their souls, their minds, will be freed. It is the only way.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_08_01">There is a creature, a blue winged serpent that lurks in the Great Cleave's waters. Some don't believe it exists, but I've had it on my line more than once and that is one tricky beastie.\n\nI've heard it roaring in the night, breaching the water like a dolphin to let loose its terrible cry. One day it shall be mine, and then no one will doubt me.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_08_02">The Soulwardens, a noble order of Aeternum, are at times all that stand between the southern settlements and complete Corruption.\n\nThey operate in Corruption-heavy areas and dish out punishment towards those who would attack innocents and spread their Corrupted filth whether by offering power or force.\n\nThey may have just arrived but they're already doing some good for this island, so I've thrown my support behind them. Will you help me as well, Machera?</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_09_01">Bi xak'ub pad xap'âni, kot'uneok t'etâknângik at ambi uyih pad. Mav kot'uneok tu añipambi 'ag K'ox Eipa, yi kot'uneok ñix ambi.\nMav kot'uneok tu 'ag Eâbtak'ongek manâx, t'ei kot'uneok tu ambi yâmbi.\nHe kot'uneok tu t'etâknângik 'adoh, yi kot'uneok ñix ambi. Ngo bih fa kot'uneok ven t'etâknângik at ambi.\nEpab eher pad bih Eipa ven ambi. He bih eipa i'âba Ketiro 'apâmbi ven ba rungegambi.\n\nPaikitkâ Ubakomeo Oseguera</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_09_02">He xa Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook bih Ubeipa uwâruknâr fipin ungok.\n\nNgo bih Eâbtabig Eâbtak'uko Uwâruna axo.\nBing Ingot fipin Uwâñi p'â yâk'up fa. Bing Uwâkombe fipin Âbta'atku p'â dek'ân fa.\nK'o ñâkaok pad k'oba he de, Uwângov p'â ngokoxo.\n\nPaikitkâ Ubakomeo Oseguera</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_09_03">He xa Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook bih Ubeipa uwâruknâr fipin ungok.\n\nNgo bih Eâbtabimbi Eâbtak'uko 'Atkâ axo.\nMab bih Uwâñi fipin p'â Ngo'ook p'â k'unoxo. Mab Ngo'ook fipin 'Agmox p'â rompuxo fa.\nXa kendu mirux urompu.\nXa Tik.\nXa Ngoñ.\nXa Gab.\n\nPaikitkâ Ubakomeo Oseguera</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_09_04">He xa Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook bih Ubeipa uwâruknâr fipin ungok.\n\nNgo bih Eâbta'ag Eâbtak'uko Yiñâmbâ axo.\nYed 'Agmox fipin Magmebeg p'â kâknahoxo. Yed 'Agmox fipin p'â At'u vevu xamitâñ ganexo.\nXa Uwâgañ fipin miñâg p'â 'afahoxo.\n\nPaikitkâ Ubakomeo Oseguera</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_09_05">He xa Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook bih Ubeipa uwâruknâr fipin ungok.\n\nNgo bih Eâbtubafix Eâbtak'uko bih Eâbtabig, bih Eâbta'atki, he bih Eâbtakendu ambi.\nXa Eâbtakendu, Uwângov p'â ngokoxo.\nXa Eâbtakendu, Eâbtak'uko p'â ngokoxo.\nÂbtakenduok fa Eâbtativ eher pad bih Ewupwat ven ambi.\n\nPaikitkâ Ubakomeo Oseguera</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_10_03" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">I ain’t sleeping right. I mean, I sleep on the job, if you can call a job sitting on a red fluffy chair thing with no arms. But at night, I hear things. Like rats, only this sounds a lot bigger than a rat. Something’s walking around on the ceiling, in the room down below.\n\nI’m gonna stay awake and see if I hear it again.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_10_04" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">I heard that sound again. Got outta bed and knocked on the floor three times. Here I am, grown man, knocking on the floor.\n\nBut then I heard it. Three knocks, right under my feet. It wasn’t Iki, I checked, and he was asleep in his chair. I ain’t religious, but I prayed to anything that’d listen. I didn’t want to go back into my room. So I’m sleeping out here tonight in the big room.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_10_05" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">I got in. Just like I thought, Iki goes out to the privy at night. \n\nIt was wide and dark down there, a cellar that covered the whole house. But it wasn’t empty. One corner was all tidy and decorated like a little girl’s room. I felt like something was watching me, so I got up the ladder and shut the trap door behind me. I’ll bring a lamp tomorrow night. I don’t think I’ll sleep.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_10_06" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">This time, candles were lit in the cellar. I heard a noise behind me–a little girl. Only her eyes and mouth, they’re sideways of what they should be. She starts screaming something fierce about Iki, her father.\n\nThe bastard himself drops down from the trap door, yelling “Stay away from her!” \n\nI saw her smile, right before she bit into my neck. I clawed up the ladder and ran to my room for my sword, thinking I’d cut their throats and be done with it. But in the steel, I saw it. My eyes, my mouth– they’re sideways now, just like hers.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Body_10_07" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">I just felt it under my feet. Three knocks.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Chapter_05">Plans of the Corrupted</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Chapter_06">James' Letters</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Chapter_07">The Herald's Victory</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Chapter_08">Klaus' Memories</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Chapter_09">Corpora Oseguera</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_05_01">Found in Sunderfort</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_05_02">Found in Acedia Bastion</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_05_03">Found in Breakaway Fort</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_05_04">Found in Hollowing Fort</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_05_05">Found in Nullcavity</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_06_01">Found in Tempest Lane</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_06_02">Written in a shaky hand</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_07_01">Found in Eeriedune Graveyard</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_07_02">Found in Misty Borough</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_08_01">Beast of the Water</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_08_02">Feeding the Troops</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_09_01">Paiveti p'ekome, mikuñ Efiki pad bih Eipa ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_09_02">Paiveti p'ekome, Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook xa bih u'aping ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_09_03">Paiveti p'ekome, Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook xa bih u'aping ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_09_04">Paiveti p'ekome, Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook xa bih u'aping ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_09_05">Paiveti p'ekome, Âbtafixok Âbtak'ukook xa bih u'aping ambi.</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_10_04" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Recovered from a large empty house in the wastes of Great Cleave</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_10_05" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Recovered from a large empty house in the wastes of Great Cleave</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_10_06" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A torn journal page, smeared with blood</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Subtitle_10_07" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A torn journal page, scrawled in blood</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_05_01">Mysterious Orders</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_05_02">The Twisted Smelter</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_05_03">Bonemeal</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_05_04">Ritual Mine</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_05_05">Clearcutting</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_06_01">Request for Reassignment</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_06_02">One Last Love Letter</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_07_01">Pictures On The Wall</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_07_02">Scorched Earth</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_08_01">Blue-Winged Serpe</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_08_02">Soulwarden Supplies</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_09_01">Codex I</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_09_02">Codex II</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_09_03">Codex III</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_09_04">Codex IV</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_09_05">Codex V</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_10_04" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Under the House</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_10_05" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">I Got In</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_10_06" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Help</string>
<string key="03_GreatCleave_Title_10_07" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Despair</string>
<string key="Topic_03_GreatCleave">Tales of Great Cleave</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_03_GreatCleave">The wintry advance towards the Shattered Mountain filled with Corrupted forces</string>