<string key="Topic_TalesofExpeditions">Tales of Expeditions</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_TalesofExpeditions">The documents and letters associated with the Expeditions across Aeternum</string>

<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Chapter_01">Garden of Genesis</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_01_01">The Party Advances</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_01_01">Garden of Genesis</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_01_01">On this day the merry band of warriors five seek to explore the overgrown garden first scouted by our legionnaires. What we may find within may be riches or ruin, but in either outcome this slice of Eden must be documented and explored for its proximity to our forward camps. \n\nWe, consisting of Lucius, Hadriana, Marcellus, Domitia, and Cassia of the reserves, fear not for our own lives but for the lives of the innocents that may be affected should this grove contain dangers within. \n\n-Cassia</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_01_02">A Strange Substance</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_01_02">Garden of Genesis</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_01_02">After fighting our way through the Dryad soldiers who protect this place it is clear that something valuable is hidden within. \n\nStranger than this, though, is a substance that Marcellus stepped in while fending off a Dryad's blows. It is a blood orange, viscous material that I quickly gathered a sample of. It seems to infect all natural things in the garden, but none of us were willing to see its effects on humans just yet. \n\nCould this substance repel the Dryads? Can it be contained to only the Dryads, or will it spread to those we try to protect? For now we save the sample for analysis back at camp. \n\n-Cassia</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_01_03">The Party Falters</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_01_03">Garden of Genesis</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_01_03">The sample in Cassia's pocket has overtaken her with a clinging sickness. The Dryads avoid her seemingly on principle now, and go for our weakest party members instead of her strong bulwark. \n\nWith Cassia suffering this way and the injuries Hadriana has sustained we can go no further. We have failed in our mission, and when we are resurrected at the next shrine we shall turn back, never to enter this forsaken place again. \n\n-Lucius</string>

<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Chapter_02">Dynasty Shipyard</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_02_01">Edict 18</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_02_01">An Edict of Her Majesty Zhou Taiying</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_02_01">An Edict from Her Majesty and Grace, Empress Zhou Taiying: \n\nAll resources gathered, whether by sickle or sword, must be brought to the Dynasty Shipyard to be forfeit immediately to the Dynasty. Any person or persons caught withholding supplies shall be punished swiftly and severely.</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_02_02">Edict 32</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_02_02">An Edict of Her Majesty Zhou Taiying</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_02_02">An Edict from Her Majesty and Grace, Empress Zhou Taiying: \n\nThe Corrupted forces of The Tempest are to be respected and allied with. No infighting shall be tolerated, as all hands must come together to create the fleet that will cleanse the world. The Tempest's forces are a gift, and shall be treated as such.</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_02_03">Edict 35</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_02_03">An Edict of Her Majesty Zhou Taiying</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_02_03">An Edict from Her Majesty and Grace, Empress Zhou Taiying: \n\nRegarding the feeding schedule of Oro and Joven, they are to be kept hungry to hone their rage and clear their minds. Anyone caught feeding the Tempest's Tigers are to be fed to the Ebonscale Alligators without trial.</string>

<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Chapter_03">Lazarus Instrumentality</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_03_01">An Unparalleled Opportunity</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_03_01">The Lazarus Instrumentality</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_03_01">Father says it is a great honor to serve the Ancients. They have been benevolent towards our existence ever since we washed upon the shores of this deathless island. \n\nI am ready to undertake the transformation. I know it shall bestow great blessings upon my parents and sister when I undergo my metamorphosis into a Guardian. \n\n-Albinas</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_03_02">A Great Sacrifice</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_03_02">The Lazarus Instrumentality</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_03_02">Three fellow humans join me in this journey today, prepared to offer ourselves as Guardians to the Ancients. Eight Ancients in their ethereal robes guide us through the cave system towards our fate, eyeing us as if we might flee. Is there a reason to flee? This knot in my stomach will not untangle. \n\n-Albinas</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_03_03">Growing Fear</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_03_03">The Lazarus Instrumentality</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_03_03">I have never seen a being so large in all my days. Its one-eyed gaze grips my heart with fear. I look back to the cave system and realize I would not know my way back even if I tried. \n\nThe first among us steps up to receive the blessing, and his hands are shaking just like mine. Are we throwing our lives away for the sake of a species we barely understand? I think of father, mother, and sister. Will I even recognize them once this is done? \n\nI am scared, and the cries coming from the man transforming sound pained. Have I made a terrible mistake? \n\n-Albinas</string>

<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Chapter_04">Starstone Barrows</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_04_01">Nakashima's Frustration</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_04_01">Starstone Barrows</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_04_01">Working with Simon Grey is near impossible at times. The man's ego is bigger than the Shattered Obelisk and he's going to get all the credit when it's been my men and I digging for him. \n\nI swear, if it weren't for Barkimedes I'd be out of here. \n\n-Foreman Nakashima</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_04_02">Ensouled Gems</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_04_02">Starstone Barrows</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_04_02">The mural depicted on the walls calls for intense inspection. \n\nThese gems around the hearts of the people depicted—what could they be? Do they hold the soul, or a part of it? If we could get this mural off the wall and into the daylight I might be able to study it better. I wonder if Nakashima would be able to isolate it. \n\n-Simon Grey</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_04_03">Next Steps</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_04_03">Startsone Barrows</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_04_03">Our next step in solving this mystery will have to be near the Amrine Temple. We will gather our supplies and make our discoveries there, I can feel it in my bones. \n\n-Simon Grey</string>

<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Chapter_05">The Depths</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_05_01">Alligators</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_05_01">Found in The Depths</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_05_01">**There is a drawing of a group of alligators. The smallest one is circled in angry red ink with text you cannot decipher above it.** \n\nBab pab rutukep nâ idok a pixadaxoxo mah mipung. Yâd dekev uwâmik'ot an veyi yi mah axo. P'â gandobde gayuraok tiv nâ mixig mi ba itki yi pixadax? Pin ketir yâd mah veb xabti a wu mah yâd fibdâ ikumo kia , ti ruko robtoki pad ti fibdâok fa royenvong mah 'a ko.</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_05_02">Myrkgard</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_05_02">Found in The Depths</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_05_02">**On the page is a drawing of the Myrkgard Church in exquisite detail signed ‘T'.** \n\nIsabella a wux t'enggâf xa Myrkgard uvendâ. Iknir mipung k'ufâ ngo tiv pad ikitkâ t'epud. Wu a mah runa, a piñab mah 'a kengâ.</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_05_03">The Box</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_05_03">Found in The Depths</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_05_03">**A drawing of a sealed box is ferociously scribbled over with repeating phrases that you do not understand the meaning of.** \n\nMIMA PAD EFITWEK MAH AMBI! ERUWEÑ PIÑAB AXO! MIMA PAD EFITWEK MAH AMBI! ERUWEÑ PIÑAB AXO!</string>

<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Chapter_06" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">Tempest's Heart</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_06_01" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">Brothers Unreliable</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_06_01" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">Found in Tempest's Heart</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_06_01" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">Philip and Cosimo have failed me. They have failed Mother and Father as well in how they squandered our fortune and connections. It is up to me now to save this family.\n\nThere is no one else I can rely upon but myself, and now I know this to be true.\n\n-Captain Isabella</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_06_02" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">The Offering of the Apple</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_06_02" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">Found in Tempest's Heart</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_06_02" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">The allure of power and knowledge has long had its draw. Just as the first humans fell to temptation so too will Isabella De Leon.\n\nI will offer her what she cannot refuse: a chance to restore the De Leon name to glory. She will pay no mind to the cost of this gift, not until it is far too late.</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_06_03" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">The Heretic's Source</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_06_03" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">Found in Tempest's Heart</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_06_03" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">They call me The Heretic, but I am not of a singular nature.\n\nThere have been countless Heretics before me, and there will be countless more after me.\n\nNedenyek seeks its next worthy vessel, one of shattered heart and broken dreams. He is nearby--I can smell it.</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_06_04" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">Father Russo and Isabella</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_06_04" rel_version="Expedition_ShatterMtn_00">Found in Tempest's Heart</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_06_04">My dearest,\n\nI was willing to go down to the depths of hell itself to rescue you, but your mind has been captured long ago. I would have wrestled with the devil himself, put old Lucifer to shame, but what lurks in your mind is stronger than any daemon I have ever encountered in my life in the cloth. I would have given up that life to be your husband, but now I see you have been of one mind and of sole purpose: the restoration of your family name.\n\nMy greatest lament is that I could not save you. My heart lies shattered as the mountain in the sky. I fear the darkness will reach me next, and only hope my last thoughts will be of you, Isabella.\n\nLove, \nRusso</string>

<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Chapter_07" rel_version="Expedition_CutlassKeys_00">Barnacles and Black Powder</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_07_01" rel_version="Expedition_CutlassKeys_00">The Darkheart's Roster</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_07_01" rel_version="Expedition_CutlassKeys_00">Damned Souls of The Darkheart</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_07_01" rel_version="Expedition_CutlassKeys_00">Admiral Blackpowder\nFirst Officer Wells\nSecond Officer Bartram\nThird Officer Gibbs\nGunner Jett\nSergeant Morris\nFire Agent Jones\nNavigator Widdershins\nChompers</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_07_02" rel_version="Expedition_CutlassKeys_00">Admiral's Manifesto</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_07_02" rel_version="Expedition_CutlassKeys_00">An account of The Darkheart's leader</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_07_02" rel_version="Expedition_CutlassKeys_00">We set sail for riches, my lads. Riches beyond any man's imagination lay in this place called Aeternum.\n\nThe Keys are our destination, and don't you go believing the nonsense about it being 'haunted', because we'll bash those ghosties right back into the sea for what we want. We are the crew of The Darkheart! Our name strikes fear into the hearts of all who hear! Will you be stopped by rumors and half-truths? I won't be, and therefore, you won't be, because your worthless hides belong to me!\n\nListen to your Admiral, or end up worse off than when you joined this crew. Listen to your Admiral, and he will lead you to more gold than you can count out.\n\nListen to your Admiral. Or else.</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Title_07_03" rel_version="Expedition_CutlassKeys_00">Widdershin's Stupidity</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Subtitle_07_03" rel_version="Expedition_CutlassKeys_00">A recollection of a failed mutiny</string>
<string key="TalesofExpeditions_Body_07_03" rel_version="Expedition_CutlassKeys_00">Wally Damned Widdershins. I should have known he had a few screws loose rambling on about curses as he did.\n\nNavigator Widdershins abandoned the expedition and tried to bring the hearts and minds of the crew with him with this curse nonsense.\n\nShould I ever see him again, the Cat O' Nine Tails would be too easy a punishment. Now the men talk about the gold turning us into monsters, as if we aren't already monsters in the eyes of so many for what we did to get here.\n\nWhat's a few barnacles on the skin for eternal gold and glory? Keeping the crew in line after this outburst from Widdershins has gotten significantly more difficult. More corporal punishment will have to be used.\n\n-Admiral's Log</string>
