<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_01_01">Is there a more beautiful view than the sunrise on Aeternum? Spent beside my family there is no place I would rather be than sitting on the docks with our feet dangling off over the water. I close my eyes, feel the warmth of the sun upon me, and I pray we stay forever this fortunate.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_01_02">Last night at sunset Bobby says he saw one of those grenadiers wandering the coast and killed it. I highly doubt his story. No undead pirates dare come so close to the settlement and Bobby is known to be a boastful man. He once 'wrestled' an alligator in an attempt to impress me and was promptly chomped in half by the gator. So no, I do not believe we are in any danger of being encroached upon. Tell that to your mother, and set her heart at ease for me.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_01_03">Those settlement people with their houses and workstations think they've conquered the land, but I am not here to conquer. I am here to coexist, to live off the bounty of Aeternum without creating structures more permanent than a watchtower. I see their chimney smoke on cold nights and shiver next to my campfire, but I would never trade my morals for a little warmth. How weak-willed my husband was to move in to the settlement overnight without as much as saying goodbye. I will never end up like him.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_01_04">The lake nearby gives us fresh water and fish, and the wolf population of the island gives us furs and meats. We are truly blessed to be here on Aeternum where nothing truly dies, assuring a steady supply of food without having to wait for repopulation or worry about overhunting. The settlement is a luxury we do not need. Aeternum provides all on its own.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_02_01">Matis and Chekov and I will distract the Captain. You, Anne, and Henry sneak into his quarters and use Anne's lockpicking skills to get into the red cabinet on the left of the room. Grab the Port, pour it into a flask and replace everything you took with seawater. This won't deter him long but it'll give us a few precious moments between him pouring the Port and realizing that some of it has been replaced. Return with the flask and Henry will give the all-clear signal and boom, we're swimming in quality drink. There's no way this plan could go wrong.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_02_02">Stay out of the Captain's Quarters if you value your sorry lives. I know at least one of you scoundrels has been helping themselves to my bottles of Port I keep locked up within, and I will find out who it is. When I do, they're getting the plank! Your days are numbered, thief, for only a fool robs a robber.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_02_03">Bets are placed on numbers two to twelve, those two being the rarest scores. Two six-sided dice are rolled, and their sum is the winning number. Whoever gets closest to the winning number gets the pot, and no two players can bet on the same number. If there is a tie, the pot is split in half favoring the higher number if the pot is uneven.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_02_04">Jackson's got loaded dice, I can tell. There's no way in hell the winning number is always seven. He's not even subtle about it! Those wooden monstrosities need to be tested before our crew loses the whole haul to him. Gonna talk to the Captain Flotsam about it tomorrow morning, and anyone who agrees can come with me.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_02_05">The man we took hostage is proving to be more profitable in our brig than it ever would be to ransom him. His knowledge of magic and runestones is plentiful. If we, with enough supervision, give him the materials to attune new runestones to something valuable, say a kind of drink, then the runestones can guide us towards it. We've seen how it works for gold and silver, just look at our stores! This wizard has more than proved his worth to us, and the only thing we have to worry about is him escaping.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_02_06">Yo-ho, Yo-ho\n\nRunestones, runestones!\n\nThey pulse and quake\n\nThey shudder and shake\n\nLeading us to liquid gold!\n\nYo-ho, yo-ho, now everybody yo-ho!</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_03_01">Today I begin my hunt for Fangsnap. I am loaded with steel arrows and my trusty sword. This beast has terrorized the coast for far too long, and it is up to me as Survivalist of the settlement to put the matter to rest.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_03_02">My body and spirit feel broken. My arm tingles where Fangsnap last closed his fangs around it, tearing flesh from bone that has now healed, but still the ghost of the injury lingers. I make my retreat today back to the settlement to regroup and possibly ask for assistance. But who would be fool enough to go into this cave after all the horrors that have occurred here at the claws and teeth of such a rabid beast? Perhaps an adventurer from the new shipwrecks down south might come along. I can only hope they do.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_04_01">Today we have a new addition to our family, a pair of spotted rabbits I rescued from Windsward where adventurers were killing them nonstop. I will call them Romeo and Juliet after the recent play of fame in the Old World.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_04_02">I don't pick favorites, but if I was to pick a favorite, it would have to be Stanley. He is the crown jewel of my rabbit collection, stolen from up north where the Corrupted hunted him for meat. He is a beautiful snowshoe hare with the softest fur I have ever had the pleasure of feeling. I hold him close to me at night when I am coughing and cannot sleep, and he seems to understand my plight. He stays at my side, and I could not ask for a more loyal companion.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_05_01">The funniest thing happened to me when I was setting up my tent. I could have sworn, out of the corner of my eye, I saw something of about knee-height rustling in the bushes. Figuring it to be a boar, I aimed my musket and fired into the brush, but whatever was there was gone when I went to find my kill. That was strange, but just an hour later, when I had finally set up the campfire, did I feel eyes on me again from the same bush. Was this boar watching me? Or am I going insane?</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_05_02">They came at nighttime, and there were too many of them to fight off. They swarmed McFarland first, all grunts and oinks as they ripped him to shreds. He was resurrected just a few feet to the left in his campsite and when he reappeared those crazed boars killed him again! It took him three more deaths and took me two more just to get out of the campsite boundary. Tomlinson says we should try and reclaim the camp on sunrise, but I say we abandon this venture. I've never seen the yellow eyes of a boar look at me with such malice, such hatred. Something is not right here, and I am not sticking around to find out why.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_06_01">I swear, if I hear one more prayer out of Captain Bubblebeard, I am going to lose my mind. He prays before battle, he prays after battle, hell, he prays during battle! We're the ones carrying this crew to victory every time we have to raid a ship or a supply line! The man's more cowardly than even some of the green young lads we take on, and that's saying something with how Katsuki acts whenever we fire a cannon.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_06_02">May Providence bless the ship\n\nMay Providence bless the crew\n\nBless the bow, the stern, the aft\n\nBless me and bless you\n\nBless each all cannon fodder, bless all the swords and shields\n\nFor we will need every blessing when we are in the field.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_07_01">Here lies a soul taken from us far too soon. A young soul, a brave soul, one who spent their life on Aeternum fighting for the good of others. They deserve more than this shallow grave in a dilapidated cemetery, but this is the best I can do. Rest well, dearest. I will visit you again soon.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_07_02">WARNING: Do not proceed! There is a dangerous individual inside of this pavilion who has lost all sense of conscience and morality. She is no longer the woman she once was, and must be avoided at all costs!</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_08_01">My colleagues, the Master Fishers, are an eclectic group of individuals with not very much in common if you were to line us up and inspect us. But if you were to weigh our hearts, they would all have the same lightness when it came to fishing. Some fish for the food to feed others, some fish for bragging rights, and some like me fish because it's the most thrilling thing on Aeternum.\n\nThe battle one is locked in when reeling in a fish is a hard-fought one on both ends, and coming out of that victorious will never cease to amuse and amaze me. Grand Master Fisher Machera has reigned as our leader long enough. My secret desire is to out-fish him and everyone else, and take the title for myself. Now that would be truly thrilling.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_08_02">I fished up the most curious thing the other day. It was an oar, one from a rowboat that might have been attached to one of the larger ships that crashed here. When I held the splintering wood up to the light I had an idea: why not use this as a weapon? I only killed a few rabbits on Rabbit Island with it before I angered the Harekeeper's wraith, but overall not a bad run for a piece of wood. I think I shall keep this oar, and use it to hit things far away from me.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_08_03">Blue-blooded Barb, oh love of mine, behemoth of the deep. One day you shall be mine, and on that day I will take your corpse to Grand Fisher Machera and show him what I've learned, challenge him to a fish-off. Once I have you, I shall rule the fishing world on Aeternum.</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_09_01">I tell you Ambeline, we're going to strike it rich! \n\nWe've finally hit upon a scheme to make a lot of money for very little effort. It's perfect!\n\nWe farm the lynx, harvest their furs, and sell them up north. They always need more furs up north, and there is a lady who is willing to pay top dollar for 'em! \n\nNo more hunting expeditions ranging up and down the coast, we'll never have to leave our camp. \n\nWe've got the cats, and a good location. Now we just need more meat.\n\nWith any luck, we'll be home sooner than expected, and with more wealth than we'll know what to do with.\n\n\nLots of love, \n\n~Your Dearest Geoff</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_09_02">My dearest Ambeline, you were right, it was too good to be true. \n\nJust when we thought things were going so well, Caryn showed up. \n\nWho is Caryn? Good question. We soon found out. \n\nSome crazy lady who believes animals shouldn't be hunted! Who believes that? \n\nSaid we better stop what we were doing and move along, or there'd be real problems. \n\nI told her it was too late. We weren't leaving, we had a good thing going here! \n\nThat's when told us what she did to Reynard. Pushing him into the lynx den. She wasn't messing around. \n\n\nHope to get out of this mess,\n\n~Your Dearest Geoff</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_09_03">Hah! Caryn has no idea the scope of what we did. \n\nSure, she took out Benet, and Piers. But she still doesn't know about the wolves. \n\nOh, she suspects something, but she's so short sighted, not like us. \n\n We weren't only here for lynx fur. We've been flooding the local wolf den with alchemical concoctions to make them more violent. \n\nThey were already getting that way from having to compete with the lynx for food, but now they are a real menace. \n\nThey are so dangerous, people pay us to kill them. So we get paid twice, once for their deaths, and then again with their furs. \n\nWait, I hear something outside. Is it the snarl of a wolf? Did Caryn lure one here? \n\nForgive me, my love, but I have to check.\n\n\n I hope this letter makes it to you someday if I do not return. \n\n~Your Dearest Geoff</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Body_09_04">If you have found this note, you have my thanks. What you have done was not pretty, indeed, it should not have happened at all. \n\nBut there are some people in the world who only know how to take, and never to give. \n\nIt was a hard mercy you gave those wolves, a mercy I couldn't give them myself. \n\nThe balance of Restless Shore has been restored. Now I am off to see justice done in the jungles to the northwest. \n\nThink of me, someday, when the alligators of Reekwater run free. \n\n\n~Caryn Berzs</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Chapter_01">Life Outside the Settlement</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Chapter_02">Pirate's Life</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Chapter_03">Fangsnap's Reign</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Chapter_04">Rabbit Reads</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Chapter_05">Boar Takeover</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Chapter_06">Eternal Conflict</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Chapter_07">Eternal Resting Place</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Chapter_08">O'Connor's Triumphs</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Chapter_09">The Fur Trade</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Chapter_10">Lady Fathom</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_01_01">Found in Eastshore Pier</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_01_02">Found in Eastshore Pier</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_01_03">Found in Decayed Campsite</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_01_04">Found in Decayed Campsite</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_02_01">Found in Neptune's Fury</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_02_02">Found in Neptune's Fury</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_02_03">Found in West Lookout Camp</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_02_04">Found in East Lookout Camp</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_02_05">Found in Fort Damnation</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_02_06">Found in Fort Damnation</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_03_01">Found in Fangsnap's Cave</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_03_02">Found in Fangsnap's Cave</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_04_01">Found on Rabbit Island</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_04_02">Found on Rabbit Island</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_05_01">Found in Boarsholm</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_05_02">Found in Boarsholm</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_06_01">Found in Minnow's Revenge</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_06_02">Found in Minnow's Revenge</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_07_01">Found in Solitude Cemetery</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_07_02">Found in Solitude Cemetery</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_08_01">Out-Fishing Them All</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_08_02">Lost Debris</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_08_03">Behemoth Sighted</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_09_01">A New Venture</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_09_02">Unexpected Visitor</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_09_03">Sabotage</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Subtitle_09_04">Rule of Tooth and Claw</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_01_01">Sunrise on Aeternum</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_01_02">Sunset Shoals</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_01_03">Coexisting</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_01_04">Aeternum Provides</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_02_01">The Great Port Heist</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_02_02">Captain's Orders</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_02_03">Rules</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_02_04">Loaded Dice</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_02_05">Captive Proves His Worth</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_02_06">Endless Drink</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_03_01">Day One</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_03_02">Day Four</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_04_01">The Family</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_04_02">Stanley</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_05_01">Campsite Set-up</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_05_02">Too Many Of Them</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_06_01">Bubblebeard's Prayers</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_06_02">A Prayer for Peace</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_07_01">Eulogy</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_07_02">Warning</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_08_01">Colleagues</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_08_02">Oar You Ready?</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_08_03">Blue-blooded Barb</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_09_01">Geoff's First Letter</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_09_02">Geoff's Second Letter</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_09_03">Geoff's Third Letter</string>
<string key="15_RestlessShore_Title_09_04">Caryn's Goodbye Letter</string>
<string key="Topic_15_RestlessShore">Tales of Restless Shore</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_15_RestlessShore">A chain of islands and archipelagos besieged by undead pirates and ghosts</string>