<string key="Topic_07_ShatteredMountain">Tales of Shattered Mountain</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_07_ShatteredMountain">The crown of Aeternum, a massive splintered mountain filled with Corruption</string>

<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Chapter_01">Plans of the Corrupted</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_01_01">Broken Branches</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_01_01">Found in Odium</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_01_01">**A page written in the Corrupted language, with sketches of Dryad bodies. Circles have been drawn around their hearts, heads, and hands.** \n\nUbahâh Mabayibok ñâv ba kepo mixanfep kengâmbi, fa paitkâ ubatânfâp yi uwâ'abto 'ag ambi. 'Aktâ, ngek mambetu mikor yâk'upambi ngo pa xa miwod mi a. Ngo imi yâk'upambi kuguok ebikning vebambi.\n</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_01_02">Pruning a Twisted Vine</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_01_02">Found in Vehemence</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_01_02">**Covered in the illegible, but unmistakable, language of the Corrupted, the images sketched here show the Corruption pillars being tended to, almost akin to gardening, with parts being trimmed, pruned, and harvested.** \n\n'Anggur ñirok atwakambi. Ñirok abdâxab ambi. Yi if 'ag ubaban deñâna uwâgap'a 'ufoxo axo. Fif 'ag 'ung p'âyi kâka, xak'ufâ af mi ba.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_01_03">Condensing Corruption</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_01_03">Found in Iratus</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_01_03">**The text of the Corrupted fills most of the page, save for an image drawn in the center: a crystal or gemstone of some kind, sparkling on a Corrupted altar.** \n\nUbuwâveti guf xa p'âta pad xañir wobi pinviñ dâ Aeternum deñ pa pad dewif migana p'ânduxo mi a. Fiv kâme ekâi pad tid uwâyâr ru panuxo xanfep kuñ midewif ambi, veg pagmax kâx 'ag ambi.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_01_04">Duality of the Word</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_01_04">Found in Pullus</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_01_04">I have remained here, hidden, writing all I can while I am still able to do so. A sound fills my mind at times, and images as well... they seem familiar, but I cannot understand them. I fear this Corruption is overtaking me. Perhaps, in my writings, I will find a way to stop it. Perhaps I will find a way to save myself from ubapampu he dekâp'ux mipung pad Euwâveti miñ vob romena mad pad mabayib mingoñ. Eâbtakendu ven a Eâbtativ, mah ven kidebu a.… with the powers they have at their disposal. I am no closer to discovering their long-term goals, but in the short term, it seems as though Isabella has returned from her travels around the island, bringing a number of new converts with her. She seems to be important to the plans underway here. Some of those she has brought may be only to increase their numbers, but others seem specially selected. Experienced smiths, alchemists, men and women of science... it may be that there are plans for some kind of profane construction.\n\nMah, 'ung, kepo kia. Mah uako 'ung ki xa degi t'onag. De axo depwang hemakte yi tânfâp a. Guf mibtâxo, pap'âyi ru Magmebeg. \n\n... I am unsure how much time has passed, how long I have held myself in this place. My stores are nearly depleted, and the time for escape has long since passed. My only solace is that somehow, whoever finds this may glean some new information from it. I have seen all manner of oddities brought through here in the recent days: hundreds of trees brought from all around this land, carts of ore placed around the base of the Thorn with the Cultists chanting incessantly, boxes and bins and bags stuffed full of unknowable items. Something is happening. Something dreadful. Something... I am powerless to stop. \n\nA axo ketir. Guf mibtâ. A axo ketir. Guf mibtâ. A axo ketir. Guf mibtâ.\n</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_01_05">A Sinister Intent</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_01_05">Found in Lapsus</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_01_05">**A dirty and splattered page, covered with the language of the Corrupted. A drawing of a large blade divides the page, wicked and powerful. While not understanding the words, the writing seems emphatic, eager, almost desperate somehow.** \n\nFiv bingu guf hemaktexo axo. Ngoñ uwâtânfâp kuk anggidambi mab bingu bip a. Miwod pad pab Magmebeg mab mideh pad pab Magmebeg igambi ambi. Kuñ miwod ig, k'okti, he 'abto.</string>

<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Chapter_02">Man's Worst Enemy</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_02_01">Day 1</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_02_01">Corrupted Hounds</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_02_01">These aren't my mother's poodles.\n\nIn the Great Cleave leading to that ominous city of corruption prowl dogs of unnatural color and ferocity. I have taken to calling them Corrupted Hounds for the red veins of Corruption visible and accompanying abhorrent behavior. These aberrations can unhinge their jaws of gnashing teeth wide enough to swallow a turkey whole.\n\nStill, they are kind of cute from a certain angle, aren't they? Mum back home raised bigger dogs--how hard could it be to domesticate one of these? A puppy of one would look just darling in a bow. A gift for a beloved, perhaps?</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_02_02">Day 2</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_02_02">Whelping Grounds</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_02_02">I have not yet been able to locate a pup no matter how deep into this crevasse of corruption I delve. All are full-grown, and fully trained to follow their shambling Masters. Do these Hounds not need to whelp? Do they just regenerate fully-grown as everything else on this strange continent? Further research required.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_02_03">Day 3</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_02_03">Molly</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_02_03">After a grueling battle I managed to slay a red-eyed houndsman in attempts to capture an adult specimen of the beast.\n\nMy arms are covered in at least two layers of bandages from wrestling the dog into a makeshift trap and my blood surely left a trail from the snowy pass, but my efforts are not in vain. I sit writing this in incredible pain and incredible pride, gazing upon my new captive before turning in for the night to rest. She's restless, obviously unused to being confined by walls and too strong to remain in the trap for long. I think I shall call her ‘Molly'.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_02_04">Day 4</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_02_04">The Hand That Feeds</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_02_04">Molly is still ruthlessly vicious around me.\n\nI present her with raw meat at feeding time and this seems to quell some of her rage, but not her distrust. She drags the scraps from the wooden bowl I made her in favor of eating in the corner of the wall enclosure. From this vantage point she can keep her eyes on me at all times--always red, always wary.\n\nFood motivation can only take us so far, and ultimately winds up being more dangerous than it is worth to feed her from my own hand.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_02_05">Day 5</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_02_05">Devildog</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_02_05">Her behavior still proves too aggressive to let out of the walled-in enclosure. I write now with my left hand as my right has been requisitioned by dearest Molly as a chew toy.\n\nResearch into leather leads required—if I could ever get close enough to her neck to sling one around. The dog looks at me with such disdain and disgust, as if I were the one with red fissures and eyes glowing like The Devil.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_02_06">Day 6</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_02_06">Man's Best Friend?</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_02_06">What joy! I woke this morning to find Molly sans her characteristic growling and snapping. She took food more gently from the bowl, obviously cowed by my superior animal handling skills. There is a strange intelligence in her eyes, as if she is beginning to understand the situation.\n\nCould this be how the first man felt taming a wolf?</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_02_07">Day 7</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_02_07">The Great Escape</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_02_07">That damnable dog, she was figuring things out--but not in my favor!\n\nI have never seen such intelligence in a canine, to feign docility long enough to convince even an experienced handler like me. Molly did not as much as whimper when I put the leather lead on through the fence. I spoke sweetly to her, told her it was time for a walk, hoping a lack of captivity would bring out her personality. It turns out her personality is evil, and the second she realized she was no longer contained, my dear Molly mauled me, draining me to my last before I woke up in bed again, alone. She ran back North to her true master, I can only imagine.\n\nThere are better ways to make profit on this lush continent than lying with the dogs. On a related note, I now certainly have fleas. Corrupted Fleas, at that. A Corrupted Flea Circus, yes, now that could work...</string>

<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Chapter_03">Bernard's Booklet</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_03_01">Lava Barb</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_03_01">The Underwater Panther</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_03_01">Armed with horns and teeth sharper than the average straight sword, the Lava Barb makes a life for itself here in Shattered Mountain. It is not a glamorous life by any means, swimming around in Corrupted waters, but it is a life nonetheless.\n\nShould you go swimming and feel something slice into your ankle, it is already too late.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_03_02">Living Amongst Corruption</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_03_02">Daily Survival</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_03_02">The other Master Fishers call me 'paranoid' and 'prone to conspiracy' but they're not the ones who chose to live life next to a giant half-floating mountain.\n\nThey have no idea what it's like fishing in my waters, getting smaller and weaker catches depending on how Corrupted the waters are. I know beyond a shadow of a doubt that it is not my fishing skill or bait that attracts these small fish, but the water itself working against me! I continue to eke out surviving here on my meager fish, meeting with the Greyjacks every so often to discuss how we can cleanse the waters. Even they think I'm overreacting. Life near the crown of Aeternum is an endless slog, made worse by the creeping red tide.</string>

<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Chapter_04" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Winter's Kiss</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_04_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Entry 1</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_04_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Seventh Day of Snow</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_04_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">On the seventh day of snow, there came a dainty tapping on me door. I sat breathing, for I feared it were that pig-faced Lieutenant Hadar come to drag me back to the Hell I ran from.\n\nBut if it weren’t a lady with raven dark hair that fell down to a tiny waist. Skin white as the snow. Only slippers on her feet, and robed in fine white linen. But I didn’t touch her, not on this day, I swear it on cold iron.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_04_02" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Entry 2</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_04_02" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Twelfth day of snow</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_04_02" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Twelve days, and naught but two words. “You key.”A key to what? But her lips smiled faint like I should know. She must be some royal runaway Princess! The way she looks at me like I’m special. \n\nShe don’t like fire. Stares at it like it were a smoking gateway into Hell. But water. She drinks it never-ending, like a dirty cup of melted snow got the taste of roast horse.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_04_03" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Entry 3</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_04_03" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">I been dreaming</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_04_03" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">I been dreaming. She lays on me like a cool blanket. But my breathing, it comes harder and harder ‘til I can’t move or cry for mercy. When I wake up, she’s just laying in the corner. These dreams got me tired.\n\nI’m taking the cart to town tomorrow. She ain’t eating nothing I put afore her. But she don’t complain. That’s how you tell a royal apart. They don’t bang knives when they hungry, but they wait all patient for the pig knuckles to come out.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_04_04" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Entry 4</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_04_04" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A boy</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_04_04" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Who’s that boy? I don't remember no boy. I only remember coming back from town, the lady still in me cabin and looking better somehow, cheeks pink like bloody meat.\n\nI was screaming then, staring at the boy’s eyes. Empty holes, cut up jagged like with a knife. I reached out to cover those eyes but she grabbed me. Cold and strong, like she were steel inside. I kicked the boy into a wolfskin rug. Rolled him into the storm and that was that.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_04_05" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Entry 5</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_04_05" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Married</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_04_05" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">We got married! We crowed our vows to the wind, didn’t we? Well I did, and you said too without a word wasted between those pale lips. And then I kissed your mouth so cold, but I had plenty of fire in me to warm you. Here on this mount, looking over blue seas of ice. I stripped off me furs and ran naked, and the snow didn’t bother me even.\n\nLast night, you called me to the bed. Called me like whispers of the dead. And I answered your call, many a time I did.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_04_06" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Entry 6</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_04_06" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Confession</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_04_06" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">How did I forget? She chose the boy like a nice lamb at market, but it were me that brought him back. My promise of coin weren’t needed, the way his eyes were all on top of her. \n\nSo I carved the bastard’s eyes while he was kicking, screaming. While she watched, waiting.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_04_07" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Entry 7</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_04_07" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Monster</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_04_07" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">She left the door open, like she wanted me to see. It was the moon’s third hour, and she hunched over the dug up grave. Mouth full of icicle teeth slicked dark with blood. Gnawing on his fingers. \n\nAnd then I remembered. What happened after I killed him.\n\nIt was when he stopped kicking. A light come up from below, into his throat. She shoved me aside, and kissed his mouth. Drank deep from his soul. And I felt only a great rage. But now I hear her laugh like the cracking of finger bones, and there’s nothing in me but fear.</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Title_04_08" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Entry 8</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Subtitle_04_08" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Cracking of winter</string>
<string key="07_ShatteredMountain_Body_04_08" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">She found me again. She lets me go, hunts me down, eats. Eats another part of me, with that laughter on her lips. Be with her forever, didn’t I wish it? \n\nI’ll bury this under cold iron. If ye read it be warned. Don’t let her into your house. Don’t give her no water. If ye see her, run while ye have feet to do it. I hear it. Crawling under the branches. And just now it come upon me like a terrible wave. I’m the pig knuckles she been waiting for.</string>