<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_01_01" speaker="Alchemist Ignatius" name="AlchemistIgnatius" gender="Male" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">For the previous fortnight, the smell of Hydra's Breath reeked from the ashes of the dead. Smoke still rose from their oil soaked remains as nightfall approached. \n\nAdmiring my creation's handiwork, I entertained the protests of a few New Corsican prisoners. These plebs spoke of "ethical warfare” and purported that the Hydra's Breath I was preparing and rationing into casks was cruel and unethical both in theory and in practice. They claimed what I was creating was lacking any virtue that the gods find admirable. \n\nI laughed heartily at their non-sensical bleating and reminded these Socratic imbeciles that there were only two truths in regards to the "ethics of war." First, those with power who fail to use it are fools. Second, those who fall prey to such power are deserving victims, whose complaints are whispered from charred, dying lips.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_01_02" speaker="Alchemist Ignatius" name="AlchemistIgnatius" gender="Male" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">When dawn broke the next day, the prisoners were at it again, seeking to dissuade me in my purpose. The casks of Hydra's Breath would soon be dispatched to set fire to their kinsman in New Corsica. "All is just and virtuous for the glory of Legatus Crassus and the 19th Legion," I told them. \n\nThe casks of my handiwork sat stacked in rows, only a few feet from their holding pit. The one called Rahat appealed to my compassion and begged me to forsake my task. She pleaded with me to seek the wisdom of the gods lest my soul be torn from my body and banished to the Underworld. \n\nAnother prisoner called me a cur and warned that the retribution of the gods would be swift and just. I laughed at the lot of them!\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_01_03" speaker="Alchemist Ignatius" name="AlchemistIgnatius" gender="Male" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Damn these New Corsican prisoners! Will their tongues never cease wagging? \n\nThe Legionnaires are having a go at them with their slings. Two score times I watched stone meet bone. I smiled as the light faded from Rahat's eyes, only to have her crawl her way back from the dead. It is not I but rather the gift of this land that is cruel. She began to speak again of my cowardice and barbarism. \n\nUpon hearing her insults, I loomed over the pit like the shadow of Hades. I rolled a cask of my "immoral" concoction over the edge, setting it ablaze with my torch. \n\nThe proceeding moments of tortured screams and crackling flesh were a small price to pay for a peaceful night’s sleep.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_02_01" speaker="Gnaeus Pompey" name="Pompey" gender="Male" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Antony, \n\nI find your offer of two hundred and fifty gold Aureus for the purchase of Vespasian, Terror of Troy, on the verge of insult. \n\nI have seen him slay two lions with nothing but a gladius. This warrior fears nothing on the sands of the Arena. He is a death bringer, and with every kill he will bring the cheers of the masses and coin to your pocket. \n\nWhile fearless and undefeated in the Arena, he knows his place and will never long for freedom. He is as simple as he is ruthless. \n\nAs such, I demand no less than one thousand gold Aureus for him. At that price, you may send him to his death in the Arena against whatever odds you deem amusing. \n\nHis death will fuel the Glory of Rome and the entertainment of the people. Freedom was never Fate's design for such a man. \n\nPompeius Magnus\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_02_02" speaker="Mark Antony" name="MarkAntony" gender="Male" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Vespasian,\n\nYou are a slave no more. Face the new dawn with your freedom and your status as a centurion in the 19th Legion. May your gladius drink the blood of my enemies.\n\nMark Antony</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_03_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">I have tried applying refined sulfur from the pools to the following materials: \n\nMercury: produces tremendous heat and a small quantity of black cinnabar \nIron: consumes iron without any application of heat \nGold: no effect \nPlatinum: no effect \nLiquid azoth: need a safer way to attempt this. My eyebrows still haven’t grown back.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_03_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">When I was a little girl, my father once showed me a bit of magic. Or so it seemed to my childish eyes. Some dark sands and a single spark came together to produce a fountain of light, more brilliant than all the stars in the sky. \n\nI asked him if it was magic. He answered that it was alchemy, and that anyone with wisdom could use it. \n\nMy mind always wanders back to that moment. What does it mean for alchemy when it exists side-by-side with magic? When each works upon the other in turn?</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_03_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">I hesitate to even write the words, but there’s no denying it: our most revered sages and philosophers were wrong about the alchemical arts. \n\nNothing on this island has behaved as it should. Increasingly, I’ve come to believe that azoth itself is the goal that so many sought; the very essence of power, transmutation, refinement, and immortality.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_03_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Aeternum itself bears witness—humanity’s use of azoth has not led to enlightenment or perfection. Azoth illuminates a false path, and if I hope to achieve anything more than my own destruction, I must find another path to walk. \n\nContrary to the claims of charlatans, the pursuit of alchemy should not be for power, riches, or glory. The truest form of alchemy aims at transmuting the soul, refining ourselves to be better than this crude matter from which we are born. \n\nLofty and unattainable, even with eternal life. But it is not the end result of alchemy that ennobles us; it is the quest itself.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_04_01" speaker="Prefect Drusilla" name="PrefectDrusilla" gender="Female" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Legatus Crassus, \n\nThere has been unrest on the outer perimeter. Covert attacks against our encampment there have scattered our forces. At first, I believed it to be that New Corsican soldier, Kraus, who has shadowed our deployments in this region. But these attacks are too bold for that coward.\n\nI fear that your absence have caused the fangs of our wolves to grow dull. They hunger for blood and need the awe of your presence to stoke their ardor, much the way I require your touch to kindle my desire. \n\nI swear upon the River Styx, I shall learn the identity of this spectral attacker! I have regrouped with my tribunes at the main Legion encampment and await your orders. \n\nThe fierce Magnus is ever at my side. If this specter shows its head, Magnus will lop it off and I'll send it to you as proof of my undying devotion. \n\nDrusilla</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_05_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">It’ll be trouble if Pontifex Charmion finds us poking among the ruins of her gods. But the Ancients are either gone or dead, and we’ve nothing to fear from a bunch of unmoving statues and dusty bones. \n\nTitus swears he saw a skeleton turn its head. I said he’d taken too many knocks on his. I ran a few dusty skulls through with my spear, just in case. None of them so much as sneezed. \n\nWe’ll be fine. Just have to find any treasure and run. Then we’ll be rich.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_05_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">That dimwit Titus turned up dead this morning. Looks like he slipped off some loose stones on the bridge above. I told him not to cross to the other side until we put up some scaffolding. \n\nNow the others are squabbling over whether they should split his share of the treasure, or wait and see if he comes back to life. My head hurts. \n\nAnd something else bothers me. We found Titus with his head twisted right around, staring up at us with him flat on his stomach. A fall wouldn’t do that… right?</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_05_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">I’m the only one left. \n\nThey woke up during my watch. It sounded like a hundred statues and corpses marching up the stairs, cold weapons glinting in their hands. I screamed to wake the others…and then I jumped. \n\nI’m pretty sure I broke an ankle. And then I heard screaming coming from the top of the Wall, felt warm drops of blood showering down around me. \n\nI stopped looking after that. I don’t think the guardians have started chasing me yet. Merciful Mercury, dull my pain and get me out of this place!</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_06_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Our small, fragile souls are not meant to exist forever. I struggle to impress this upon young Miresis. He thinks that the gods must strengthen our souls to help us bear our eternal lives. He says anything less would be cruel. \n\nWhere did he get such a strange notion? The gods enforce order and hold chaos at bay. Who claimed they had to show mercy? \n\n-Pshereamun</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_06_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Being Lost is no curse. It is the natural end of our existence. \n\nWe accumulate so many dark deeds over the centuries. Eventually, even the most virtuous succumb to evil. When we stand before Anubis, our hearts weigh heavy. \n\nThen Ammit devours our souls, but our bodies return as hollow shells. Perhaps she has developed a taste for those trapped here. Perhaps our souls, weighed down by centuries of life and suffering, are her preferred sustenance. \n\n-Pshereamun</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_07_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">My mentor sent me out marching out here with a waterskin, a strange shape on a scrap of paper, and an admonition not to return until I opened the way. Open the way? There’s nothing here but crumbling ruins and dust!\n\nI suppose I did learn one thing. I should be more specific when I ask for advanced lessons.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_07_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">My water has run dry. The sun beats down overhead.   \n\nThe only respite to be found is in the shadow of these ruined gateways. From here, I can see the rooftops of New Corsica. Maybe I should just return to town, before my strength gives out.   \n\nNo, no, I won’t give my mentor the satisfaction of another self-righteous lecture. There must be something about this scribbled shape, like a fishhook. Open the way. \n\nOpen the way…</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_07_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">It’s so obvious. A child could’ve reasoned their way past this, but I nearly missed it.   \n\nThe meaning is not in the glyph itself, nor the word attributed to it. The meaning is in the experience. By undertaking my journey to this place, I had already begun opening the way. I was just too exasperated and stubborn to see it.\n\nNow the gates reveal their secrets to me, and I can finally return to my mentor. &lt;i&gt;After&lt;/i&gt; I cleanse myself of all this wretched dust.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_08_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">After arriving on Aeternum, the 19th Legion shows clear evidence of modifying the organization of its centuries over time. Initial attempts at reorganization were a direct response to the peculiar phenomena of resurrection. \n\nIf the Legion here evolved as a response to changing material conditions, it is only logical to conclude that the legions of the Roman Empire did the same, though perhaps not in as dramatic of a fashion. \n\n(If I ever get off this wretched island to publish my findings, my theories will be vindicated. I can’t wait to see the looks on those Florentine imbeciles’ faces!)</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_08_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The locals believe the most curious things about the Legion. First, that they are uniquely cursed beyond resurrection from the dead. Second, that this curse represents the judgment of Egypt’s gods. And third, that the curse originates in a universally evil phenomenon called “Corruption.” \n\nEvery time I’ve tried to hire a guide to show me around, they start spouting nonsense about this “Corruption.” I suppose I’ll just have to make the climb to the castrum myself.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_08_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">God’s blood, they HURT. Field studies take on a whole new meaning in this terrible place. \n\nMother was right. I never should have left Milan.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_09_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Roman washed ashore last week, during a terrible storm. Our scouts found him carrying coins stamped in the image of an Emperor Trajan.\n\nThen the usurper Octavian must be long dead. Has it been so many years? The days slip into decades, like droplets of water vanishing into the sea. Charmion tries to soothe my mind, but tonight, the home that we left behind dominates my thoughts.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_09_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">It cannot be.\n\nThe man who we pulled from the sea awoke, and now tells terrible tales. He says the usurper won, and tried to destroy even the memory of noble Antony. He says our brothers of the 19th Legion disappeared into the forests of Germania, never to return.\n\nHe says that in Rome, the 19th Legion has never been remade. It died a final death, its spirit scattered and broken in utter defeat.\n\nIt cannot be.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_10_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Monsieur Heron only speaks of one other collaborator in his writings, and I’m beginning to see why. Nobody I’ve spoken to in New Corsica had a whit of academic integrity! \n\nI asked some other travelers to guide me to the aqueduct, and they asked about a share of the treasure. When I said knowledge was its own reward, they laughed me out of the inn! I suppose I’ll have to make my own way up to the aqueduct. I do hope the merchant sold me sound equipment…</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_10_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">I can’t do it again. I just can’t. I know I must not look down, but my eyes betray me. Then my heart seizes, and I remember the very first tumble I took down the cliff. \n\nEven writing about it leaves me in a cold sweat. How am I meant to advance the noble cause of human knowledge when I’m such a craven? \n\nPerhaps I should write to Monsieur Heron. Then again, he may not give a coward like me the time of day.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_11_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A pilgrimage is a bad time to entertain blasphemous thoughts, but here I am anyway. \n\nOsiris was unique among the gods for dying and rising again from the grave. We revered him for it, and Isis for her role in his resurrection. \n\nWhich begs the question: if we also die and resurrect here, in the land of the gods, what does that make us? More than human? Less than gods?</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_11_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Of the nine of us who set out on this pilgrimage, seven remain. One, we lost to a deep, yawning chasm. We waited three days, but he never returned. Another pair quarreled endlessly, until one drew a sword on the other. \n\nKollauthis says this is normal, that the pressures of a long and arduous pilgrimage test the soul and bring out one’s true character. I say it’s the heat and wind, not to mention the crumbling ruins. You’d think the gods could take better care of their own temples.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_11_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The gods found me unworthy. \n\nI know because their guardians repel me at every step. But above all else, I feel it in my soul. Any desire I had to complete my pilgrimage is gone, dulled by pain and fear and the exhaustion of constant peril. \n\nI don’t care how much shame I endure. I’m going home, and may the gods find their champion elsewhere.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_12_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">It stalks us by both night and day.\nAlways the hunter, never the prey.\nYou dare not sleep, nor look away.\nPoison stings, lead to decay. \nShriveled skin, so cold and grey.\nWhen will it strike? You never can say.\n\nBone white fortress, blood red sand,\nWith corpses piled as high a man.\nIf you wish to defeat it, you best have a plan.\nSword and shield had best be in hand. \nKilling brave heroes, dead by the score, \nRoar, roar, comes the Manticore.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="200" xPadding="250" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_1.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="200" xPadding="250" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_2.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_3.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_4.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_05" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_5.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_06" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_6.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_07" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_7.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_08" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_8.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_09" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_9.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_10" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_10.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_11" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_11.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_12" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_12.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_13" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_13.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_14" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_14.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_15" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_15.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_16" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_16.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_17" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_17.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_18" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_18.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_19" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_19.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_20" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_20.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_21" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_21.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_22" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_22.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_23" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_23.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_24" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_24.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_25" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_25.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_13_26" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.8" height="180" yOffset="-200" xPadding="250"  src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_26.png"&gt;&lt;/img&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_14_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">My dearest Andrea,\n\nIt is with a heavy heart that I pen these final words. I had hoped to never have the need for such a confession. But my demons proved far stronger than either of us could've imagined.\n\nThe others reluctantly participated in this scheme. I was the one who led them down this dishonorable path and swore them to secrecy. Your anger and blame belong with me alone.\n\nBut here is the truth: We who had been entrusted with the safety of these evacuating citizens have been robbing them of their goods to enrich ourselves.\n\nOur actions will bring disgrace to the Praetorians and to our families. But worst of all, they will hurt you, dear Andrea. And for that, I will be eternally sorry.\n\nI do not ask pardon for myself but rather for my comrades only. Their mistake was placing their trust in a scoundrel such as myself. And in the end, it cost them their lives.\n\nAs for me, my fate is exactly as I deserve. I shall endeavor to take as many of these Corrupted legionaries with me as I can. A small atonement for my many sins perhaps. \nMy only wish is that the pain I have caused you fades as quickly as my memory.\n\nYours devotedly,\n\nEmiliano Malatesta\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_15_01" speaker="Pontifex Charmion" name="PontifexCharmion" gender="Female" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;i&gt;Arrival Year 73, second month of Shemsu, day 4:&lt;/i&gt;\nPraise Atum! I have at last deciphered the glyphs from the sacred Temple of Akhet! The Book of Gates has given me the answers. \n\nThis land is not Aaru, sacred home of Osiris, but rather the netherworld Duat. The Ennead that rests inside the Temple houses the 12th Gate, beyond which lies the true Field of Reeds. \n\nThe inhabitants of this island call the gods "Ancients" but their true names are known to us. Opening the 12th Gate would bring forth the Purifying Light of the Blessed Nine to all who dwell here.\n\n\n&lt;i&gt;Arrival Year 73, fourth month of Shemsu, day 2:&lt;/i&gt;\nI must convince my beloved Lucius of the truth. He mistakenly believes the Temple has nothing to do with our gods. He fears the Ennead poses a grave danger to the people and must be sealed away. \n\nI must be patient with the noble man who guided us through many hardships to our destination, who built our new home and kept us safe from the spirits and demons that plague this land.\n\nHe may have lost his faith, but my love for him rivals my devotion to the gods. May Osiris forgive me! \n\n\n&lt;i&gt;Arrival Year 73, second month of Akhet, day 5:&lt;/i&gt;\nI’ve received word that Lucius is thinking of marching the 19th Legion to Akhet. They say he seeks to expel us from the Temple, preventing us from fulfilling our sacred destiny. \n\nI must convince him to abandon this plan and to join us instead in welcoming the gods. I pray the gods may open his eyes. \n\nOnly together we can we accomplish this!</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_15_02" speaker="Pontifex Charmion" name="PontifexCharmion" gender="Female" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;i&gt;Arrival Year 73, third month of Akhet, day 1:&lt;/i&gt;\nThese tablets, which I have named the Great Ennead Codex, have provided the answer to opening the 12th Gate.\n\nThey speak of a Prime Key gifted by the gods to the faithful who built Akhet. They tell of a terrible cataclysm that broke the key and scattered the pieces. They mention a war amongst the gods and a terrible scarlet plague.\n\nCould this refer to Seth's betrayal of Osiris?\n\n\n\n\n&lt;i&gt;Arrival Year 73, fourth month of Akhet, day 9:&lt;/i&gt;\nI believe that the wonders of Aaru have waited for millennia for us, the chosen people of New Corsica, to claim them. Wonders that will enlighten us and set us on the true path to wisdom and prosperity.\n\nI must find the pieces of the Prime Key. The locations must be contained in the Codex. Is there a way to assemble it anew? I must decipher more of these glyphs!</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_15_03" speaker="Pontifex Charmion" name="PontifexCharmion" gender="Female" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;i&gt;Arrival Year 73, fourth month of Akhet, day 16:&lt;/i&gt;\nThrough the blessing of Isis, I discovered the location of the Ancient Forge! Only there can the Prime Key be remade.\n\nBut a monstrous guardian known as the Lore Keeper protects it. No one but Lucius and the 19th could contend with such a foe.\n\nI will send word and try to divert them here. I pray Lucius will listen to me!\n\n\n\n\n&lt;i&gt;Arrival Year 73, fourth month of Akhet, day 19:&lt;/i&gt;\nAtum preserve us! The 19th has reached Akhet and begun to force their way into the Ennead!\n\nLucius ignored my warnings and now he will offend the gods and invoke their wrath! He accuses me of being blinded by my faith!\n\nSuch words are a dagger in my heart!  \n\n\n\n\n&lt;i&gt;Arrival Year 73, fourth month of Akhet, day 21:&lt;/i&gt;\nI am left with no choice! I will go to the Ennead at once and attempt to open the 12th Gate without the Prime Key. \n\nI pray the gods heed my desperate plea! I pray the people of New Corsica and especially my beloved Lucius can forgive my reckless act! \n\nMay the gods have mercy on us all!</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_16_01" speaker="General Crassus" name="GeneralCrassus" gender="Male" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Prefect Drusilla, \n\nThe First Cohort continues its assault on the cursed temple. We have broken through the first wave of guardians. Although we fight like lions, the defenses of this temple are like nightmares from Tartarus. Curse the Ancients and their devices! \n\nWithin a fortnight, all of the secrets contained in the Ennead will be mine. With this power, we will bring the glory of Rome to all of Aeternum. Neither Charmion's threats nor the efforts of these traitorous New Corsicans will stop me. \n\nWhile I secure the temple's secrets, you will prepare the remainder of the 19th Legion's forces to embrace their destiny. Stand them at the ready and be prepared to lay siege to the rest of this island. We will lash out with the power of these supposed gods and drive the spear of a new Roman Republic into the heart of Aeternum. \n\nSteel yourself, gather your Tribunes, and put them to task. The birth of a new world awaits us.\n\nLegatus Legionis Lucius Decimus Crassus\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_17_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.4" height="180" xPadding="250" yOffset="100" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_13.png"/&gt;\n&lt;img vAlign="center" lPadding="177" scale="0.4" height="180" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_2.png" /&gt;&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.4" height="180" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_10.png" /&gt;&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.4" height="180" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_19.png" /&gt;\n&lt;img vAlign="center" lPadding="177" scale="0.4" height="180" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_24.png" /&gt;&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.4" height="180" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_21.png" /&gt;&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.4" height="180" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_17.png" /&gt;\n&lt;img vAlign="center" lPadding="177" scale="0.4" height="180" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_18.png" /&gt;&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.4" height="180" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_6.png" /&gt;&lt;img vAlign="center" scale="0.4" height="180" src="LyShineUI/Images/LoreImages/AncientGlyphs/AncientGlyph_16.png" /&gt;</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_18_01" speaker="Imhotep" name="SageImhotep" gender="Male" VO="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_18_01" VO_Status="Recorded" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Most intriguing... My aim was to formulate a plan against the Corrupted Legion. Theirs is a threat not seen in centuries.\n\nBut all I’ve found are scattered remnants of the Legion. Broken swords and shattered shields. Who could’ve defeated these fearsome legionnaires? And did they reconstitute? Or become Lost? They seem to have simply vanished!\n\nTo further complicate matters, I’ve seen evidence of the Angry Earth. They’ve not been a significant force here in over a thousand years. Why are their numbers suddenly increasing? A most intriguing conundrum...\n\nAs for that terrible presence, I’ve felt it stirring, heard it whispering. An ancient malevolence, of this I’m certain. And it's... familiar to me...\n\nBut my memories begin to fade, like morning mist at dawn. I must steel my mind lest I lose myself. I cannot allow that to transpire! Not now!\n\nAban and I will continue our search for more clues regarding this disturbing enigma. I will send word to Ghazi when we find something.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_18_02" speaker="Imhotep" name="SageImhotep" gender="Male" VO="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_18_02" VO_Status="Recorded" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The enigma deepens. Still no sign of the Corrupted Legion. They should have overrun this site. This is beyond perplexing, it’s a veritable mystery!\n\nAnd the malevolence grows stronger. Its presence pushes further into my mind… I can feel myself... slipping... losing my grip...\n\nAh, the price that must be paid for our centuries of life is a cruel joke by the Ancients. Or perhaps by something darker, far more terrible... The cold vastness of space is filled with unknown horrors...\n\nI must find answers! What is keeping Aban and Ghazi? I will continue searching for answers here but I will desperately need their help soon... very soon...\n\nAh, I think I hear them now! We have much to discuss.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_19_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The sacrifices looked promising, so we ordered the Legionnaires to unseal the first entrance. So far, we’ve unearthed little but bare walls and dust. Wondrous to behold and of marvelous proportions, but nothing like what Pontifex Charmion sought.\n\nAnd yet, I cannot deny a certain feeling. There is a presence within the Ennead itself, unlike any I have ever felt. It’s a heaviness in every breath, and a feeling of eyes watching from the empty walls. Uncanny...but not unwelcome.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_19_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A frenzy has come over Pontifex Charmion. She neither sleeps nor eats, pacing before the entrance to the Ennead with wide, staring eyes. \n\nWhen I offered to relieve her torment with prayers, she snapped at me. “You know nothing but the ink on your scrolls. The gods are so much more than images and words.” \n\nI opened my mouth to protest her blasphemy, but she kept speaking as though I wasn’t there. “We &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; find our way. We &lt;i&gt;will&lt;/i&gt; meet our gods.” I left her like that, speaking to only the desert wind.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_19_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">What Pontifex Charmion proposes is heresy. Casting aside the rituals of our forebearers, which have preserved us for generations. Replacing them with something audacious and terrible. \n\nAnd yet…and yet… \n\nDo we not live in a land of marvels and horrors? Are we not slain and resurrected like Osiris himself? We must be closer to the gods here, on Aeternum, than we ever were before. My bones quake, yet the more I listen to Pontifex Charmion’s reasoning, the more obvious it seems. \n\nWhy would the gods leave such wonders behind, if not to guide us to them?</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_20_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">I know I shame myself with these words, and I do not care. We are trained to stare death in the face without flinching. We have endured death, resurrection, monstrosities, and madness on this island. But I cannot go back to the Ennead. I cannot lead more Romans into this unnatural realm. \n\nEach breath was a trial. Even the cobwebs seemed to resent our passage. The shifting walls and silent, staring guardians offered no awe, only a nameless dread. I knew it in my bones: we were being watched, and by something with no love for humans.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_20_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Praetorians whisper among themselves around the evening campfires. Nobody eats much, and I sleep with my sword within reach.   \n\nMessengers race between our camp and Charmion’s, to no avail. Last night, I couldn’t help overhearing raised voices from the Legatus’s tent. Yet he said nothing. Just sat in stoic silence, listening to the priests and captains shouting obscenities at each other. \n\nAll I can do is pray that the Legatus decides soon, and wisely. I even made an offering to mighty Mars…to grant us victory at arms, should the worst come to pass.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_20_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Ennead must be sealed. \n\nAll further excavations and explorations of the ruin are expressly forbidden. Praetorians will guard all known entrances. Any trespassers will be driven off by force. \n\nI, Lucius Crassus, command this by my authority as Legatus of the 19th Legion. I will personally see that it is enforced. Should the worst befall me, it is my wish that my son Evandrus lead the Legion, if they accept and acclaim him.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_21_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">(This brittle sheet of papyrus is fragmentary at best, with many words and sentences scratched out in a firm hand.) \n\nThe void, bursting with stars beyond counting. \n\nThe voices, each deeper than the sea and greater than the dome of the sky.  \n\nThe visions. The &lt;i&gt;visions&lt;/i&gt;. They grant me no rest. \n\n-Imhotep, Vizier of the Gods</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_21_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">In exchange for sleep, I seek wisdom from the gods. \n\nThough I sit at Sutekh’s feet night after night, I cannot make sense of the visions that plague me. Even the infinite wisdom of the divine is no comfort. I glimpse boiling red seas, the earth heaving and plants crumbling to ash. I awake in agony. \n\nNo one else seems to hear or see. The city is silent in the cold morning light. Do I flirt with enlightenment, or madness? \n\n-Imhotep, Vizier of the Gods</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_21_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">At last, my vision clears. \n\nSutekh calls, as he has done so often before, and I answer. There is no choice. There is no other path. All paths are one, and it has been laid out before me. \n\nWith stone and blood, with gold and azoth, with the greatest beacon this land has ever seen… we shall forestall the end. The Ennead will be our crowning glory, and our salvation from doom. \n\n-Imhotep, Vizier of the Gods</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_22_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">I fell and it clambered on top of me. Its six legs pinioned my body to the sand, holding me fast. I felt fire as something large and sharp inserted itself into my belly, slowly, as if the mindless beast were careful not to break me. \n\nI held fast to this irony as a drowning sailor clings to a broken mast, made breathless as a churning sea of pain gripped up my soul and plunged me into dreamless night.  \n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_22_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">I came to my senses in a kind of large earthen nest, without knowledge of whether it had been moments or days that had passed. I scrambled toward freedom, to the lip of the nest, with the alacrity of wounded prey. \n\nI kept a silence, not daring to look at the depredations the creature had wrought upon my tender flesh lest I cry out, but it knew my intent and scuttled quickly to block my path. And yet, it did not slay me. \n\nA slow horror crept upon me, as I realized that the creature wanted or needed me alive.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_22_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">It watches me with wet, black pearls that I hope one day to burst. I think it never sleeps, though I have long since yielded any attempt to escape. \n\nMy body is no longer capable. And yet I hunger. It brings me meat, at times. I try not to think. No, truthfully, I do not think. I greedily consume the oozing guts it provides as if it were indeed I that were the monster. \n\nIt let me crawl to the edge of the nest, to drink from a small pocket of steaming water, though I suspect the noxious liquid slowly poisons me. I wonder, my friend, if you are still alive. Would you laugh with me, knowing the price we paid to hunt iron hides?\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_22_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">I lay in fever. I write to distract myself from hundreds of small movements I now feel in my bloated, darkened belly, movements that ripple just beneath the surface of my skin as if my body were a demon’s cauldron brought to boil. \n\nIt dawns on me now. Scorpion’s Cradle is not a place. It is my body. I cannot help but laugh. Ah, the pain…\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_23_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">“It is not that I do not love you,” I swore, watching the color drain from poor Shukri’s face, “But that I promised myself to another.” \n\nArikh, my dearest love, had somehow found me. I had heard his voice call to me under the moonlight. It was quiet at first, and I feared it was merely an apparition, an artifact of my own guilt. But it was clear as day now. I would not leave him again. \n\nThe sands swirled around me in the blistering wind as I struggled to follow the call of his voice. I needed to see him. To embrace him. To know he had forgiven me so that I could forgive myself. I climbed to the top of a dune and shielded my eyes from the wind, staring off into the dark. He called my name again. Closer this time.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_23_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">“Arikh!” I cried out with joy and desperation, running as best I could in the dim light of the stars.\n\nBut the fel beast before me had stolen the form of my beloved. Ice flowed through my veins as I gazed upon the cruel parody of his handsome face. It smiled at me, this phantom, this doppelganger. Its sallow lips pulled away from its gaunt cheeks, exposing a long, foul grin of cracked and pointed teeth. \n\nAs it stretched out its arms to embrace me I froze. I lost the will to run, the will to live! That's when I heard it—the cruelest sound I shall ever hear.\n\n“No!” came Shukri's voice, “Take me! Take me instead!” The creature turned its gaze past me into the dark. I collapsed, pulling my knees to my chest, too frightened even to breathe.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_23_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">After the apparition left, it was a long time before I dared to stir again. I sat, quivering in the darkness, knees pulled to my chest. When I at last dared to move, I saw Shukri, my brave beloved, lying prostrate in the dirt, flesh blue and mottled like a festering corpse. I hobbled to his side to confirm what I already knew.\n\nBut he moved. Horror overcame me and I wrenched myself free from his grasp, dashing off into the night. The last thing I heard was his soft, tender voice, imploring me not to abandon him.\n\nI hear his call now, every night, carried like a whisper on a soft wind, loving me endlessly. And when I hear him call my name, I ache with the knowledge that I dare not answer.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_24_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">I screamed, but no sound came, my eyes darting quickly from form to form in the swirling darkness.\n\nThey were all around me, a mass of fang and claw in the blackness. I stumbled, and fell weakly to the hot sands, my ragged breath catching in my throat.\n\nSomething hard and sharp dragged across my back, ripping the skin away like wet parchment. I gasped as the creatures descended, each crueler and greedier than the last. Suddenly, within the grains I felt a child's hand reach out and clasp mine.\n\nI awoke once more, lying atop a rough-hewn altar of stone, my body feeling at once alien and familiar. My clothes were as tattered as ancient paper and the hairs on my arms were gray. In my arms was a child who sobbed with the voice of a grown man. His name was Khnum, and he promised to bring prosperity.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_25_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">My body withers, and yet I hunt the sands, in search of a fleeting vision of her. Her hair hung low in a heavy braid, draped over her fur-covered breast. Pelts and bones were the only garments that adorned her lithe body, and her green eyes stared through me as I rose from the pools. She, the lioness, and I, her startled prey.\n\nI froze, and the cumbersome words of man left me. It was not the desert lions that flanked her that sapped the strength from my knees, but my own, insatiable desire. As they, I yearned for her touch, for the caress of her supple fingers, winding their way through my rival’s mane. Did her cheeks flush with color as she disappeared silently into a mist of sand?\n\nAfter, I lay for many days in a dazed and troubled heat, speaking only of her, my madness reflected in the gentle eyes of those who tended me.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_26_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">I would never have believed it, had I not seen it with my own eyes. The spectacle was a mad absurdity even for that ragtag bunch known as the “Blood of the Sand.” I should start by saying, their reputation for fearlessness is well-earned. As is their penchant for mad, displays of said courage, bordering on the suicidal. \n\nThey were five that day. Each stripped off the blood-red regalia that marked the tribe, and took a seat atop a shield of one he had felled in battle. The ritual masters sat at the base of the cliffs, each beating a great drum, it’s base dug deep into the earth. The rest of their number crashed their weapons together in time with the percussion, adding to the din. They shouted “Shah-Neshen!”\n\nAfter a time, the earth began to shake. I could feel it in my very bones. And that is when I saw it… the great wave on the horizon. Something was coming.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_26_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The five pushed against the rocks, sliding down upon the great shields toward the sandy arena. As the wave approached they readied great spears, each one lashed to a cable at his waist. Then the ground gave way.\n\nWhat I saw that day shook my very soul. The body of the great serpent rose from the sands, maw agape, its endless mass blocking out the very sky. But the madmen never faltered. They continued to ride the cliff face, oblivious to the danger. They cried out to their many and varied gods – to Tyr and Ares, to Anhur and Donar – as a cheer went up from the assembled throng.\n\nAnd I realized, that I was screaming, too. Not with the ecstasy of the congregating lunatics, but with a horror beyond comprehension.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_26_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The first of the riders reached the sandy arena, hurling his spear toward the hulking mass of the Devourer. The beast paid him no heed. Instead, it turned at its apex, yawing maw now directed back at the earth, and dove back into the unknown abyss from which it had emerged.\n\nThe ground shuddered again, and my teeth and bones rattled as an opaque cloud descended over the flatlands. Calmness returned, and oppressive silence blanketed the clifftops, as all eyes stared intently into the settling dust. At long last, the sands calmed, leaving behind nothing but the dunes. \n\nAll eyes turned to the chief, who seemed to shrug slightly. That was when I understood. Their deaths were expected— the warriors were to travel the underworld and find a path off the island.\n\nI turned to record my observations, and when I looked back— they were gone. All of them. We must have an alliance with these Blood of the Sand, if we are to succeed in our efforts.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_27_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Today I found a flower, its tiny yellow petals adorned like a miniature crown on a green bulbous frame. When I saw its tired, ugly, scarred flesh I thought of your face, my love, and smiled. \n\nFor I, the delicate flower, grew ever lovelier in your succulent soil of wealth and adoration. Now, I have been blown on a warm wind to this distant land, to adorn it with my gentle beauty. \n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_27_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Yvette and I ran hand in hand through the desert today. Her health is much improved, and her spirits as well! I thank the Gods we had the sense to depart from Reekwater. Surely a swamp is no place for man to live. \n\nYvette has become hale, and often visits town to see the Consul. Today I shall follow, and surprise her with a handful of desert sage!\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_27_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Sand. White bones. That’s all you’ll find in Brimstone, they said, as if to say Windsward was some kind of magical faerie forest. Windsward. A bunch of farms growing rocks and Lost instead of turnips! I had enough of that, and plenty more. \n\nSure, here they’ve got rocks and sand. And sure there’s cockroaches big as a bull. But come the evening time? I don’t get near as many bug bites as I used to, whilst looking for a dumb cow that’s wandered into some den of blue-skinned man-eaters. \n\nAnd when it’s all cool on your skin and the air is all crisp like, up on the rooftop, it’s- it’s damn satisfying is what it is. \n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_27_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">No man can sell water. It is a fault of mine, to always prove them wrong when they say a man can do only this or a man can do only that. But a merchant, he knows. He understands his customer. And once he understands, then anything! \n\nSo. One hundred jugs I fill, I put in the cart, I swim in mud, across sand, I lose half my cargo to the sand serpents, Umbria take you. And after thirty-nine days I come to the Brimstone Hamlet. \n\nAnd I sell everything. Everything! How long it takes me? One day. Just water? No! It is home. I sell home. I sell the clear memory of a summer day. I sell the song of the brook by the big pine tree, where you read the poetry, eh? Home. And I, Giovanni, I will do it again! My water from Everfall. My Everwater.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_28_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Never thought I’d miss the rain from Mourningdale. Brimstone Sands, a demon’s blessing on it. An alchemist heaven, they said. Sulfur by the armful, they said, just go you to the Pools of Orcus and pluck it off the ground! \n\nWell I went and saw- I don’t know what. Twenty feet tall, shaped like a man, but hunched over with knives for fingers. Slimy green branches for hair, and clumps of eyeballs bunched together like grapes! And it talks, with a beak too small for its head. “Meat,” it said. \n\nWell that was it for me. I roared and swung at it with my pickaxe, bashed its eyeball stalk into a bloody paste. It screamed, and I ran. As I’ll run all the way back to the blessed rains of Mourningdale.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_28_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">How many times I did say it, I wish we lived somewhere far, far from here! \n\nHere, what will be our fate? Eaten by some monster, and goats will shit our bones. Father, you say we must keep to what we know, we must be safe. \n\nSafe. What is safe? No water, you will die. Meet a Devourer, run into lion, you will die. See pretty lights in the sand at night, you will die. \n\nOh father, I want to see something new. I want to see the wetness of a great lake. I want to see trees that grow round, soft leaves. I want to see a land with no goats! You say it is a danger, but I will hug a monkey’s bottom, as long as it is new.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_28_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">In the bazaar, one may find everything the eye or stomach wants for. On a day when the desert hawks fly and bring a breeze, I eat of grapes, drink sharp wine, and coat my tongue in honey and cream. If I turn, I see great Caesar crowned with the sky. \n\nYet, I would rather gaze upon my sweet Hasti’s face than on Caesar’s furious brow. I would rather taste Hasti’s lips, sweeter than any date. It is lonely now, for I cannot bring her here anymore. She no longer feeds on grapes and honey. But her beauty remains undiminished. Her lips still sweet. \n\nSomeday, Hasti, I will join you, and we will feast together. Such succulent grapes we shall find.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_29_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Master Zhuang, I hope that this letter finds you well. And I hope most fervently that you will change your mind on this, to join me here in Brimstone Sands. \n\nThere are so many mysteries to explore here, each more delicious than the last! Of late I have followed the great shishi lions guarding Diospolis. The stone beasts move! Their movement is as graceful as a cat’s. I dared to pet one. It was unlike any other sensation. Powerful muscles rippled under stone skin, smooth and cool to the touch, even in Brimstone’s blazing forge. \n\nMy favorite, I call Ming-Ming, after you. He is painted with the colors of night- blue, gold, black. He has killed me many times, but I have finally established a kind of friendship with him. \n\nIt is a great joy. Though, at times I miss my left arm. Ming-Ming likes that one best.\n\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_30_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Oh Sutekh, master of chaos, storms, disorder,\nKeeper of those who dwell away from the Nile,\nForsake not your people, far from Hapi’s embrace\nLay bare your heart, a feather, at Osiris’ trial.\n\nDo the offerings of our great hearths displease you?\nWe keep all rites and rituals that gods compel.\nWould you forsake your supplicants’ appeasements?\nIn this, the Land of Reeds, wherein your people dwell?\n\nCorruption deepens, the Earth herself is wrathful \nLands split asunder, and the winds and waters roil.\nAbandon not those whom you once held as faithful.\nRaise up our host here in this time of blood and toil!\n\nLord Sutekh, grant us your wisdom, strength, and guile\nThat we may drive the insolent foe from these our lands.\nGrant us the power of your scepter and your vision\nThat we may better carry out your sacred plans.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_30_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">And our Lord spake: “Behold, I am Sutekh, master of the primordial, shaper of storms, and he who has conquered death. As the waters of the Nile drew life out of the desert sands, so I have drawn you from your world of death, to life eternal.”\n\n“I raised this place from the waters of Nun, from the nothingness of what came before, and have brought you here to raise a great city. From the red sands of the desert, our greatness shall spill forth to cover these lands like a garden of reeds. Those who follow shall bring forth multitudes, and hold themselves inheritors of all this power and glory.”\n\n“But those who disobey, they shall be cursed with wanderlust. Into the desert, I commend their kin, to scrape out a living from the dust. There, they shall know despair. For their pride I curse them to deathless life, for in their hubris they have turned their back on true divinity. And their punishment shall be unending!”</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_30_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Take heed and bear witness to the fury of the gods of the Nile. \n\nAll plagues and anarchy. All savagery at the hands of the corrupted foe. All these great tests wrought upon the faithful have paled by comparison, to this: the revolt of the House of Geb, and the rise of Apophis, Dragon of the Abyss. For deep beneath the western mountains of Bhaku, the waters of Nun boiled over, and from their depths they birthed a great evil.\n\nMighty Sutekh, Lord of Chaos and Creation, Bringer of Order out of Disorder, has fallen. And in his absence, Chaos itself now reigns. Out of the void he has birthed creatures of earth and air, and spirits of fire made flesh. In his anger, the primordial lord of the desert sands has unleashed this wrath upon the great city, scouring her halls of life and wealth all the trappings of civilization. And in the red desert, he has conveyed his serpents of the sands, who burrow beneath the land to devour any who dare seek refuge among the dunes. \n\nGods of mercy, abandon not your children, far from the home of their ancestors. Who answered your call to unknown reaches to build your Land of Reeds. Spare us the trials of these grotesque spirits called forth from the infinite darkness of Duat, that we may escape yawning oblivion in the crocodile maw of Ammit, Eater of Souls. \n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_30_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Fire engulfed the endless sky,\nAs hate corrupted the land.\nThe gods have gone, our dream destroyed,\nGreat sage, please outstretch your hand.</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_31_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Imhotep, the Great, the Wise, the Merciful, who once counseled the gods of the Nile, declares himself Pharaoh over the lands of Brimstone and her peoples. From the high priests of the great temples to the lowliest serfs of the quarries, I bid you rejoice, for your homeland is restored!\n\nLet it be known that Imhotep, your lord magnanimous, on the dawning of the first day of the season of rains, took up his mace and struck down the last of the corrupted. As the rituals demanded, the remains of this defeated foe were carried in procession to all the great districts of the city, that all might witness the final triumph of our master.\n\nIn keeping with the laws of our ancestors, the Pharaoh now declares a year of celebration of his rule. He bids all the sons and daughters of the Nile return to the great city, to feast alongside him and restore the glory of their birthright. Envoys shall carry the news to all corners of the desert, proclaiming to all her vast  \n\nRejoyce, children of Egypt, children of eternity, children of the gods, for your long exile is ended! The home of your ancestors is restored. So proclaims Imhotep, first and only Pharaoh of the Eternal Kingdom, and so it is written. May his reign be unending. \n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_31_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Imhotep, the Great, the Wise, the Merciful, who once counseled the gods of the Nile, has declared that the ancient holy places of the times before, that once gave residence to living gods, shall be forbidden to all who now dwell within the Great City, until such time as divinity returns to sands of Brimstone. For upon their departure, the ancient gods placed upon these places a terrible curse.\n\nFor those with the hubris to act in defiance of this order, beware, for within the souls of our forefathers spill forth from the underworld of Duat to defend these sacred temples for eternity. Any who set foot upon this hallowed ground, may be bound to join them in their deathless watch for all time. Bring not this horror unto yourself and your kin, but rather heed the wisdom of Imhotep, and let any vestige of the bygone age pass as a memory into the eons.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_31_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Great Pharaoh called us home, but now bars us from the sacred places of our heritage? How can this be? The gods of the Nile once dwelt upon this sacred earth, alongside their chosen of the faithful. Can it be that they have now forsaken us? That they would welcome us home to the Great City of our ancestors, but forbid that we pay tribute with them? No. It cannot be. It must not be.\n\nMy forefathers were faithful to Sutekh, who conquered death and brought immortality to his people. Why would he do such a thing if not to ensure that we may worship him forever? The holy places of our predecessors must be restored, and their holy artifacts reclaimed. If not, the gods will only abandon us again, and scatter their wretched people onto the sands once more.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_31_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Gods forgive me, for I have acted in defiance of their will. In my zeal, I believed we were worthy to return to the holy places of the forerunners, but within them, only doom remains.\n\nWhen I set foot in the Great Pyramid, that wonder of the living god Sutekh, in hopes I might gaze upon the splendor of the Ennead, I witnessed such horror as the eyes of man have never seen. The deathless still stand watch there, not as spirits or phantoms, but bound within their ancient joints and sinews. Even unfleshed as they were, I could see the torment in their lifeless eyes, burning with the ancient energies of creation. \n\nHow cruel must the gods have been to forsake them in this state of putrefaction, these, their most faithful, who stood watch over their kingdom when they dwelt upon the earth. Lord Sutekh, I implore you, grant me your wisdom that I may understand the necessity of this pitiless fate.  And look not with anger upon your disobedient servant, for doubting the voracity of your Pharaoh’s decree.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_32_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">I’ve walked battlefields from the forests of Gaul to the banks of the Nile, and I would have never imagined that a soldier of Rome could find himself in such a sorry state. Octavian has prevailed, and it is now clear who will sit on the imperial throne of Rome. \n\nWith Antony’s defeat on the battlefield, the queen poisoned herself with an asp, Charmion bid her priests carry her body off to someplace called the “Field of Reeds”—a ridiculous superstition. As her praetorian guard, it’s my duty to see to it she reaches that destination safely. Safe, I imagine, is a relative term for a doomed woman, but as it guarantees me a place aboard the imperial barge, under the circumstances, I’m happy to oblige. \n\nGiven that I doubt I’ll be returning to Egypt anytime soon, consider this my last will and testament. Whoever finds it, I bequeath my lands in Rana and its olive groves to my wife Jamal, and later our son. My dear love, forgive me for leaving—it is the only way I know to protect you and our son. \n\nCenturion Quintus Publicus \n\nPraetorian Guard to Marcus Antonius, 19th Legion</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_32_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The skies opened, and the wrath of the gods had fallen upon us. As the storm raged outside, and the ship pitched and rolled with the waves, so our queen writhed and tossed in her own struggle against the poison in her veins. I knew in my heart, that the long shadow of Ammit was upon us, and that we would soon be returned to the abyssal waters of Nun, from which all life flowed. \n\nThen suddenly, salvation came. From within the fog, I beheld a man, wrapped in linen with a crown atop his head. In his hands, he carried the crook and flail of his office, and I knew that he must be the great lord Osiris, father of all Pharaohs, and judge of all that is mortal. All who dared look upon him knew he was not of our realm, for not even the guards dared to stir from their posts at his intrusion.  \n\nLady Charmion prostrated herself before him, pleading for his intercession with our queen – our Cleopatra, daughter of Isis. His daughter! He proclaimed that he had been riven by Sutekh, but that our Queen’s presence had roused him from deathless torpor. He would deliver her from mouth of the crocodile unto the Land of Reeds, where she would reign forever.\n\nLady Charimon kissed the hands of our deliverer, and at his approach, a stillness fell over the Queen. He took her in his embrace, and they both vanished in a flare of light. Outside, the rocking of the ship abated, and the wind has grown quiet. I could hear the soft cackle of the gull far off in the distance. \n\nPraise be to Osiris, who has weighed my heart against his feather, and found me unburdened by sin!\n\nIras, Handmaid to Cleopatra, Queen of Egypt</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_32_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Well, this land continues to be a source of amazement.\n\nToday, a priestess of Isis and attendant of the queen broke down, despairing that she had failed poor Cleopatra, and that the goddess had abandoned them. I confess, I can’t entirely disagree— the queen has been missing since the strange report of her abduction during the storm, and I can only assume is quite dead. Still, the outburst was proving disastrous for morale, and I can ill afford any treasonous impulses on the part of our Egyptian comrades. So I did the only sensible thing, and ordered a member of the 19th’s to quickly silence her.\n\nHis report was rather unorthodox. Apparently, after he slit her throat she vanished in a ball of light. My first thought was to have him checked by the medics. But before I could manage it, the woman showed back up at the camp spewing her usual doomsaying. \n\nFor the time being I have her locked up in a trunk in the bilge. It’ll have to do until I can devise a more… creative solution for dealing with dissidents.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_32_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The rage of the maelstrom has abated, but the outlanders continue to wash ashore. By last count, over 80 ships have made landfall, but still more may be lost in the Stormwall. Moreover, they have proven competent mariners, and many have thus far remained on the open ocean with the intention of rescuing those whose vessels have been lost at sea.\n\nOf those who have made landfall, some wear the traditional garb of our ancestors. They bear little resemblance, however, to the soldiers with whom they mingle. Their segmented armor and livery are of origins mysterious to me. By nightfall I have no doubt that hundred, perhaps thousands of their number will have come ashore, with their intentions as yet unknown. \n\nI would propose that we call a meeting of all of the desert-dwellers. We must assess the threat posed by the outlanders, and appoint an emissary to engage them on our behalf. Such numbers represent an inevitable shift in the balance of power here in Brimstone, and it would be wise for us to position ourselves to benefit when it does.\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_32_05" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">To the one known as Legatus Crassus,\n\nI see by your order and discipline of your ranks, that you are a strong soldier and veteran of many campaigns of conquest. But by now it is surely known to you that this land is like no other that you have dared to tame. The wages of immortality render the prospect of prolonged conflict grim, and the ruins you now call home are evidence that there are greater dangers slumbering beneath the sands of this strange and terrible place.\n\nAnd so, in the interest of peace, and the prosperity of the greater whole, I make this proposal: take me into your service. You have, no doubt, gained much in the way of wisdom through your travels and tribulations. You should then know, then, that I have lived many lifetimes and died many deaths in the pursuit of such knowledge. I offer you this insight, along with my vast chronicles of this new world and its denizens, if you will only agree to entertain my council.  \n\nIf you find my terms acceptable, look for me at the foot of the Great Pyramid. I will be waiting.\n\n-Imhotep, Sage of the Brimstone Sands\n</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_33_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">BEHOLD JUPITER\nBEHOLD AMUN-RA\nBEHOLD THE MIGHT AND GLORY OF THE REPUBLIC\n\nInscribed by ceremonial ritual\n\nDignitaries present,\nImhotep, Sage of New Corsica\nGeneral Crassus, XIX\nEvandrus Crassus, XIX\nCharmion, Pontifex of Akhet</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_33_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Atum, sovereign of the Gods and Goddesses\nTefnut and Shu are under your command\n\nLord of lords, King of the Ennead\nFather of the father, Geb\nMother of the mother, Nunut\nAuthority in heaven, earth and underworld\nLifetime is assembled together in your fist\n\nYou give to those you love\nIsis, Anpu, Heru, Nebet-Het\nYou protect us from Sutekh</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_33_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Bless the stones and the soldiers who guard this Wall\nBless the Mother for Her Protection\nBless the Scales of Justice\nAll who disavow Judgement\nMay they crash as waves on the Shores of Aaru</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_33_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The mighty XIX determined in all faith\nHave built a Temple to our Father\nMay this seed of Rome grow\nAnd spread to all corners under the heavens</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Hydra's Breath</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Blaze of Glory</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Transmutation</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Ultimate Intentions</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_05" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Vigil Eternal</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_06" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Ammit's Hunger</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_07" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Opening the Way</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_08" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Froderico's Notes</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_09" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Consigned to Oblivion</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_10" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Woes of an Amateur Antiquarian</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_11" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Pilgrim's Diary</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_12" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Roar of the Manticore</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_13" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Ancient Glyphs</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_14" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Trouble for the Praetorians</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_15" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Charmion's Journal</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_16" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Head of the Snake</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_17" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Book of Gates</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_18" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Great Architect</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_19" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Priest's Tale</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_20" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Legion's Tale</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_21" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Pious Echoes</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_22" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Scorpion's Cradle</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_23" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Dune Phantoms</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_24" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Bringer</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_25" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Huntress</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_26" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Trial of the Devourer</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_27" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Desert Lights</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_28" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Desert Thorns</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_29" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Favorites</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_30" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Prayers and Portents</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_31" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Age of the Pharoah</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_32" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Romans' Journey</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Chapter_33" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Brimstone Monuments</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_01_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">From Ignatius's journal</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_01_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">From Ignatius's journal</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_01_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">From Ignatius's journal</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_02_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Terror of Troy</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_02_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Vespasian's freedom</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_03_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Rima's Grimoire</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_03_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Rima's Diary</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_03_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Rima's Diary</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_03_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Rima's New Grimoire</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_04_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Drusilla's devotion</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_05_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">From a brittle page at the Great Wall of Nebet-Het</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_05_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">From a brittle page at the Great Wall of Nebet-Het</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_05_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">From a bloody page south of the Wall</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_06_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">From Pshereamun's Writings</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_06_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">From Pshereamun's Writings</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_07_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Found before a gateway at Hermopolis</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_07_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Found before a gateway at Hermopolis</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_07_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Found before a gateway at Hermopolis</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_08_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Third Treatise, First Draft</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_08_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Miscellaneous Observations</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_08_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Written during medical recovery</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_09_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A page from the Legion's annals</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_09_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A page from the Legion's annals</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_09_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A page from Legatus Crassus's personal records</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_10_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">From Perrin Mercier's Field Journal</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_10_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">From Perrin Mercier's Field Journal</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_11_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Found in the Lamp of Osiris Lighthouse</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_11_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Found in the Temple of Shu</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_11_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Found near the Gates of Sutekh</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_12_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Manticore</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is ABOVE</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is SHADOW</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is CROSSROADS</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is JOURNEY</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_05" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is GIFT</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_06" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is SUN</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_07" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is MOUNTAIN</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_08" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is DAWN</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_09" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is ORDEAL</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_10" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is OCEAN</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_11" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is DAY</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_12" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is BELOW</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_13" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is FIRST</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_14" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is SEALED</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_15" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is WALL</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_16" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is HOME</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_17" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is CHAOS</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_18" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is PERSONA</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_19" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is VIRTUE</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_20" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is STRENGTH</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_21" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is DESTRUCTION</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_22" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is NIGHT</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_23" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is SHIELD</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_24" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is FOOD</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_25" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is WATER</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_13_26" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is RIVER</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_14_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A confession</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_15_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A journal page</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_15_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A journal page</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_15_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A journal page</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_16_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Invasion of Aeternum</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_17_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">VEIL OF THE WEARY ONE</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_18_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">An abandoned page from the journal of Imhotep</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_18_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The final page in the abandoned journal of Imhotep</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_19_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Ennead Pilgrimage Scroll, Part 1</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_19_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Pilgrimage Scroll, Part 2</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_19_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Ennead Pilgrimage Scroll, Part 3</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_20_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">On the Breaching of the Ennead</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_20_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The calm before the storm</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_20_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A centuries-old page with a broken seal</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_21_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">What Came Before</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_21_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">What Comes After</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_21_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">What Must Be Done</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_22_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">When the end began</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_22_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Needed</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_22_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Meaning and meat</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_22_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Is me</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_23_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">His voice</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_23_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Its arms</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_23_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">His voice</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_24_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">From the Prophetess of the Desert, Khnum’s prayer, page 62</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_25_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A weakness</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_26_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The chosen</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_26_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A mad dash</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_26_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Blood travelers</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_27_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A bright new day</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_27_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A healing town</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_27_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Anywhere’s better than Windsward</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_27_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">My Everwater</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_28_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Blessed rains</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_28_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Goats and sand and goats and sand</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_28_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Hasti’s ties</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_29_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A letter to Master Zhuang</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_30_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A plea for the return of lost divinity</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_30_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Arrival on Brimstone</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_30_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The return to disorder</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_30_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Sung to many different tunes</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_31_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Call of Return</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_31_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Disturb not the graves of our ancestors</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_31_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Forbidden from my ancestors’ glory…</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_31_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The horror of what I have witnessed…</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_32_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The living will of a broken man</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_32_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The gods have delivered us</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_32_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">No one can die…</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_32_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Newcomers from beyond the clouds</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_32_05" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">An offer of service</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_33_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Placard dedicating the construction of the Colossus of New Corsica</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_33_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">An inscription found on the Pyramid</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_33_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Placard dedicating the construction of the Wall</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Subtitle_33_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Placard dedicating the construction of the Temple</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_01_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Debate on Ethical Warfare, Part One</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_01_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Debate on Ethical Warfare, Part Two</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_01_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">An End to the Debate</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_02_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Pompey's Letter</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_02_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Antony's Letter</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_03_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Brimstone Sulfur Experiments</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_03_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Nostalgia</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_03_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Against the Sages</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_03_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A New Path</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_04_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Drusilla's Letter</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_05_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Dream of Riches</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_05_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Mind the Gap</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_05_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Awakening</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_06_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Problem of Suffering</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_06_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Natural Order</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_07_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Small Test</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_07_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Last Resort</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_07_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Gnosis</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_08_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">On the Evolution of the Roman Centuries</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_08_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Local Superstitions</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_08_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Firsthand Observations of Roman Pila</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_09_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Passage of Time</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_09_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Bitter Truths</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_09_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Crassus's Oath</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_10_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Materials</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_10_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Methods</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_11_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Blasphemous Musings</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_11_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Narrowing Road</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_11_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Abandonment</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_12_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Mysterious Riddle</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">DINGTA</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">JIIBA</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">KEYYA YIB'</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">TEYII</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_05" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">WETZUU</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_06" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">CRUUJ</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_07" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">AMBA</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_08" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">PIMBII</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_09" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">D'UN-YICH</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_10" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">HIMDE</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_11" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">AABER</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_12" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">ITKA</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_13" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">DZUU</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_14" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">J'IJ</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_15" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">TSADZUI</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_16" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">HID</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_17" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">B'EYEG</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_18" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">RIIGA</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_19" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">EYBUE</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_20" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">CRUUJ'II</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_21" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">D'UN-GA</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_22" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">TAB'</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_23" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">B'ENGYING</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_24" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">TSANGMIIJ</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_25" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">JICH</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_13_26" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">DUBUU</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_14_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Malatesta's Letter</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_15_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Gateway to the Gods</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_15_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Secrets of Akhet</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_15_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Will of the Gods</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_16_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Crassus's Letter</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_17_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The wisdom of the word is</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_18_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Mysterious Threat</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_18_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Malevolence Grows</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_19_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Unsealing</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_19_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Charmion Transfixed</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_19_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">On Breaking with Tradition</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_20_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Legionnaire Scout's Report</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_20_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Unhappy Discord</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_20_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Legatus's Duty</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_21_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The First Revelation</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_21_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Second Revelation</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_21_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Third Revelation</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_22_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Day 1</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_22_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Day 2</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_22_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">What Day?</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_22_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Cradle</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_23_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Arikh, Part 1</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_23_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Arikh, Part 2</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_23_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Shukri</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_24_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Child</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_25_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Huntress</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_26_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Devourer, Part 1</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_26_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Devourer, Part 2</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_26_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Devourer, Part 3</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_27_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">To My Love</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_27_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Yvette</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_27_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Satisfying Home</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_27_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Amazing Trades of Giovanni</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_28_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Ogdan's Journal</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_28_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Goat-sick</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_28_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Quiet Corner</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_29_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Favorites</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_30_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Hymn to Absent Gods</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_30_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Testament of the First Peoples</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_30_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Doom of Eternity</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_30_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Brimstone Nursery Rhyme</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_31_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Pharaoh’s Decree vol. I</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_31_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Pharaoh’s Decree vol. 2</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_31_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Witness of the Faithful vol. 1</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_31_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Witness of the Faithful vol. 2</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_32_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">A Legionnaire’s Lament</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_32_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Behold our queen’s salvation!</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_32_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The Journal of Publius Canidius Crassus</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_32_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Scouting Report</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_32_05" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">To Legatus Crassus</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_33_01" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Glory of the Republic</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_33_02" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Great Pyramid of Akhet</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_33_03" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Great Wall of Nebet-Het</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Title_33_04" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Diana's Nemorensis</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">The sandswept and sunscorched desert in the West, and the last known home of the Ancients</string>
<string key="Topic_Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">Tales of Brimstone Sands</string>
<string key="Tales_of_Brimstone_Sands_Body_09_03" speaker="General Crassus" name="GeneralCrassus" gender="Male" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Territory_Brimstone_Sands">What remains of my Legion must never fall. We are the last survivors, the living memory of the 19th. I will endure any hardship, face any darkness, overcome any torment, rather than let the 19th Legion vanish from the world. \n\nI, Lucius Decimus Crassus, swear this by Jupiter and by unbreakable stone. I swear it by the genius of the fallen Caesar and his rightful heir Antony. \n\nIf I do not do this, may divine Jupiter strip the gift of immortality from my flesh. May I be cursed forever as an oathbreaker. May I bear all the suffering of the 19th Legion, for all time.</string>