<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_01_05">Our crops continue to rot as villagers leave one by one. Those who were stubborn enough to stay are now too stubborn to leave. Those foolish enough to eat these crops turn gravely ill. All our harvests fail, what did we do to deserve this blight? \n\n- F. Sneed</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_01_06">I sense that the lightning storm was merely the beginning of the end for our lives here. We've had vicious attacks from these... monsters. Husks that seem human, but only ravage and destroy. The remaining families have lost members in the attacks, and we survivors are now forced to flee this area. We have no choice but to leave. \n\n- F. Sneed</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_01_07">We've had some luck to move farther north. We've found fertile land and decided to rebuild. Nestled within the crags that surround it, we soon saw a small lake as a respite in our journey and replanted our crops. Scorching our tools, we found that fire cleansed them of the stench of the blight. We remain vigilant in how we use the soil. But, we are unsure if those freaks with the red eyes will find us here, too. Mayhap it is only a matter of time...\n\n-F. Sneed</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_01_08">No matter how far we go, the monsters do not leave us. They’ve taken to attacking in hordes, storming the farms, wasting everything in their wake. \n\nBut the fates aren’t entirely cruel. We have the support of a knight. He tells us how to hide and how to ambush them. He holds them back with his trusty cannon. \n\nWe will work together and we’ll all live to see another day. We will not succumb. \n\n– F. Sneed</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_01_09">The attacks begin again, but none of us were under the naive impression that those fiends would leave us alone. \n\nThose of us that have survived these attacks have decided to make for the settlement of Prydwen. It is the last judgement for us, and this may be our only salvation. \n\n- F. Sneed</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_03_01">I don't think I can take much more of this. I try my best to craft weapons for these insolent pirates, and all I am met with are more demands from this mad Captain! All he wants is more shine, more gilded handles... I am collecting my due fees, and quite a handsome pay at that, but I shall decidedly not put my mark on these weapons. In fact, I would be ashamed to admit these trinkets are my own work!\n\n-L. Harrison, Master Artificer</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_03_02">The damn weapons won't even fire! What use are these damn things if they're nothing but pretty toys!</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_04_01">The Master Builder is depending on us for ore. The settlement won’t be able to defend itself without a timely supply. \n\nWe scraped together what iron we could and sent that with a few of our brothers. But the way that the Lost are crowding the mines? They may not be able to make it. \n\nWhatever Gods there are on Aeternum, I hope they guide their way! \n\n– Elias</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_04_02">Quite curious is the case of the creatures in this mine! As some lucky adventurers have discovered, these fiends do in fact eat any gems they find. One could hypothesize that in life they worked these mines, once a rich source of precious stones on Aeternum. However, one must ask, why do they eat them? The idea I propose is based on their patterns of hoarding! They must have some semblance of the value of these stones and, in a lust to hoard wealth, they put such small stones into the safest place they can muster: their own bodies!\n\nFinding precious gems in the belly of these poor wretches is still rare. Some guess that only one in a group of ten Withered may have a gem in their belly. With that in mind, good luck! You may need it.\n\n-Dr. H. Garrison</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_05_01">Some madman attacked me! He was crazed and wild, with red eyes that struck fear in my heart. I held him back with my pitchfork, and he ran away. The stink coming off of him is one I will not soon forget. Now, that stench won't come off my pitchfork no matter how many times I wash it.\n\n- M. Barovier</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_06_01">Now I see what Thorton was talking about in her last letter. These Ancient Guardians are ferocious, suspended in undeath to guard the ruins of a society we may never understand. Well, out with the old and in with the new as I always say. I will try to cull as many Ancient Guardians as I can while out hunting so that Survivalist Thorton might have some relief from their blockades. If only I had someone to help with this...</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_06_02">Those bastards! Those dastardly, villainous fiends! The mace-wielding miscreants of Archernar killed me, and even worse, they damaged my pants! This is azoth-infused silk, and incredibly hard to come by. It isn't easy being the most fashion-forward Survivalist of all the settlements but it's a title with which I find immense pride. I will have my revenge for this affront to my aesthetics.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_07_01">Coming to this island was a mistake. I came to this island seeking fortune and riches. But, I was misled. This place is no heaven...\n\nAs I lie here, dying, I feel my soul leaving this husk. Ah, is this how it felt Faustus? To have body and soul ripped to pieces by the claws of fiends?\n\nMaybe, like Faustus, my fate was sealed when I signed to come to this place. Maybe coming to this island was both my sin and my punishment.\n\nOh, Margarete...\n\n- N. Leevs</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_08_01">I hear his footsteps coming closer, his boots booming against the wooden planks beneath me... He'll make quick work of the flimsy door and barricade I've created. Montore has gone mad. He's slaughtered his own crew as we crashed on the island. But, more terrifying than that, the dead sailors around me seem to come back to life. Their eyes are empty, twisted by Montore's madness. I hide here, but I know that I too will meet the same fate. This entire expedition was doomed. - Helvan</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_12_01">Out by the coast she still lurks, evading me at every turn. I know I had her on my hook once or twice, for her favorite bait is glowworms and I have them in great supply.\n\nI know it's the same Ray-Finned Barb. I've taken to calling her 'Nibbler' for the way she toys with my bobber before I can properly hook her. This one is too smart for her own good. Nibbler must be a lady, for you see it is the female Barb who hulks over the male in size, and her wit is mighty quick.\n\nBut I shall not let her outswim or outsmart me. I'll get her one day, and mount her on my home wall. One day, Nibbler, you shall be mine... - Q. Warwick</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_12_02">If you give a man a fish you feed him for a day, but if you teach a man to fish you feed him for a lifetime. Or at least that's what Papa said.\n\nThat is why I taught all my subordinates in the army the essential skill of fishing. It's why I continue to teach fishing even in my retired living. It is not only a pleasurable hobby but a means of survival here in Aeternum. Fish are food, and food is life.\n\n- Q. Warwick</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_13_01">Stinky,\nWe were hoping you'd join our hunt, but your odor is spooking all the game.  So we're heading out on our own.\nDon't know what you've got spoiling in them guts of yours, but you can expel it in solitude. We've had enough of it!\nOnce we've bagged a bear or two, we'll be back to let you out.  Hopefully, your arse will have said its piece by then.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_14_01">Captain Capili\nFirst Mate Tupu\nChief Technical Officer Salesa\nSecond Mate Hoapili\nNavigator Eketone\nBoatswain Arona\nRigger Hamakua\nSurgeon Kekai\nEngineer Lavea\nGunner Fiso\nQuartermaster Sapani\nCook Rata\nMessman Pihopa</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_14_02">- Three crates of bullion\n- Hardtack rations\n- Two reels of parchment\n- Thirteen hatchets\n- Fifteen bows\n- Five crates of arrows</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_14_03">Day 13:\nMutiny is upon us. Boatswain Arona has gotten it into everyone's heads that the ship would be better run by him and the whispers of dissent have grown to a dull roar belowdecks. I will have to reinstate my authority by any means necessary if we are to reach our destination in time.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_15_01">In th' beginning, there was naught but formless energy. \n\nA material energy, though sublime. \n\nAn ethereal fire. \n\nWithin the fire was contained all life, every thought, every impulse. \n\nWhen bullet or lead ball be fired, therein do an infinite power of impulse reside. A single second, betwixt thy click of a hammer and thy mighty spark's ignition be where secrets of the universe hide. \n\nThe Island has given me sight. Every death and every return, I see our purpose yet clearer. \n\nListen to me true story, and believe! \n\n-          &lt;i&gt;Captain L. Wright&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_15_02">In the Before, was I a humble pirate warlord. \n\nMy ships numbered hundreds and every nation was afeared. How little did I know, me true path had yet been revealed. \n\nMe First Mate, family on th' high seas, had raised mutiny. I had no choice. So sadly, had I no choice but to execute the poor soul on sight. Without a sea breeze of a second, I barely thought and fired. \n\nA click. \n\nAn explosion. \n\nThe cool sizzle of th' exhausted barrel. Saw the universe explode before my very eyes! That was the day, I always say, that I became a Master Cannoneer.\n\n -         &lt;i&gt;Captain L. Wright&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_15_03">I once felt the life in my veins. Was electric. But to be truly Lost... is electricity and a strange numbness at the same time. With every death, me spark mixes with something alien and divine. \n\nAnd when the dream ends, ye wake up on th' shores of yer long-lost passing. Again and again and again. Every journey be breathless and infinite! Every moment awake is a gift! And a poisoned fruit. \n\nI've seen the end though! \n\nI've seen when the spark gives up! There be nothing left but formless energy! \n\nEthereal fire! \n\nIt only takes time! And time, I think, is all we have.\n\n-          &lt;i&gt;Captain L. Wright&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_15_04">Loyal comrades! Faithful friends!\n\nJoin! Submit to the Cannon. Submit to th' bullet, gunpowder, and musket. \n\nJoin and be shown yer truest path. Path to enlightenment, and th' only way we ever escape this godforsaken Island. \n\nJoin and I shalt carry ye beyond thy veil. Through dusk and moonlight's peak, where we may all rest… Join me and find eternal freedom!\n\n-          &lt;i&gt;Captain L. Wright&lt;/i&gt;</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_16_01">Laikina,\n\nI left town at twilight, to avoid a scene with Constable Saville. But she was there, waiting at the gate, like she knew my thoughts. “Such a shame to see you go,” she said. “Monarch's Bluffs will surely miss you.”\n\nA perfectly normal thing to say. For the hundredth time, I wonder if the things I saw Saville do that night were just a nightmare. I can hear your voice, telling me that I'm being too paranoid.\n\nI find myself watching her. She seems so normal, wrapped up in the petty concerns of the settlement. But sometimes…I catch a flash of it in her eyes, when she looks at me. Maybe it's always been there. Or maybe she sees me as a threat, now.\n\nI'm coming to Windsward. If I head straight east all night, I should be able to get there by daybreak. The terrors of the nighttime wilds are nothing, compared to what I'm leaving behind.\n\nI'm looking forward to a fresh start.\n\n-Christopher\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_16_02">From the desk of Constable Saville:\n\nChristopher Ward has vanished from Monarch's Bluffs. His house was found emptied of all belongings. His soul has not returned home. None of the other settlements, nor any of the Watchers, have seen hide nor hair of him. \n\nI must note Christopher had been acting strangely in the days leading up to his disappearance. He seems to have fallen victim to some kind of paranoid delusion. I even caught him peering into my window late at night.\n\nDisappearances are, of course, nothing new in Aeternum. There are many dangers that await the underprepared and the overly-curious. Still, as the Constable of this settlement, I feel somewhat responsible. In the end, Christopher simply wouldn't heed my warnings.\n\nUnless further evidence turns up, Mr. Ward is presumed Lost or Corrupted. I'll ask Adjudicator Owgan add his name to the Covenant prayer list of wayward souls.\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_17_01">--gave me news of this “High King’s” arrival. I am told it was nothing short of miraculous. His vessel seemed undamaged and of a strange design. It was said to shine with a blinding light. I doubt this to be true but these stories are spreading.\n\nWhoever he fancies himself to be, he will no doubt prove a threat to your lordship’s dominion over these lands. I counsel you to gather your warriors and go to meet this potential usurper. I shall send word to the other lords. Perhaps united we can prevent calamity-- \n\n(No signature but the author was a high-ranking military officer who served a noble named Darius a thousand years ago.)\n\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_17_02">The High King’s magician has knowledge of an incantation that gives him mastery over the strange power of this land. I have never witnessed such a thing. Could he have discovered the secrets of the Ancients? How did he accomplish this so quickly?\n\nOnly a few words are known to me. It’s ancient Celtic. It speaks of a “serpent’s breath” and a “twilight realm” and of “folk of light and shadow.” \n\nI must learn the secrets of this charm. With its power I could change our fortunes.\n\nAmaranth the Raven-Haired\n\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_17_03">I held the Eternal Blade in my hands. I could not identify the metal. It was lighter than steel and glittered like polished silver. I would swear it hummed. \n\nThe High King bid me strike an old anvil with the edge. I dared not until he commanded it. Gripping it firmly, I smote the anvil and sheared away its heel in one stroke.\n\nThe Eternal Blade bore no mark. Its edge remained keen as a razor. By God, I will never see its equal. \n\nMaster Auric\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_17_04">Dearest Maeve, \n\nIt is my hope that this finds you in good health.\n\nThe High King’s call has gone out. He summons all to his banner, to build a great kingdom where all may prosper.\n\nEven though I possess no great strength of arms or cunning with magic, even the mightiest warriors and wisest wizards will have need of tables, chairs, and beds when they are weary from their toil.\n\nIf the High King can keep us safe from the horrors that roam this land, I will gladly pledge myself to him.\n\nIt is my fervent desire, my beloved sister, that you will choose to join me in this worthy cause.\n\nCullum\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_18_01">Our work on the Great Wall continues. I have met master masons from every known land. The collection of knowledge and skill assembled here astonishes me. \n\nThe High King’s wizard uses his craft to help us rebuild and fortify these ancient stones. He speaks of an evil that gathers in the north. We have seen more of those crimson demons. We must be ready for what is coming.\n\nConnor Hewer, Master Mason\n\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_18_02">The High King’s wizard fancies himself Taliesin of the old legends. He is cunning to be sure, and possesses knowledge of the Ancients unknown to us. He wields a staff of intricate design that allows him to manipulate the magic of this land. He claims he will pass on this knowledge to others. He has already taken on many apprentices. \n\nI believe he harbors a secret desire in his heart. The people give him their trust but I feel this wizard will bring doom to us all. The evil of this land will taint him. I must learn his secrets before it is too late.\n\nAmaranth the Raven-Haired\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_18_03">The High King has commanded that the stars be carefully measured and charted. I will do my part in this endeavor for I believe the answers to this world’s mysteries can be found in the heavens. The Sumerians, Greeks, and Persians knew this to be true. The Ancients knew this as well as evidenced by their study of the stars.\n\nBut Myrddin advises caution. He claims that just as we gaze out into the vast darkness, so too does it gaze back at us. He warns us to be forever vigilant for evil does not sleep.\n\nEstere\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_19_01">Myrddin cast me out of the Order. He accused me of deceit and of sowing the seeds of discord. But I have spoken the truth. I know the evil that has taken root in his mind. I see what he is becoming. \n\nThe others will not heed my warnings. Fools! The fall of the High King will be on their heads! I do not possess the strength to challenge Myrddin directly, but I must try to foil his purpose for the sake of us all. \n\nI will plead my case directly to the High King. I have found the “Folk of Light and Shadow.” They may prove to be allies. It is my fervent hope the High King is as wise as they say.   \n\nAmaranth the Raven-Haired\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_19_02">God’s blood! Waves of demons crash upon us with the fury of a storm. They strike where we are weakest. We cannot hold them! Our fortifications crumble!                                                                                                       \n\nWe’ve been betrayed! The Crimson Sorcerer has revealed himself. It is said he commands the infernal hordes. God in heaven, we are lost!   \n\nThe High King has retreated to the shore. They say the Raven-Haired fights by his side. May God see him safely away from this accursed island! And may He have mercy on our souls…  \n\nCaptain Ulfric\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_19_03">The demons have overrun the land, slaughtering every living soul. A lucky few may have found the peace of eternal death. The rest have joined the ranks of the Withered or been twisted into fell shapes.  \n\nWe have taken refuge here but it’s only a matter of time before we are discovered. Even if we are not, our stores of food and water dwindle. A few of us shall have to venture out in a few days.                                                                                                       \n\nHow could we have come to this? The High King’s promise of a fair world has been shattered. This land exists under a curse which cannot be lifted. I dared to hope and dream. Now, I pray I can forget…  \n\nCullum\n\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_21_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">You’ve caused me so much worry, Olive. I near fainted when your mother told me she was having you. I panicked when you first became a woman. I still remember the red everywhere. I couldn’t sleep all night when you stayed at the house of that fellow you were smitten with.\n\nYou stole my heart, when you first clutched my thumb as a baby. Your eyes spoke volumes even then. They spoke to me when you didn’t know words. Later, they spoke to me when you didn’t have the right ones.\n\nYour eyes were always a stormy blue sky. I’ve tried to capture their color in my final glasswork. There’ll be no more after this.\n\n- M. Barovier</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_21_02" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">I miss my little Olive. I hope you’re happy. Are you taking care of your health? Are you earning well? You should come home if you need money or food. This house is yours as well.\n\nWhen did you grow up so much that you forgot me? You could come home, greet your poor old father, ask me how I am doing. I am not doing well. How could I be happy when you’re not with me?\n\n- M. Barovier</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_21_03" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">I’ve not been a good father, Olive. I never should have raised my hand to you. I’d cut off that hand if it meant you’d forgive me, come back to me.\n\nLife hasn’t been easy without your mother. She was always the smart one. Every decision I make without her scares me.\n\nBut I don’t love crafting glass more than I love you. Crafting glass was just easier. And I am a lazy fool. I took the easier path. Maybe you were right to leave. But would you come back and forgive your ailing father?\n\n- M. Barovier</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_22_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Darling Edda,\n\nYou know I hate writing but I thought this would be a nice surprise. You’re a strong, kind, wonderful woman and I feel stupidly lucky that I can call you mine. \n\nDo you remember when we first came here? You got so excited by the silkweed and wirefiber! You made so many garments, I barely had any place to sit. \n\nIf I could gift you anything, it’d be that excitement again.\n\n\n\nYour Loving Husband,\nEdwy</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_24_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Greetings, my beautiful wife. I'm enjoying another sunny day by the farms. The haunted Lost and the groaning beasts are keeping me company. The guys and I joke and lollygag while we wait for the uglies to show their faces. We can hear them from a mile away.\n\nI’m eating well and I’m healthy as a horse. The farmers are taking good care of me. The only downside is not having you here in my arms but I’ll rectify that soon.\n\n\nAll My Love,\nSymon.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_24_02" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Today is the 3rd day of winter. The Lost aren’t receding. They do not sleep and they do not die. They’re slowly wearing out the men. If even Symon can get turned, what hope is there for any of us? \n\nI wish I could see Marietta again, even if just one more time. We had a hasty marriage, sanctified by a cleric named Dayo. I promised her we’d have a huge celebration at Geertie’s when I got back. Ach, the universe must be laughing.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_25_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Minister Lochnir,\n\nWhy aren’t you responding to my missives? We’re being overrun by the Lost! My miners are not equipped enough to fight all of them off. We need help immediately or we will LOSE the mines.\n\nSend every knight available and hasten to the mines.\n\n\n-	Foreman Allya\n\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_26_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">It’s hard to come by trustworthy friends in Aeternum. Someone who won’t try to offer you as a sacrifice to the Lost, who won’t try to wheedle an extra penny from you for a meal. \n\nOlaf is a good friend. He’s steadfastly and honorably by my side, come hell or high water. \n\nWhen the two of us mount our defense together, the Lost will be severely disadvantaged. With a lit fuse and a boom, we’ll lay them all to waste.\n - Ser Tenny</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_27_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Tenny came to me this evening. He wore not his usual livery, but a plain tabard that made him seem somehow unclothed. His eyes were downcast. \n\n“Captain. I heard Minister Lochnir will speak to Ser Dubois,” he said.\n\n“Yes,” I replied. “The four seals are needed to retrieve the crown for the True Heir.” I saw a doubt in his eyes. I hid my own, and waited.\n\n“The True Heir- has changed.”\n\nI felt a righteous anger enflame my face. “He has sacrificed!” I met his fearful stare and realized that I stood, sword drawn, as if I would hew him down.\n\nI tossed aside the weapon and took his shoulder. “Tenny! The heavens have granted us the greatest honor, to follow Ser Gawain. Wear joy in your heart, and don his colors proudly.” I saw his face flush and his eyes kindle with renewed life. “Captain,” he said.\n - Captain Hugh Ainsley</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_28_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">You are more than you’ve been. You’ve grieved over King Danjong’s untimely death. You’ve escaped the horrors of Empress Taiying. And you’ve stayed strong. You’ve abided by Confucius’ teachings and found yourself here, a land once ruled by an English king. \n\nLochnir is giving you a path, a way to care for the people and keep the place pure as Knight-Regent. You worry if you can do all that is needed. But you’ve learnt much from the rulers you’ve supported since you’ve been a child. Even Percilla says, “If anyone can do it, you can”. \n\nSo, arm yourself in mail and make your hair as a Joseon woman. Make Prydwen prosperous and peaceful for when the True Heir returns.\n</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_03">Notes from Traitor's Hold</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_04">Missives from the Mines</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_05">Ranching by Riverside</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_06">Lee's Reconnaissance</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_07">Deals with the Devil</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_08">The Ballad of Madman Montore</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_12">Warwick's Fishing War</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_13">The Huntsman's Stench</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_14">Monarch's Wreckage</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_15">The Cannonomicon</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_16">Monarch's Bluffs Legacies</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_17">King Arthur’s Arrival</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_18">The Reign of the High King</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_19">The Fall of the High King</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_20" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Lochnir’s Discoveries</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_21" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A Father’s Prayer</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_22" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Letter to Edda Yonkers</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_24" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Letters From The Lost</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_25" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Allya's Missives</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_26" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Faithful Olaf</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_27" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Knights Of Teyrnon Keep</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Chapter_28" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Jin Jae's Journal</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_01_05">A Farmer's Words</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_01_06">A Farmer's Words</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_01_07">A Farmer's Words</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_01_08">A Farmer's Words</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_01_09">A Farmer's Words</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_03_01">Found in Traitor's Hold</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_03_02">Found in Traitor's Hold</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_04_01">Found in Cynefin Mine</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_04_02">Found near Cynefin Mine</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_05_01">Found in Arruda Ranch</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_06_01">Found in Archernar</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_06_02">Found in Archernar</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_07_01">Found in Devil's Quarry</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_08_01">Found in Deadman's Anchor</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_12_01">Fish Escapee</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_12_02">Feeding an Army</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_13_01">Found in a campsite in Hiraeth Lookout</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_14_01">Found in Capili's Coronation</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_14_02">Found in Capili's Coronation</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_14_03">Found in Capili's Coronation</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_15_01">BOOK OF DAWN</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_15_02">BOOK OF DAY</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_15_03">BOOK OF DUSK</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_15_04">BOOK OF NIGHT</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_16_01">Found on the Road out of Monarch's Bluffs</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_16_02">Found at the Constable's Desk in Monarch's Bluffs</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_17_01">Letter to Lord Darius</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_17_02">A Master of Azoth</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_17_03">The Eternal Blade</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_17_04">The High King’s Call</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_18_01">Fortifying the Wall</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_18_02">Staves of Power</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_18_03">An Astronomer’s Observation</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_19_01">A Wizard Corrupted</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_19_02">The Final Stand</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_19_03">A Desperate Prayer</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_20_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A Study Of The Ancient Altars</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_20_02" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A Study Of Ancient Artifacts</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_20_03" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A Study of The Tablet’s Summoning Properties</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_20_04" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">In Honor Of The True Heir</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_21_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">An Artist’s Inspiration</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_21_02" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A Daughter’s Health</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_21_03" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A Final Request for Forgiveness</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_22_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A Love Letter</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_24_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Keeping Spirits Up</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_24_02" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Hasty Wedding Regrets</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_25_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A Call For Help</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_26_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A Trusted Friend</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_27_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A page from Captain Hugh Ainsley’s journal</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Subtitle_28_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A Place of Peace</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_01_05">Undying Rot</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_01_06">Running Away</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_01_07">Brief Respite</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_01_08">Tenny’s Kindness</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_01_09">Last Judgement</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_03_01">Captain's Demands</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_03_02">Pistoleer's Plight</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_04_01">Ore For The Settlement</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_04_02">Belly Full of Riches</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_05_01">Stenchfork</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_06_01">Now I See</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_06_02">Lee's Special Pants</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_07_01">Punishment</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_08_01">The Last Words of a Doomed Sailor</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_12_01">The One That Got Away</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_12_02">Food Rations</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_13_01">Note for Stinky</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_14_01">Capili's Coronation: Roster</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_14_02">Manifest of the Coronation</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_14_03">Capili's Coronation Log Day 13</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_15_01">THE CANNONOMICON</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_15_02">THE CANNONOMICON</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_15_03">THE CANNONOMICON</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_15_04">THE CANNONOMICON</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_16_01">I Know What She's Hiding</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_16_02">Missing Persons Report: Christopher Ward</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_17_01">The High King</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_17_02">The King’s Magician</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_17_03">A Legendary Weapon</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_17_04">Uniting the Land</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_18_01">Defending the Realm</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_18_02">The Art of Magic</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_18_03">Searching the Stars</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_19_01">The Fall to Darkness</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_19_02">The Corruption Surge</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_19_03">Darkness Falls</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_20_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Altars of Power</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_20_02" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Artifacts Of The Ancients</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_20_03" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">The Call Of The Tablet</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_20_04" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">The Circlet Of The Swords</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_21_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">The Final Glasswork</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_21_02" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">One’s Only Child</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_21_03" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">A Reassurance of Love</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_22_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">The Love Of One’s Life</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_24_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Wistful Note</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_24_02" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">One Day Closer To The End</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_25_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Need Help Now!</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_26_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">What Would We Do Without Olaf</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_27_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">Tenny’s Doubt</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Title_28_01" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">For the Future of Prydwen</string>
<string key="Topic_12_MonarchsBluffs">Tales of Monarch's Bluffs</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_12_MonarchsBluffs">Hilly bluffs with an island fortress that stands tall against the waves</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_20_01" speaker="Lochnir" gender="Male" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">These altars in Khalladan, seem to have some power over the Lost. “Power” might be the wrong word. But definitely some kind of influence.\n\nI can use Younge Geiser’s notes to figure out how to channel their essence. And if I can’t tap into their magic, maybe I can convey them to where they’ll be most useful.\n\nI must think this plan through to support my True King in the way he deserves. Only then, can I join him.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_20_02" speaker="Lochnir" gender="Male" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">The Ancients clearly had ways of controlling the Guardians. I wonder if it’s the same magic that powers the altars.\n\nI found runes here that light up when the Lost come near them. Maybe there are more objects like these within the nearby ruins of Antares, so I shall continue my search there.\n\nFor the true heir and the restoration of Prydwen's glory, we will find a way to unite behind the royal bloodline once again.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_20_03" speaker="Lochnir" gender="Male" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">The legends are true! I just needed to replicate that stone tablet.\n\nI had to bind and kill the poor young squire nearly a dozen times before he finally surrendered his soul, but after he fell... he was easy to control. He will walk to wherever this replica is placed.\n\nAnd this sphere, a tiny thing with tremendous power! Having this power in the palm of my hand will be an immense boon to my objective. I will make myself a staff from it, a fitting accessory for the right hand of the True King.</string>
<string key="12_MonarchsBluffs_Body_20_04" speaker="Lochnir" gender="Male" VO_Status="Script Generated" rel_version="Quest_MSQ2_Revamp">The knights are loyal to the True Heir. He was after all, Artorius’ most trusted knight and nephew, the one who the High King himself put in charge of the circle.\n\nSer Gawain looks at me, now, trusting me with his power. He commands me without words.\n\nOur path is set. He will be crowned with the Circlet of Swords, and watch as the Lost multiply and submit to his glory.</string>