<string key="Lore_Chapter_Crafting">Crafting</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Crafting_Overview">Crafting Overview</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Crafting_Overview">The Basic Steps</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Crafting_Overview">Crafting is a major part of New World. Most weapons, armors, tools, and utilities must be crafted by a player. Even players who don't craft items themselves rely on others who do for their equipment.\n\nThe process of crafting an item often involves several steps, some of which require Trade Skills. For steps in the process you don't have the necessary skills for, you'll have to work with another player or check the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_Overview"&gt;Trading Post&lt;/a&gt; for what you need.\n\nThe steps to craft an item are:\n  1. &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Gather"&gt;Gather Raw Resources&lt;/a&gt;\n  2. &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Refining"&gt;Refine Materials&lt;/a&gt; - Tier 1 recipes can usually skip this step and use the raw resources directly\n  3. &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Recipes"&gt;Craft the Item(s)&lt;/a&gt;\n\nIt is often a good idea to work backwards when trying to make a specific item. Use a &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Stations"&gt;Crafting Station&lt;/a&gt; to view all of the recipes for that station. Select the type of item you want to make to open the recipe Tiers. Select the Tier of item you wish to make to see its recipe. You can also pin the recipe as an Objective so you can easily keep track of what you need.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Crafting_Gather">Gathering</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Crafting_Gather">Collecting Raw Resources</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Crafting_Gather">Crafting always requires materials. Raw, unrefined resources are gathered from around Aeternum, and usually require using &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Gather2"&gt;Gathering Tools&lt;/a&gt;. There are several Trade Skills related to gathering. These increase the number you collect and grant a chance to gather resources of a higher &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Rarity"&gt;Rarity&lt;/a&gt;. These skills are also required to &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Refining"&gt;refine&lt;/a&gt; that type of resource into higher Tier materials.\n\nSome items don't require tools to gather. Flint can be found on the ground all over Aeternum, but especially along the beaches. Small amounts of Wood can be gathered from bushes without the need for tools. Turkeys can be harvested for meat and feathers without a knife. If a tool you do not have is required, you will see that requirement in place of the option to gather when you approach.\n\nA simple Tier 1 version of each Gathering Tool can be crafted at your &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Camping"&gt;Camp&lt;/a&gt;. They only require Flint and Wood, which can be gathered without tools, and have no skill requirement to craft.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Crafting_Gather2">Gathering Tools</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Crafting_Gather2">Harvesting Resources</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Crafting_Gather2">There are 4 kinds of gathering tools: Logging Axes, Pickaxes, Sickles, and Skinning Knives. Each has a corresponding Trade Skill to increase its effectiveness.\n\nA Logging Axe or Hatchet is used to chop trees to gather Wood. Trees can be found almost anywhere in Aeternum, though in more corrupted areas they may be withered and provide unusable wood. Wyrdwood trees are rare, and tend to grow in dangerous and &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="GettingStarted_Sanctuaries"&gt;Lawless Areas&lt;/a&gt;, but the Wyrdwood they provide is required for the highest Tiers of items. The Logging and Carpentry Trade Skill improves how much you gather from each tree, grants a chance to receive higher Rarity Wood, and allows refining the Wood.\n\nA Pickaxe or Pick is used to gather stone from Boulders and ore from metal veins like Iron Veins. Boulders are common, but are found most densely in Highlands areas. Ore Veins are less common, and are also most likely to be found in Highlands areas. You can use the Map to identify Highlands areas to search. Starmetal and Orichalcum are rare metals that only appear in dangerous and &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="GettingStarted_Sanctuaries"&gt;Lawless Areas&lt;/a&gt;. They are required for the highest recipe Tiers. The Mining, Stonecutting, and Smelting Trade Skill helps you gather more from Boulders and Ore Veins, grant a chance to gather higher Rarity resources, and allows you to refine those resources.\n\nA Sickle is used to harvest various plants, both mundane and alchemical. Throughout Aeternum, plants like Hemp, Vegetables, Herbs, and Alchemical Ingredients can be found growing in the wild. Hemp provides Fibers, which are important to creating cloth and clothing. Vegetables and Herbs are used in many Provisioning recipes to create meals, and can be grown by Companies in their owned Territories. Alchemical Ingredients are unique to Aeternum, and provide the power needed to create Potions and Magical Gauntlets. The Harvesting and Weaving Trade Skill lets you gather more from plants, gives you a chance to gather higher Rarities of resources from plants, and allows you to weave Fibers into cloth.\n\nA Skinning Knife is used to cut Rawhide from dead animals, and to collect their Meat. Many types of wildlife can be found across Aeternum. Most allow the harvesting of Rawhide, but some species like Elk have a chance of providing Animal Horn, and others like Wolves could provide Animal Fangs. Explore to find the types of areas each species prefers. The Tracking, Skinning, and Tanning Trade Skill lets you harvest more resources from animals, gives you a chance to harvest higher Rarities of those resources, allows you to tan Rawhide into leather, and gives you the ability to track animals on your Compass at the top of the screen.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Crafting_Refining">Refining</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Crafting_Refining">Creating Higher Tier Materials</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Crafting_Refining">Most recipes require materials that have been refined. Refining is done at Refining Stations, which can be found at &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="GettingStarted_Outposts"&gt;Outposts&lt;/a&gt; or built by Companies on their Territories. Refining Stations have Tiers associated with them and can only refine materials up to that Tier.\n\nThe Woodshop is used to refine Wood into Timber, Lumber, and Planks. It requires ranks in the Logging and Carpentry Trade Skill to use, and higher Tier refining requires a higher level of skill.\n\nThe Smelter is used to refine precious metals into Ingots, as well as to create Charcoal from Wood. Ranks in the Mining, Stonecutting, and Smelting Trade Skill are required to smelt Ingots, but anyone can create Charcoal. A higher rank is required to craft higher Tier Ingots.\n\nThe Loom is used to weave Fibers into cloth like Linen, Sateen, and Silk. It requires ranks in the Harvesting and Weaving Trade Skill to create cloth, with higher Tiers requiring more ranks.\n\nThe Tanning Station is used to turn Rawhide into Leather. It requires ranks in the Tracking, Skinning, and Tanning Trade Skill to use, and requires more ranks to craft higher Tiers of Leather.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Crafting_Stations">Crafting Stations</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Crafting_Stations">Where Things Get Made</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Crafting_Stations">Crafting Stations are structures where crafting can be done. Each allows crafting recipes of a certain type, and require a different Trade Skill to use. Crafting Stations can be found in &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="GettingStarted_Outposts"&gt;Outposts&lt;/a&gt; or built by Companies on their Territories. Each has a Tier, and can only be used to craft recipes of that Tier or below.\n\nForges have recipes for Melee Weapons, Shields, Gathering Tools, and Heavy Armors.\n\nWorkshops have recipes for Ranged Weapons, Ammunition, and Siege Weapons.\n\nOutfitting Stations have recipes for Light and Medium Armors, Bags, and Trinkets.\n\nKitchens have recipes for food and drinks that provide a wide range of benefits in addition to filling your &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_FoodDrink"&gt;Food&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_FoodDrink"&gt;Drink&lt;/a&gt; meter.\n\nArcane Repositories have recipes for Tinctures, Potions, Weapon Coatings, and Magical Gauntlets.\n\nYour &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Camping"&gt;Camp&lt;/a&gt; is also a Crafting Station, but is a bit unique in that it has recipes for a very wide range of items. Many of these recipes don't require refined resources, but don't always have options for every Tier. The Tier of your Camp and the ability to craft the recipes found there is determined by your ranks in the Wilderness Survival Trade Skill.\n\nWhile viewing a Crafting Station, you can use the tabs at the top to switch to viewing recipes from any other Crafting Station. However, you cannot craft items for a station you are not using.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Crafting_Recipes">Crafting Recipes</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Crafting_Recipes">How Things Get Made</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Crafting_Recipes">When you visit a &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Stations"&gt;Crafting Station&lt;/a&gt;, you are presented with a number of types of items. If the item is presented in white, you have the materials and skill to craft one or more of its Tiers. If the item is in red, you are missing one or more of the requirements. You can click the item to view the specific Tiers and Recipes either way.\n\nAfter selecting an item type, you can see the different Tiers of the item this station can craft. Click a different Tier's column to view its Recipe. While viewing a Recipe, you can select what &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Rarity"&gt;Rarity&lt;/a&gt; of each material you want to use, and see how those changes affect your odds of crafting it at each possible Craftsmanship level. For equippable items, you can switch from the Craftsmanship view to see the resulting item's stats, or you can hover your mouse over each section of the Quality Bar to see the item's stats should you roll that Craftsmanship.\n\nIf you lack the materials to craft any given recipe, you can choose to pin that recipe to the HUD as an Objective. Doing this keeps all the required ingredients visible as you play, so you can easily keep track of what to seek out.\n\nIt's very common that you cannot refine all the materials needed for a recipe. You'll need to work with other players or use the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_Overview"&gt;Trading Post&lt;/a&gt; to get anything you can't supply yourself.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Crafting_Rarity">Rarity and Craftsmanship</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Crafting_Rarity">Quality in Material and Execution</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Crafting_Rarity">Many items can have a Rarity and a Craftsmanship rating.\n\nTo craft an item of a higher Rarity, you need to use higher Rarity materials. As the name suggests, higher Rarity materials are tougher to obtain. They require more ranks in the relevant gathering Trade Skill as well as a bit of luck to obtain.\n\nCraftsmanship is a representation of how well made an item is. If you have enough ranks in the relevant crafting Trade Skill, you have a chance to craft items of higher quality.\n\nUsing a higher Rarity of the primary material will increase the Rarity of the final item, which is always better. Using a higher Rarity of any material, including the primary material, combines with your ranks in the corresponding Trade Skill to increase your chances of crafting at a higher Craftsmanship. You can see your chances of crafting at each possible Craftsmanship level while viewing the Recipe. Just like Rarity, having a higher Craftsmanship results in an item with better stats.\n\nWhen you craft the item, you automatically make a Crafting Roll. You'll see the results of your roll on the Quality Bar when making the item.\n\nItems that are both high Rarity and high Craftsmanship are extremely valuable. Making these requires a significant amount of investment, both in the form of skill and valuable resources.</string>