<string key="Lore_Chapter_Outpost">Outposts</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Outpost_LordEveretts">Deprecated: Bug This! Lord Everett's Watch</string>
<string key="Lore_Title_Outpost_TrueDuncansWatch">Deprecated: Bug This! True Duncan's Watch</string>
<string key="Lore_Title_Outpost_AuroraAeternae">Deprecated: Bug This! Aurora Aeternae</string>
<string key="Lore_Title_Outpost_FirstLight">Deprecated: Bug This! Firstlight Station</string>
<string key="Lore_Title_Outpost_WeaversStation">Deprecated: Bug This! Weaver's Station</string>
<string key="Lore_Title_Outpost_WeaversPost">Deprecated: Bug This! Weaver's Post</string>
<string key="Lore_Title_Outpost_WeaversPeak">Deprecated: Bug This! Fort Velazquez</string>
<string key="Lore_Title_Outpost_MonarchStation">Deprecated: Bug This! Monarch Station</string>

<string key="Lore_Body_Outpost_LordEveretts">All cast from the sea are welcome in Wind's Edge\n\nShelter from the wind for those seeking trade\n\nThose who stand with my brother Miles\n\nWill swing in the wind from a noose\n\n\n\nBounties on Withered and Wolf pelts paid here\n\nSkilled hunters for both needed\n\n\n\nEverett Duncan, Rightful Lord of Windsward</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Outpost_TrueDuncansWatch">Travelers take heed – East of Wind's Watch, avoid the Town of Violets\n\nWithered lie thick as the flowers there\n\nAll refugees, castaways, company men – esp. tradesmen - I grant you shelter within these walls\n\nBut those of Wind's Edge who have cast your lot with my “brother” Everett,\n\nMay you die at Wind's Edge with the bastard\n\n- Order of Miles Duncan, the only Duncan who holds the true and rightful claim to the Windsward</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Outpost_AuroraAeternae">Travelers – know that the former outpost of Wind's Pointe is no more, it has taken on a new name from the aurora that now shines over us. Our doors are open to ALL pilgrims who seek the light that shines within the great ring of stones. In the aurora's light, cast aside fear, hold fast to faith. The Aurora Aeternae is fury, frozen - wrath, suspended – and it shields us all, for it is heaven's herald.\n\nYet like heaven's mysteries, let the light of the Aurora Aeternae ever remind us that not all secrets of Aeternum are for us to uncover, else one day the sun within the stone shall blossom with its full light and consume us all. To seek and never be content is Grenville's folly, the ‘scholar' who caused the blue flames of the road to be lit, the cursed dead of the eastern ruins to rise, and awoke this second sun in these lands – what knowledge did he gain when consumed by the aurora's light?</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Outpost_FirstLight">By order of Malcolm Rotheschilde, Lord of this post, all pilgrims are welcome at Firstlight Station.\n\nHere, the first light of Aeternum beckons to all who seek these shores. As it called to us with its holy radiance, it shall call to others. But in its shadows, lie dangers - keep within Firstlight Station at night, for Withered devils infest the Breakwater Bay to the Southwest. Skeletons of explorers, slow in dying, the flesh stripped from them mark the paths to warn away the foolhardy – if you choose to travel to the Bay, no rescue party will come for you - and none shall mourn your passing.\n\nAlso beware the lighthouse to the East. The paths that wind around the base of the monument walk with a different kind of dead, older than us, perhaps older than any – and they still grip ancient blades and their eyes blazing with Azoth.\n\nNo stories to scare children these - they are truth. Do not test them.</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Outpost_WeaversStation">All are welcome here, lest you speak ill of the witch that once dwelled in the Fen – for those that do, you will find no shelter here.\n\nMany she helped in her life, and Weaver's Fen honors her sacrifice, and her efforts.\n\nSpeak ill of her or curse the Fen, and many curses in return will fall upon your head. Seek out her path and her journey may help you as it helped others.</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Outpost_WeaversPost">Tradesmen, Craftsmen, Companies all –\n\nYou are welcome to trade, but you may not spill blood here.\n\nNo dueling, no fighting, none is allowed,\n\nEven if Aeternum somehow permitted violence within this claim.\n\nMake of the forge and inn as you will, but to those seeking trouble,\n\nPiss off somewhere else.</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Outpost_FortVelazquez">From Consolation do you come, then continue on in our graces.\n\nBefore you ask, yes, the legends of the red fountain are true – crimson Azoth awaits in the center of the isle, red with corruption, and we are content at Fort Velazquez to watch you leave in search of it as the Captain did when he abandoned his crew on Aeternum's shores.\n\nWe will give no warnings, no words of caution – the devils that hound us, Withered and Corrupted things all, are proof of where red-drenched temptations lead.</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Outpost_MonarchStation">MONARCH BAY this may be, but in this fort be NO Kings, Queens, Lords, and other royal bastards - only those willing to WORK the land, and STAND with their fellow BROTHERS AND SISTERS.\n\nAZOTH does not come freely, but at least here, you STAND beside others who, like you, may NEVER see their homes again, and have committed to making Aeternum theirs – not for any lord, not for any King or Queen, but for the PROMISE of the future Azoth brings.\n\nP.S. If you pride yourself a Scholar – we have NO need of you. The words writ here are the most that shall be spent in these walls.\n\nP.S.S. If you bear the mark of the Red Sign – you are less than a Scholar and less than a dog. If seeking your “fortune,” seek it by drowning in the Corrupted of the Cleave, for that's the only fortune your greed deserves.</string>