<string key="Lore_Chapter_Companies">Companies, Territories, and War</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Companies_Building">Building</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Companies_Building">Erecting Structures on your Land</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Companies_Building">If a player has the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Ranks"&gt;permissions&lt;/a&gt; to do so, they can build Structures in any &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Territories"&gt;Territories&lt;/a&gt; that their Company owns. Building is done by first placing a Blueprint, then supplying the required resources.\n\nTo place a Blueprint, enable Build Mode (default: [B]). Using Build Mode, you can navigate possible Blueprints using the mouse wheel. When you've found what you want to build, move to where you want the Structure to go and place it, much like you do with your &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Camping"&gt;Camp&lt;/a&gt;. You can only place Blueprints up to the same Tier as the Territory's Protection Ward.\n\nOnce placed, you need to supply the Blueprint with material to actually construct it. These resources are supplied from your &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Inventory"&gt;Inventory&lt;/a&gt;. They do not have to be added all at once, allowing you to make multiple trips.\n\nStructures that can be used, like &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Refining"&gt;Refining Stations&lt;/a&gt; and Storage Containers, can have a minimum rank set to use it. In order to set this requirement, interact with the Structure yourself and use the dropdown menu at the top of the screen. Most Structures can have this permission set to any rank or even be opened for public use. A Structure with its permissions set to public can be used even by players outside of the Company that owns it.\n\nTo repair or demolish a structure, approach its interact point and press the key for More Options (default: [R]). This will allow you to select what you want to do using your mouse.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Companies_Overview">Companies Overview</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Companies_Overview">Many Players Working Together</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Companies_Overview">Every player in New World is a member of a Company, even if they are the only member of their own. Players can join each other's Companies, which allows them to work together to achieve things they couldn't alone.\n\nTo invite someone to your Company, use the flyout on their &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_SocialMenu"&gt;Player Portrait&lt;/a&gt;. To join someone else's Company, you will need to be invited in the same way. Once you've received an invitation, you can accept it from the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_SocialMenu"&gt;Social Menu&lt;/a&gt;. \n\nYou do not need to leave your Company before joining another. You will be removed from your previous Company automatically.\n\nAll claimed &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Territories"&gt;Territories&lt;/a&gt; and player-built &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Building"&gt;Structures&lt;/a&gt; are owned by Companies, and can be used by any member with adequate &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Ranks"&gt;permissions&lt;/a&gt;. This means that any Territory you claim or Structure you build is to the benefit of your Company and all its members. Conversely, leaving a Company means you lose access to those Structures since it's the Company that owns them, not the player.\n\nCompanies will also want to capture and defend Territories. They usually do this through &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_War"&gt;War&lt;/a&gt;, which allows them to fight each other without the usual &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Crime"&gt;criminal penalties&lt;/a&gt;. Wars also include a Siege phase, during which the Defender's Territories' protection can be bypassed.\n\nCompanies have Treasuries that the Governor and Consuls can withdraw from. Any member of the Company can provide money to this Treasury, making it easy to collect funds for Company use, like buying &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Territories"&gt;Claim Charters&lt;/a&gt;.\n\nUp to 50 players can be in a single Company. Players cannot be members of multiple Companies at once.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Companies_Ranks">Ranks</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Companies_Ranks">Hierarchy and Permissions</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Companies_Ranks">Company members each have a Rank. Depending on their Rank, members have access to perform various actions on behalf of the Company.\n\nEvery Company has a Governor who has all possible permissions. The Governor is the leader of the Company, and holds the power to set the status of every other member. For the Governor to leave the Company, they must promote a different member to be the new Governor. The only exception is if the Governor is the only member of the Company, in which case they cannot leave it without joining a new one.\n\nThe Ranks tab of the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_UI"&gt;Company screen&lt;/a&gt; allows you to explore all the available ranks and their permissions. Additionally, most Company &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Building"&gt;Structures&lt;/a&gt; can have a rank requirement set. This allows Companies to have even more fine grain control over who can use each Structure.\n\nHigher ranks offer a member more potential since they can access more aspects of the Company, but they also offer risk to the Company because the member could then sabotage things. Beware of spies and double agents.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Companies_Siege">Siege</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Companies_Siege">Battle for a Territory</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Companies_Siege">Every Company may set a Siege Window. This is the time of day that a &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_War"&gt;Siege phase&lt;/a&gt; will take place when defending in a War.\n\nIt is very important to set this time to a time that most of the Company's members are available! This time must be set before the War begins, so set it as soon as possible. If you are the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Ranks"&gt;Governor&lt;/a&gt; of your Company, make efforts to ask your members what time works for them most reliably. If War is declared on you and none of your members are online during your Siege Window, the attackers will be able to take one of your &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Territories"&gt;Territories&lt;/a&gt; uncontested, even if you've paid for protection.\n\nTo set your Company's Siege Window, use the Siege Window tab in the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_UI"&gt;Company screen&lt;/a&gt;.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Companies_Territories">Territories</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Companies_Territories">Claiming Land</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Companies_Territories">In order to start building &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Building"&gt;Structures&lt;/a&gt;, a Company must claim Territory. Territories are spread around Aeternum, and vary in size and resources. There is no limit to the number of Territories a single Company can hold.\n\nIn order to claim a Territory, a member of the Company must use a Claim Charter on the vacant Protection Ward. Claim Charters are purchased at &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_BuyTab"&gt;Trading Posts&lt;/a&gt;. They cost a lot and can be dropped just like any other item, so be careful when carrying the Charter to the Territory.\n\nIf a Territory is already held by another Company, it cannot be claimed until its Protection Ward is destroyed. If protection is not active for the Territory, this can be done through &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Crime"&gt;Criminal action&lt;/a&gt;. If protection is up on the Territory, then the Company that wishes to take the Territory must declare &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_War"&gt;War&lt;/a&gt;.\n\nOnce claimed, Company members with adequate &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Ranks"&gt;permissions&lt;/a&gt; can manage aspects of the Territory from its Protection Ward. At the Protection Ward, you can improve the Tier of your Territory and purchase protection for it.\n\nUpgrading a Protection Ward allows the construction of higher Tiers of &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Building"&gt;Structures&lt;/a&gt;. When you interact with the Protection Ward and choose to upgrade it, a new Blueprint is placed over the Protection Ward. You must then supply the required resources as you would any other Blueprint in order to complete the upgrade.\n\nPurchasing protection for a Territory prevents all Structures, including the Protection Ward itself, from being damaged. This protection can be bypassed briefly during a &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Siege"&gt;Siege&lt;/a&gt;, but is otherwise impenetrable. Keeping protection up on a Territory allows you to not have to worry about bandits and raiders destroying your progress. Protection requires both Coin and Azoth to maintain.\n\nRemember that protection only applies within a certain radius of the Protection Ward, and it does not protect players.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Companies_Treasury">Company Treasury</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Companies_Treasury">Shared Coffers for a Company</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Companies_Treasury">Many aspects of managing a Company require funding. To that end, Companies have Treasuries. These act as a shared location for storing the Company's funds.\n\nAny member of a Company may deposit Coin into the Company Treasury. To do this, use either the Treasury tab in the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_UI"&gt;Company screen&lt;/a&gt; or the Give Coin button in your &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Inventory"&gt;Inventory&lt;/a&gt;.\n\nOnly a Company's &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Ranks"&gt;Governor&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Ranks"&gt;Consuls&lt;/a&gt; can withdraw from the Treasury. The Governor can withdraw any amount at any time. They can also set a limit for how much Coin that the Consuls can withdraw in one day. Consuls may only withdraw Coin up to this limit. The Governor could also choose to remove this limit altogether.\n\nThe Treasury is a great way to collect the required Coin for &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Territories"&gt;Territory protection&lt;/a&gt;, new &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Territories"&gt;Claim Charters&lt;/a&gt;, and declaring &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_War"&gt;War&lt;/a&gt;.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Companies_War">War</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Companies_War">Attacking and Defending Territories</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Companies_War">In order to capture &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Territories"&gt;Territories&lt;/a&gt; from each other, Companies can declare War. To declare War, you can use the Map or the All Companies menu. Declaring War costs a significant amount of Coin, and you can only declare War on a Company that owns at least one Territory. The exact cost varies based on a number of factors, including difference in size between the Companies.\n\nWar plays out in a number of Phases, each with slightly different rules of engagement.\n\nWhen War is first declared, it enters the Pre-War phase. During this phase, the Companies still may not attack each other without commiting a &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Crime"&gt;crime&lt;/a&gt;. This phase grants the Defending Company the opportunity to muster their forces, and prevents surprise attacks while most of a Company's members are offline.\n\nAfter the Pre-War phase comes the Battle phase. During this phase, the involved Companies can attack each other freely without any criminal punishment. Territory protections are active, however. The length of the Battle phase can vary depending on when the War was started and what time the Defender's Siege Window is set for.\n\nThe next phase is Siege. The Siege phase takes place during the Defending Company's &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Companies_Siege"&gt;Siege Window&lt;/a&gt;. During this phase, the Attacking Company can bypass the Defending Company's protection on their Territories. This means the attacker can destroy one of the Defender's Protection Wards even if they've paid for protection. This phase ends early if a Protection Ward is successfully destroyed.\n\nAfter the Siege phase, the War enters a Resolution phase. The Companies can still attack each other during this phase just like during the Battle phase. However, during this phase the Defending Company can declare a counter attack. This is a special way of declaring War that costs less than the initial attack and skips the Pre-War phase. Instead, a counter attack's Battle phase starts immediately after the Resolution phase ends. If no counter attack is declared, the War ends when the Resolution phase does.\n\nYou can see the times that each phase will take place in the popup that appears when you choose to declare War, before committing and spending the Coin. While at War, you can check on what phase it is in and when the next one starts in the Wars tab of the &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_UI"&gt;Company screen&lt;/a&gt;.</string>