<string key="Lore_Chapter_Progression">Progression</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Progression_Attributes">Attributes</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Progression_Attributes">Core Abilities</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Progression_Respec">Respeccing</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Progression_Respec">Changing Your Abilities</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Progression_Respec">At certain Levels you will gain the option to Respec. When you choose to Respec, all points you've invested will be returned so that you can spend them in a new way. This means you are never truly locked in to any rank you've gained, so you can spend your points without fear of regretting the investment.\n\nRespeccing is done on &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Progression_Attributes"&gt;Attributes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Progression_TradeSkills"&gt;Trade Skills&lt;/a&gt; separately.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Progression_TradeSkills">Trade Skills</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Progression_TradeSkills">Becoming a Master in Your Field</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Progression_TradeSkills">Your ability to craft, gather, and refine items is determined by your Trade Skills. These skills align with the various &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Stations"&gt;Crafting Stations&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Refining"&gt;Refining Stations&lt;/a&gt;.\n\nCrafting Skills\nThese skills are required to craft items at their respective &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Stations"&gt;Crafting Stations&lt;/a&gt;. Having more ranks in these skills allows you to craft more recipes and grants improved chances to craft with a higher &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Rarity"&gt;Craftsmanship&lt;/a&gt;. These are:\n  • Blacksmithing\n  • Engineering\n  • Outfitting\n  • Cooking\n  • Alchemy\n\nGathering and Refining\nThese skills are required to refine resources at &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Refining"&gt;Refining Stations&lt;/a&gt;. In addition to granting the ability to refine resources, higher ranks also improve your ability to gather the related resource and grant a chance of getting a higher &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Crafting_Rarity"&gt;Rarity&lt;/a&gt; of raw material. These are:\n  • Logging and Carpentry\n  • Mining, Stonecutting, and Smelting\n  • Harvesting and Weaving\n  • Tracking, Skinning, and Tanning\n\nPersonal Skills\nThese skills can cover a range of abilities. Each has use outside of &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="GettingStarted_Outposts"&gt;Outposts&lt;/a&gt;. These are:\n  • Wilderness Survival: this improves the Tier of your &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Mechanics_Camping"&gt;Camp&lt;/a&gt;, and unlocks the ability to craft more recipes there\n  • Repairing: this allows you to repair items at the cost of fewer resources and with a decreased loss of maximum durability</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_Progression_XP">Leveling and XP</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_Progression_XP">Reaching New Levels</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_Progression_XP">Characters in New World have a Level. This broadly represents their capabilities, with higher level characters having more &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Progression_Attributes"&gt;Attributes&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="Progression_TradeSkills"&gt;Trade Skills&lt;/a&gt; than lower level characters. However, level alone is not a full measure of someone's combat or crafting effectiveness. It depends on how those points were allocated.\n\nAs you fight, gather, and craft you will earn XP. When you've accrued enough XP you will gain a Level. The amount of XP you need to earn varies, increasing as your level does. Earning level 10 requires more XP than earning level 2.\n\nYou can see your current progress towards your next level along the bottom of the screen. When you gain XP, you will see the amount added appear briefly and the bar will fill further. When it fills completely, you gain a Level.\n\nWhen you gain a Level, you are awarded points to spend on either Attributes or Trade Skills. These points are not interchangable, and which you gain and how many depends on the Level you just reached. Gaining a Level provides no other benefit, so you have to spend your points on the Progression screen (default: [K]) to improve your abilities.</string>
