<string key="Lore_Chapter_TradingPost">Trading Post</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_TradingPost_Overview">Trading Post Overview</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_TradingPost_Overview">Buying and Selling in New World</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_TradingPost_Overview">Every &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="GettingStarted_Outposts"&gt;Outpost&lt;/a&gt; in Aeternum includes a Trading Post. There you can buy and sell items for Coin.\n\nThe market is entirely player driven. Every item available for sale was posted by a player, and every item you wish to sell must be bought by a player. The only exceptions are Talismans and Animorum, which are dropped by Corrupted and Angry Earth enemies. These items can be sold directly to the Trading Post for Coin, and have no other purpose.\n\nTrading Posts offer three views:\n  • The &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_BuyTab"&gt;Buy Tab&lt;/a&gt;\n  • The &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_SellTab"&gt;Sell Tab&lt;/a&gt;\n  • The &lt;a action="GoToPage" data="TradingPost_MyOrders"&gt;My Orders Tab&lt;/a&gt;\n\nThe Trading Post works on the concept of postings and orders. Players can post items for sale, and they can also order items for purchase. Doing this requires a fee determined by how much the post or order is worth and how long it will be available.\n\nEvery Outpost has a separate inventory. Items and orders are placed at a specific Outpost's Trading Post, and are not transferable. You can view items and orders at different Outposts by using the location dropdown menu to select another location, but you cannot make the purchase or sale without traveling there.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_TradingPost_BuyTab">The Buy Tab</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_TradingPost_BuyTab">Making Purchases</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_TradingPost_BuyTab">All purchases are made through the Trading Post's Buy Tab. There are two methods of making a purchase:\n  • Browse posted items, and buy them directly\n  • Place a Buy Order for a specific item to be fulfilled later by another player\n\nDirect purchases are simple. You can browse all the items that have been posted by looking through the list. You can filter these items using the search bar or the category options on the left. When you find an item you want to buy, just select it to see a breakdown of the costs, including a tax charged by the Trading Post. Once you buy the item, it will be added to your Inventory. You can only purchase items that were posted to the Outpost you are at.\n\nIf you can't find the item you want, or it isn't available for a price you'll accept, you can place a Buy Order. To place a Buy Order, you need to identify the specific item you want by using the search bar or clicking into the filters until you find it. Once you drill down to the item, you will be presented with the option to order it. Clicking the button will open a window where you can define how many, what Rarity or Craftsmanship you'll accept (if applicable for the item), how much you're willing to pay, and the maximum time the order should remain active for. When the order is fulfilled, the item will be added to the Outpost Storage where you placed the order.\n\nPlacing a Buy Order requires paying a Listing Fee, which is determined by a combination of the price you are offering, the quantity, and the duration. If you do not have enough Coin for the Listing Fee, you cannot place the order. This fee is not refunded if the order expires.\n\nThe Buy Tab is also where you can purchase a Claim Charter, which is necessary to claim a Territory for your Company.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_TradingPost_SellTab">The Sell Tab</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_TradingPost_SellTab">Selling Items for Coin</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_TradingPost_SellTab">Items can be sold using the Trading Post's Sell Tab. Most items are sold using one of two methods:\n  • Fulfilling a Buy Order\n  • Posting an item\n\nTalismans and Animorum are exceptions. These items can only be sold directly to the Trading Post by clicking the button in the top left of the Sell Tab. They have no other use, so sell any you have every time you visit.\n\nFulfilling a Buy Order is a mirror of purchasing an item. When you select an item to sell, you will be shown any open orders for that item. Alternatively, you can switch to viewing All Items to see what orders have been placed even if you don't have the item being requested. When you click on an open order, you'll be able to select how many to sell if the order is for multiple, and how much you'll make from the sale. Click Sell Now to make the transaction immediately.\n\nPosting an item is done by selecting the item from the list in the My Sellable Items view. Clicking the button opens a window that lets you set the quantity, price, and duration of your posting. Each of these values factors into the Listing Fee, which you'll need to pay to post your item. Once posted, the item will be removed from your inventory or storage and held until it is sold or the posting expires. If the posting expires, the item will be returned to the Outpost Storage where you posted the item. The Listing Fee is non-refundable.</string>

<string key="Lore_Title_TradingPost_MyOrders">The My Orders Tab</string>
<string key="Lore_Subtitle_TradingPost_MyOrders">Keep Track of Transactions</string>
<string key="Lore_Body_TradingPost_MyOrders">The My Orders tab allows you to see all of your open Buy Orders, items you've posted for sale, and your past transactions. You cannot edit open orders or sales, but you can cancel them before they expire.\n\nCanceling costs nothing, but the Listing Fee you paid is not refundable.</string>
