<string key="Topic_SummerMedleyfaire" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Summer Medleyfaire</string>
<string key="Topic_Description_SummerMedleyfaire" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">A time of fishing and dancing and ultimate jubilation.</string>

<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Chapter_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Everfall Summer Village</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_01_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Wishing Bones</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_01_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">The Test</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_01_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">I feel a fool even writing this down. \n\nAfter dinner, I saved the sturgeon’s bones. Every last one. They weren’t golden, like in the fairy tales. But I placed them in a bowl, poured seawater over the bones, and spoke a wish anyway. \n\nWoke up this morning, and my boat still leaks. Useless, stupid story. At least I got a warm meal out of it.</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_01_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Repairing the Leak</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_01_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">An Unexpected Visitor</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_01_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Tried to repair the leak myself. I’d been at it for hours when I heard music coming from the shore. A strange, warbly flute that rose as the sun set. \n\nThe sound of music came closer, until a masked stranger stepped out from behind the trees. They lowered the flute and smiled at me. \n\n“Well met, well met! I’m hosting a little fishing competition, and I heard of a lonely fellow who happened to be one of the finest anglers on the island.”</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_01_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Masked Flattery</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_01_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Flattery</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_01_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">I’m not one for flattery, so I was going to shoo this strange jester off. But then they came closer. Their eyes glinted golden behind the mask, in the light of the setting sun. \n\n“There are prizes for the biggest, most magnificent catch! Please do come. A party’s merrier with more guests!” \n\nDon’t know what made me follow. Maybe it was the music, maybe it was the chance to brag.</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_01_04" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Grand Prize</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_01_04" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Prizes</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_01_04" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Caught the biggest sturgeon of the year, and you know what the grand prize was? \n\nA new boat. The masked musician presented it to me with this knowing look, and I didn’t know what to say. \n\nNext year, I’ll search for that musician as soon as summer comes around. And I’m saving every fish’s bones.</string>

<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Chapter_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Brightwood Summer Village</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_02_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Maudlinbug Music</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_02_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">All that Glitters</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_02_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Poor Luis spends the heat of the day chasing Maudlinbugs away from his darling bees. I haven’t said this to Luis, because I’m quite sure he’ll howl with rage if I do. But I find the Maudlinbugs adorable, myself. \n\nTheir funny short wings, glittering dust, and the way they bump into everything around them. They’re like tiny drunken revelers, each buzzing cloud its own miniature party!</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_02_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Last Night's Dream</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_02_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">My Midsummer Night's Dream</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_02_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">The dream I had last night was unlike any other. \n\nThe creature spoke with a thousand small, buzzing voices, a chorus both rapturous and painful to my ears. “The song, the sssong! We wish only for the sssong!” A universe of beaded, jeweled eyes stared unblinking. Dust poured from their myriad glittering wings. \n\nI awoke with a pounding head from Luis’s mead, and a new melody in my heart.</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_02_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Bugging the Bugs</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_02_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">All’s Well that Ends Well</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_02_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">My tiny patrons approve! The Maudlinbugs adore my new tune. They gather and dance around me in whirling clouds. And dear Luis and his beehives can finally have some peace and quiet for the rest of summer. \n\nI think I’ll take this little show on the road, though I’ll have to find a suitable tailor first. The darling little Maudlinbugs cover everything with their dust, and my new garb must match theirs.</string>

<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Chapter_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Weaver's Fen Summer Village</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_03_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Feastingtide</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_03_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">A Fortuitous Meeting</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_03_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">So on the hottest damn day of the year, this outrageously dressed stranger waltzes—literally waltzes!—down the street and right through my back door! Who does that? I nearly threw them out, but they got down on their knees, right on my brand new rug. \n\n“Oh, mistress Appius, purveyor of culinary delights, won’t you give this humble musician an audience?” \n\nI couldn’t say no. I couldn’t say anything. I was struck speechless by the sheer audacity of it all.</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_03_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Menu</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_03_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Claudia's Original Course List</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_03_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">First course: olives with parsley and fennel, small fish pastries in hot sauce, fresh oysters, smoked sturgeon with cold sage soup \n\nSecond course: fish pie with cinnamon and nutmeg, ginger-stuffed sturgeon, roasted sturgeon and jelly, thrice-spiced sturgeon skewers (brave guests only) \n\nDesserts: Damn the dessert. I’m good, but I can’t conjure dessert out of a sturgeon!</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_03_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">The Smell of Fish</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_03_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Next Year</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_03_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">My eyes ache. I’ll never get the smell of frying fish out of my best apron. I bought up every last jar of pepper in this town and the next one over. \n\nAnd when I said that to the Maestro, what did they do? Smiled that beatific smile, clapped me on the back, and asked, “Same time next year?” \n\nFor Heaven’s sake, I must be mad, but of course I’ll be back next year! And I’m bringing reinforcements. Kartik makes the finest fish curry, and I hope he won’t mind a stranger waltzing into his kitchen.</string>

<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Chapter_04" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Monarch's Bluffs Summer Village</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_04_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">The Sturgeon's Tale</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_04_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">The Fisherman</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_04_01" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Once upon a time, an old fisherman washed up on the shores of Aeternum. Though others sought treasure and power, the fisherman was content to build himself a small hut overlooking a delta, and sail out every day to catch his meals. \n\nOne summer evening, the fisherman found himself lost in a dense fog. He drifted until he saw a light beneath the waves. He cast his line, watching the light bob and sink. The creature that he reeled up was unearthly: an enormous sturgeon with glittering jeweled scales, twice as long as he was tall. \n\nThe astonished fisherman nearly dropped his line, but not before the sturgeon spoke: "Release me, friend, and I will grant you a wish."</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_04_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Glowing Trail</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_04_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">The First Wish</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_04_02" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">In a land of wonders, a talking fish is hardly noteworthy. But something about the sturgeon's blinding scales and golden eyes gave the fisherman pause. \n\nHe bowed and answered, "Will you guide me home?" The sturgeon turned and began swimming away, with the fisherman paddling after. He followed its glowing trail all the way back to shore.</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_04_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Good Fortune</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_04_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">The Second Wish</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_04_03" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">When his hut was in sight, the fisherman stopped paddling. "Thank you,” he said to the sturgeon. “May I ask for a second wish?" \n\nThe sturgeon did not answer. \n\n"I wish for your good fortune, friend," continued the fisherman. "I wish for you to prosper, and for the oceans and rivers to be as good to you as they have been to me."</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Title_04_04" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">Generous Spirit</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Subtitle_04_04" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">The Third Wish</string>
<string key="SummerMedleyfaire_Body_04_04" rel_version="Event_Summer_Perm">More lights appeared from beneath the waves. Soon, the shallow water was full of jeweled sturgeon, as many as the stars in the night sky. They all spoke with a single voice as deep as the sea: \n\n"For your generous spirit, you may make a third wish." The fisherman thought, until the fog cleared and the moon rose high in the sky. Patiently, the many sturgeon waited. \n\n"I wish for death," said the fisherman. "I am old, and the next step awaits me." \n\nNo one ever saw the fisherman again. He left behind only his boat, his rod, and a single fish scale that crumbled to shimmering dust with the sunrise.</string>